<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
  <LocalizedText>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Fortaleza|Fortalezas</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Quartel-General|Quartéis-Generais</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Lille</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Reims</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Nancy</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Belfort</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Orleães</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Chartres</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Colônia</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Coblença</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Mannheim</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Estrasburgo</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Colmar</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Antuérpia</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Liège</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Namur</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Mons</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Luxemburgo</Text>
      <Gender>neutral</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Os alemães desenvolveram armas de cerco especializadas para quebrar a defesa do círculo de fortes em torno da Bélgica. Elas se mostraram muito eficientes, fazendo os fortes caírem antes do planejado. Os franceses desenvolveram um canhão de artilharia de 75 mm sofisticado e poderoso que se mostrou durável e flexível. Porém, nada disso foi suficiente para quebrar o impasse das trincheiras. Novas tecnologias de taques e aeronaves e táticas de unidades pequenas viriam a alcançar este feito.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Logística é o processo de fornecer material para um exército para repor perdas e gastos. Apesar de não ser glamouroso, o sucesso da guerra depende da execução correta desses detalhes. Amadores estudam táticas; especialistas estudam logística. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Após a era napoleônica, os oficiais militares profissionais começaram a incorporar o planejamento estratégico e operacional em seus trabalhos. O comando profissional é a parte do exército responsável pela tradução dos objetivos políticos da guerra em objetivos militares. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Na guerra, todos os recursos do estado são colocados a serviço dos objetivos da guerra. Em uma sociedade industrial, isso implica em uma reformulação total da infraestrutura industrial para a criação de armamento, treinamento e parte da população para alistamento em massa e direcionar a economia através de ferramentas políticas evidentes. Isso pode transformar a sociedade de maneiras que perduram por muito tempo após o término do conflito.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A invenção da metralhadora e das munições novas e altamente explosivas fizeram com que as fortificações também mudassem nos anos que precederam a Primeira Guerra Mundial. O extenso sistema de trincheiras da Frente Ocidental pode ser visto como uma expressão física da supremacia da defesa sobre o ataque em grande parte da guerra. Da mesma maneira, as táticas modernas de infantaria e tanques desenvolvidas a partir de 1916 podem ser vistas como um esforço para superar essa supremacia da defesa.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>No começo da Primeira Guerra Mundial, a aviação ainda estava em seus primórdios e as aeronaves eram máquinas caras e instáveis para reconhecimento. Ao final da guerra, elas eram padrão em todos os grandes exércitos do planeta e eram utilizadas em ataques táticos e bombardeios estratégicos, tendo passado por uma rápida evolução no período mais intenso da guerra. A pesquisa e o desenvolvimento eram tão caros que muitas vezes eram feitos com financiamento do Estado ou com parcerias público-privadas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Após a desastrosa Batalha de Sedan durante a Guerra Franco-Prussiana de 1870, o exército francês precisou se recuperar da perda catastrófica e da humilhação política conseguinte para se reconstruir e se transformar em um dos melhores exércitos da Europa. Ao contrário da tendência alemã de planejamentos operacionais detalhados para as batalhas, os franceses começaram a aderir à doutrina de ofensivas flexíveis.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O exército, pensava-se, conseguiria avançar através dos ataques constantes às linhas inimigas e da exploração de qualquer ponto fraco que surgisse desses ataques. O inimigo não conseguiria atingir um equilíbrio, a iniciativa permaneceria no lado francês e os avanços dos inimigos alemães seriam frustrados por contra-ataques rápidos. Isso se aplicaria tanto a nível dos batalhões quanto em maiores escalas: onde o invasor estivesse fraco, era ali que os franceses atacariam.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Esse foi um dos maiores paradoxos de agosto de 1914. Mesmo com os franceses enfraquecidos na frente dos Países Baixos, eles conseguiram avançar por Alsácia e Lorena, mas elas precisavam ser ocupadas para oferecer reforços para salvar Paris. Ao final daquele ano, o espírito do "atacar sempre" havia esmaecido e as trincheiras definido a Frente Ocidental.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Os sucessos do exército prussiano em 1870 durante a Guerra Franco-Prussiana justificaram o planejamento compreensivo e metódico do exército, que incluía cronogramas de marchas e vagões nos trilhos. Considerando inevitável uma futura guerra contra a França, o Conde Von Schlieffen, chefe do Estado-Maior alemão, traçou planos para uma futura invasão à França, passando pelos Países Baixos e descendo até Paris, ao sul. Este plano de invasão exigia uma concentração de forças no flanco ocidental do exército alemão para obter sucesso, mas ele nunca foi executado em sua totalidade.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Com guerra em duas frentes, o alto comando da Alemanha transferiu algumas de suas forças destinadas ao flanco oeste para uma frente totalmente diferente (neste caso, contra os russos). Com o exército alemão atravessando os Países Baixos com sucesso, o exército francês foi surpreendido e a formação saliente dele apresentava-se como um alvo tentador para o Estado-Maior alemão. Porém, diversos fatores, como a redução das forças no Plano Schlieffen, as manobras improvisadas das tropas alemães em resposta aos franceses e a forte resistência dos franceses e britânicos significavam que o golpe não havia causado o efeito desejado.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Os alemães haviam arriscado e perdido, e a guerra perdurou por quatro anos nas linhas onde o Plano Schlieffen havia falhado.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A Força Expedicionária Britânica foi um pequeno exército colocado em campo com o propósito de aproximar os britânicos da entente com a França. Posicionados a oeste da linha francesa, inicialmente eles foram vistos mais como uma cortesia política do que como uma força militar significativa. Porém, quando os alemães desceram pelos Países Baixos até Paris, a FEB enfrentou um exército alemão numericamente superior na Batalha de Mons e, apesar de abatidos e forçados a se retirarem, eles impediram a aniquilação do Quinto Exército Francês. A Batalha de Mons é uma das conquistas militares mais celebradas e homenageadas da Grã-Bretanha e é praticamente um sinônimo da FEB.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A nação da Bélgica havia sido criada no final da Era Napoleônica como parte do equilíbrio de poderes europeus, mas era desde longa data uma aliada especial da Grã-Bretanha. O plano de invasão da França necessitava que o Exército Alemão invadisse através da Bélgica. De fato, as primeiras versões do plano afirmavam que o Exército Belga forneceria uma guarda de honra nas estradas para a passagem do Exército Alemão, uma suposição altamente incorreta, como ficaria óbvio. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A cidade de Liege estava cercada por uma série de fortes e representava o primeiro obstáculo militar significativo para o Exército Alemão em 1914. Os fortes, embora lutassem bem em muitos casos, eram incapazes de conter o avanço de armas de cerco especiais construída especificamente para o propósito de quebrá-los. O colapso das fortificações de Liege e a crueldade do Exército Alemão contra a população da Bélgica virou a maré da opinião popular contra a Alemanha, especialmente na Grã-Bretanha.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O pequeno principado de Luxemburgo fica entre a França e a Alemanha e, além disso, é o centro de uma grande ferrovia entre os dois países. A captura destes trilhos ferroviários foi essencial para o plano alemão de invadir a França e, consequentemente, a invasão de Luxemburgo foi uma das primeiras ações da guerra em 1914. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A França esteve se preparando para uma guerra contra a Alemanha desde o desastre da Guerra Franco-Prussiana em 1870, quando o Exército Prussiano devastara o exército de campo francês, capturara o Imperador e extraíra concessões humilhantes na paz que se seguiu, incluindo a concessão dos territórios da Alsácia e Lorena, a leste da França. Uma geração inteira de políticos e oficiais franceses crescera na sombra desta derrota e estava determinada a buscar o acerto de contas, senão a direta vingança pela perda. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Os principais aliados militares da França eram a Rússia e a Grã-Bretanha, e foi a declaração de guerra da Rússia contra o Império Austro-Húngaro que precipitou a entrada da França na guerra em nome dos aliados. A França, porém, estava focada primeiramente em sua própria luta contra a Alemanha em vez do conflito contra a Austro-Hungria. Com esta finalidade, o esforço principal da França no começo da guerra foi um ataque na Alsácia e Lorena, para recapturar o território rapidamente, deixando a fronteira norte com a Bélgica e Luxemburgo pouco protegida. Os planos de guerra franceses subestimavam criticamente o número de forças alemãs que atacariam neste eixo (eles presumiam que os alemães viriam através das Ardenas), forçando os exércitos a mudarem de planos abruptamente logo no começo da guerra.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Uma geração antes do começo da Primeira Guerra Mundial, o Exército Prussiano causara à França a sua maior derrota militar desde o fim da Era Napoleônica, e logo após formara a nação moderna da Alemanha. Políticos alemães enxergavam muito claramente como os termos extraídos dos franceses estavam contribuindo com as raízes do próximo conflito em potencial: e então passaram a se preparar para a próxima guerra. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A assinatura da Tríplice Entente (a aliança militar entre França, Grã-Bretanha e Rússia) botou a Alemanha em uma situação militar precária, já que agora ela estava cercada de adversários militares a leste e oeste. A grande estratégia formulada antes da Primeira Guerra Mundial era realizar um ataque único, potente e massivo no oeste da França antes que a Rússia tivesse a chance de trazer sua vantagem numérica enorme ao leste. Este se tornou o objetivo político motriz do Plano Schlieffen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Às vésperas da Primeira Guerra Mundial, havia poucos exércitos no mundo que eram tão bem treinados e preparados quanto as forças militares alemãs. E ainda assim, a preparação e o treinamento não bastaram para realizar o fim rápido que o plano visava.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A participação da Grã-Bretanha na Tríplice Entente (a aliança militar entre a França, a Grã-Bretanha e a Rússia) não era, de modo algum, uma conclusão óbvia. A longa competição militar entre a França e a Grã-Bretanha, que datava à era de Napoleão, além dos laços entre as famílias reais da Grã-Bretanha e da Alemanha, tornaram a participação britânica nos Impérios Centrais um resultado plausível. Por fim, a Grã-Bretanha se juntou à Entente devido à rápida crescente competição entre a Alemanha e a Grã-Bretanha que fez muitas pessoas buscarem algo que desafiasse o poder alemão. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Às vésperas da Primeira Guerra Mundial, não havia garantias de que a Grã-Bretanha enviaria forças militares à Europa continental. Isso ocorreu em maior parte devido à constante pressão de um pequeno grupo de oficiais nos Exércitos Francês e Britânico que fez a Grã-Bretanha enviar uma pequena força para solo francês. De fato, até mesmo o Kaiser ficou chocado pelos ingleses declararem guerra à Alemanha, declarando que eles haviam cometido um "erro tolo" com base em um "mero pedaço de papel".</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A nação da Bélgica havia sido criada no final da Era Napoleônica como parte do equilíbrio de poderes europeus, mas era desde longa data uma aliada especial da Grã-Bretanha. O plano de invasão da França necessitava que o Exército Alemão invadisse através da Bélgica. De fato, as primeiras versões do plano afirmavam que o Exército Belga forneceria uma guarda de honra nas estradas para a passagem do Exército Alemão, uma suposição altamente incorreta, como ficaria óbvio.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A cidade de Liege estava cercada por uma série de fortes e representava o primeiro obstáculo militar significativo para o Exército Alemão em 1914. Os fortes, embora lutassem bem em muitos casos, eram incapazes de conter o avanço de armas de cerco especiais construída especificamente para o propósito de quebrá-los. O colapso das fortificações de Liege e a crueldade do Exército Alemão contra a população da Bélgica virou a maré da opinião popular contra a Alemanha, especialmente na Grã-Bretanha.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O comandante de campo é um oficial responsável por uma porção significativa da força militar de uma nação, normalmente de uma frente inteira. Ele precisa saber o plano operacional do seu exército e estar disposto a se adaptar às mudanças no decorrer da guerra. Apesar de trabalhar com outros comandantes subordinados e ser aconselhado pelo comando geral, o sucesso ou fracasso do exército depende do seu próprio julgamento. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O comandante de campo é um oficial responsável por uma porção significativa da força militar de uma nação, normalmente de uma frente inteira. Ele precisa saber o plano operacional do seu exército e estar disposto a se adaptar às mudanças no decorrer da guerra. Apesar de trabalhar com outros comandantes subordinados e ser aconselhado pelo comando geral, o sucesso ou fracasso do exército depende do seu próprio julgamento.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O comandante de campo é um oficial responsável por uma porção significativa da força militar de uma nação, normalmente de uma frente inteira. Ele precisa saber o plano operacional do seu exército e estar disposto a se adaptar às mudanças no decorrer da guerra. Apesar de trabalhar com outros comandantes subordinados e ser aconselhado pelo comando geral, o sucesso ou fracasso do exército depende do seu próprio julgamento.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O comandante de campo é um oficial responsável por uma porção significativa da força militar de uma nação, normalmente de uma frente inteira. Ele precisa saber o plano operacional do seu exército e estar disposto a se adaptar às mudanças no decorrer da guerra. Apesar de trabalhar com outros comandantes subordinados e ser aconselhado pelo comando geral, o sucesso ou fracasso do exército depende do seu próprio julgamento.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O comandante de campo é um oficial responsável por uma porção significativa da força militar de uma nação, normalmente de uma frente inteira. Ele precisa saber o plano operacional do seu exército e estar disposto a se adaptar às mudanças no decorrer da guerra. Apesar de trabalhar com outros comandantes subordinados e ser aconselhado pelo comando geral, o sucesso ou fracasso do exército depende do seu próprio julgamento.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O quartel-general é o local onde os planos de operação de um exército são transformados em ordens. Conectados aos comandantes subordinados na linha de batalha através de mensageiros e telégrafos, eles costumam ser temporários, já que as linhas de batalhas mudam e demandam que o alto comando fique próximo da ação.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Comandante de Campo</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Aumenta a força de suas defesas externas para resistir a todos os ataques, menos os mais concentrados.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Vitória da Máquina de Guerra</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Com a Alemanha, você deve capturar Paris dentro do tempo limite. Com a França, você deve defender Paris até o tempo acabar.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+3 de [ICON_Strength] força de combate para unidades terrestres dentro de 2 painéis.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+3 de [ICON_Strength] bônus de combate de Grande General.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+100 de pontos de saúde em todas as cidades.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+6 de [ICON_Strength] força de combate para unidades de artilharia.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Permite a formação e treinamento de Exércitos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Concede 2 [ICON_GreatGeneral] Grandes Generais na sua [ICON_Capital] capital.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+5 de [ICON_Strength] força de combate para todas as unidades.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Unidade de suporte da Era Medieval. Requer um Arsenal para produzir. Pode construir melhorias de Ferrovias, Fortes e Pistas de Pouso.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Controle de Paris</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Controle de Paris</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Marechal de campo</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>A prova da maestria militar não está em campanhas prolongadas, mas sim nas vitórias decisivas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>General</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Comando é a arte de direcionar as forças da guerra com sucesso e sem esforço.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Coronel</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>O sucesso e a derrota se equilibram no fio da navalha da informação e da intuição.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Major</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Onde há coragem, há audácia. Onde há audácia, há movimento. Onde há movimento, há vitória.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Capitão</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Vitória, se possível, mas honra acima de tudo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Aeronave</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Fortificações</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Artilharia Pesada</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Logística</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Comando</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>Guerra Industrial</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>{1_Day} de agosto de 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>{1_Day} de setembro de 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} Guerra Industrial</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="pt_BR">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} de Artilharia Pesada</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Forteresse|Forteresses</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Quartier général|Quartiers généraux</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Lille</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Reims</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Nancy</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Belfort</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Orléans</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:vowel</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Chartres</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Cologne</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Koblenz</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Mannheim</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Strassburg</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Colmar</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Antwerp</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:vowel</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Liège</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Namur</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Mons</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Luxembourg</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:no_article</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les Allemands développèrent des pièces d'artillerie spéciale pour éventrer les défenses des forts belges. Ces nouvelles armes furent très efficaces, et les forts tombèrent plus rapidement que ce que les assaillants espéraient. De son côté, l'armée française développa un canon de 75 mm puissant et sophistiqué, résistant et polyvalent. Mais ni l'artillerie allemande ni l'artillerie française ne purent venir à bout de l'immobilisme des tranchées : il fallut pour cela attendre les nouvelles technologies des blindés et de l'aviation, et des tactiques d'escouades.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La logistique rassemble les systèmes rationnels visant à déplacer le matériel dont a besoin une armée, et remplacer les objets usés ou défectueux. Ce n'est peut-être pas une activité exaltante, mais la logistique est la clé de nombreux conflits. Les amateurs étudient la stratégie, les experts étudient la logistique.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Après l'ère napoléonienne, les officiers se mirent à intégrer des éléments de réflexions stratégiques et opérationnelles à leurs travaux. L'état-major est la partie de l'armée qui a pour mission de traduire en objectifs militaires les objectifs politiques des dirigeants d'un pays.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Dans la guerre totale, toutes les ressources de l'état sont mises au service des objectifs de guerre. Dans une société industrielle, cela signifie que toute l'infrastructure de production est utilisée pour fabriquer des armes, inciter la population à s'enrôler en masse, et stimuler l'économie via des initiatives politiques. Cette approche peut avoir des conséquences sur toute la société bien après la fin du conflit armé.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>L'invention de la mitrailleuse et de munitions d'artillerie hautement explosives fit évoluer les systèmes de fortification dans les années qui précédèrent la Première Guerre mondiale. La généralisation des systèmes de tranchées sur le front occidental souligne la suprématie de l'approche défensive dans l'art de la guerre, et les tactiques militaires modernes développées pour l'infanterie et les blindés à partir de 1916 cherchèrent toutes à renverser ce rapport de force.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Lorsque la Première Guerre mondiale éclata, l'aviation était encore au stade embryonnaire, et les aéronefs étaient des machines chères et peu précises employées pour des missions de reconnaissance. À la fin du conflit, il s'agissait désormais d'un élément indispensable de toutes les armées de la planète, utilisé pour des attaques tactiques ou des bombardements stratégiques. Les coûts de recherche et de développement étaient si élevés qu'il était indispensable d'obtenir le soutien financier de l'état ou des partenariats privé-public.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Après la bataille de Sedan lors de la guerre franco-prussienne de 1870, l'état-major français tenta de se reconstruire malgré des pertes humaines catastrophiques et des humiliations sur la scène internationale, dans le but de redevenir une puissance militaire de premier plan. À l'opposé de l'approche allemande, avec ses plans de bataille très détaillés, les officiers français élaborèrent une doctrine d'offensives flexibles.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>L'idée était d'attaquer les lignes ennemies sans relâche et d'exploiter les faiblesses de l'adversaire. L'ennemi, incapable de reprendre contenance, ne pourrait que subir les assauts français. Les avancées allemandes seraient contrées par des contre-attaques éclair. Cette stratégie devait s'appliquer au niveau du bataillon, jusqu'au front lui-même : là où l'envahisseur serait le plus faible, les Français attaqueraient.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>C'est l'un des grands paradoxes de ce mois d'août 1914 : même si les Français étaient à la peine en Belgique, ils parvenaient à progresser en Alsace et en Lorraine. Mais ces avancées ne durèrent qu'un temps : les troupes étaient attendues en renfort pour sauver Paris. À la fin de l'année, la stratégie du "Toujours attaquer" avait vécu, et les tranchées devinrent le quotidien du front occidental jusqu'à la fin de la guerre.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les succès de l'armée prussienne en 1870 justifièrent l'organisation méthodique de l'armée allemande, ses planifications, son organisation millimétrée des journées des troupes, l'utilisation des voies ferrées, et bien d'autres choses encore. Sachant qu'un nouveau conflit avec la France n'était qu'une question d'années, le comte von Schlieffen, chef d'état-major de l'armée allemande, établit une stratégie pour une future invasion de la France, via la Belgique et jusqu'à Paris, avant de descendre plus au sud. Cette invasion devait nécessiter des forces très concentrées aux extrémités ouest du flanc allemand, mais le plan ne fut jamais exécuté dans son intégralité.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La guerre se développant sur deux fronts simultanés, le haut-commandement allemand transféra certaines ressources prévues pour le front occidental sur des théâtres d'opération très différents, et contre les Russes. L'armée allemande parvint toutefois à s'enfoncer en Belgique et à mettre en déroute l'armée française. Une formation saillante dans les lignes françaises offrit une cible de choix à l'état-major allemand, mais plusieurs facteurs, notamment la réduction des forces du plan Schlieffen, une relative improvisation dans les mouvements de troupes en réaction à l'ennemi, et la farouche résistance des Français et des Britanniques, empêchèrent de porter le coup fatal.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les Allemands avaient fait un pari et l'avaient perdu. La guerre s'installa pour quatre longues années infernales, sur des lignes de front qui avaient vu la mort du plan Schlieffen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le corps expéditionnaire britannique était une petite troupe qui fut précipitée sur le champ de bataille dans le but de renforcer les liens de la Triple Entente. La présence de ces hommes à l'ouest de la ligne de front française tenait plus du symbole politique que de l'atout militaire. Toutefois, tandis que les Allemands s'enfonçaient dans les terres depuis les Pays-Bas en direction de Paris, le corps expéditionnaire britannique affronta des forces ennemies en plus grand nombre lors de la bataille de Mons. Malgré des pertes importantes et un relatif échec militaire, ces hommes réussirent à sauver la cinquième armée française. De nos jours, cette bataille est toujours commémorée en Grande-Bretagne, à jamais associée au corps expéditionnaire britannique.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Alliée de longue date de la Grande-Bretagne, la Belgique moderne fut créée à la fin de l'ère napoléonienne afin de garantir l'équilibre des puissances européennes. Pour envahir la France, la stratégie de l'armée allemande consistait à d'abord envahir la Belgique, et dans ses premières moutures, le plan des Allemands imaginait même que l'armée belge effectuerait une haie d'honneur aux soldats du Kaiser jusqu'à la France. Ce ne fut pas le cas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La ville de Liège, entourée par une série de forts, constitua le premier obstacle sérieux que rencontra l'armée allemande en 1914. Mais ces forts, même s'ils opposèrent une résistance farouche pour la plupart, ne purent tenir bien longtemps face à des pièces d'artillerie conçues spécialement pour la guerre de siège. L'effondrement des fortifications de Liège et la cruauté de l'armée allemande envers la population belge retournèrent l'opinion publique contre l'Allemagne, notamment chez les Britanniques.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La petite principauté du Luxembourg se situe entre la France et l'Allemagne, et est traversée par les lignes ferroviaires de ces deux pays. La capture de ces lignes revêtit une importance majeure pour les Allemands dans leur objectif d'envahir la France, et l'invasion du Luxembourg fut l'un des premiers événements de la guerre de 14-18.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La France se préparait à la guerre contre l'Allemagne depuis 1870 et la débâcle de la guerre franco-prussienne, au cours de laquelle l'ennemi avait écrasé l'armée française, capturé l'Empereur et obtenu des conditions humiliantes lors des négociations de paix. La France avait notamment perdu les territoires de l'Alsace et de la Lorraine, à l'est. Une génération entière d'hommes politiques et d'officiers français vécut dans le souvenir amer de cette défaite, avec une envie de revanche chevillée au corps.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Les principaux alliés de la France étaient la Russie et la Grande-Bretagne, et ce fut la déclaration de guerre des Russes à l'Empire austro-hongrois qui précipita la France dans le conflit par le jeu des alliances. Cependant, la France se concentra essentiellement sur son propre combat contre l'Allemagne, au détriment de l'Autriche-Hongrie. Lorsque la guerre éclata, la stratégie militaire française consista à reprendre rapidement l'Alsace et la Lorraine, quitte à laisser peu de défenses le long de la frontière au nord, près de la Belgique et du Luxembourg. Cette tactique sous-estimait très largement les forces allemandes qui allaient attaquer sur cet axe, la France prévoyant que les Allemands passeraient par les Ardennes. Ainsi, dès le début des hostilités, l'armée française dut modifier ses plans dans la précipitation.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Une génération avant la Première Guerre mondiale, l'armée prussienne avait infligé une importante défaite militaire à la France, la plus sévère depuis la fin de l'ère napoléonienne, et les années suivantes virent la fondation de la nation allemande moderne. Les dirigeants allemands ne se faisaient guère d'illusions : ils savaient que les termes de la reddition française après la défaite de 1870 ne pouvaient déboucher que sur un sentiment de revanche, et un nouveau conflit. C'est pourquoi ils préparèrent le pays en vue d'une nouvelle guerre.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La signature de la Triple Entente, l'alliance militaire entre la France, la Grande-Bretagne et la Russie, mit l'Allemagne dans une position militaire délicate, car elle se retrouva entourée à l'est et à l'ouest par ses adversaires. La grande stratégie formulée avant la Première Guerre mondiale consistait à jeter toutes ses forces à l'ouest pour terrasser la France, avant que la Russie pût mobiliser sa gigantesque armée à l'est. Cette tactique, utilisée à des fins de politique intérieure, fut surnommée le "Plan Schlieffen".</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>À la veille de la Première Guerre mondiale, peu d'armées étaient aussi entraînées et préparées que l'armée allemande. Et pourtant, l'État-major allemand ne fut pas en mesure de mener la guerre rapide qu'il avait imaginée.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La participation de la Grande-Bretagne à la Triple Entente, alliance militaire formée avec la France et la Russie, était loin d'être une évidence, au vu des rivalités militaires qui opposaient les Français aux Britanniques depuis plusieurs siècles. Par ailleurs, les liens entre la famille royale anglaise et l'Allemagne auraient pu faire pencher pour une participation britannique dans la coalition des empires centraux. Finalement, la Grande-Bretagne rejoignit tout de même la Triple Entente, car de nombreuses nations cherchaient à contenir l'influence grandissante de l'Allemagne.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>À la veille de la Première Guerre mondiale, il n'existait aucune certitude que la Grande-Bretagne enverrait des troupes en Europe continentale. Il aura fallu la pression constante d'un petit groupe d'officiers français et britanniques pour que le pays s'engage, faiblement, sur le théâtre des opérations français. Le Kaiser lui-même fut stupéfait de voir les Anglais déclarer la guerre à l'Allemagne. Selon lui, ces derniers avaient commis une "grossière erreur" à cause "d'un vulgaire bout de papier".</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Alliée de longue date de la Grande-Bretagne, la Belgique moderne fut créée à la fin de l'ère napoléonienne afin de garantir l'équilibre des puissances européennes. Pour envahir la France, la stratégie de l'armée allemande consistait à d'abord envahir la Belgique, et dans ses premières moutures, le plan des Allemands imaginait même que l'armée belge effectuerait une haie d'honneur aux soldats du Kaiser jusqu'à la France. Ce ne fut pas le cas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La ville de Liège, entourée par une série de forts, constitua le premier obstacle sérieux que rencontra l'armée allemande en 1914. Mais ces forts, même s'ils opposèrent une résistance farouche pour la plupart, ne purent tenir bien longtemps face à des pièces d'artillerie conçues spécialement pour la guerre de siège. L'effondrement des fortifications de Liège et la cruauté de l'armée allemande envers la population belge retournèrent l'opinion publique contre l'Allemagne, notamment chez les Britanniques.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le chef d'état-major général des armées est l'officier qui dirige les forces militaires de son pays, souvent sur tout un front. Il doit à la fois comprendre les enjeux du plan opérationnel de son armée et pouvoir l'adapter en fonction des aléas de la guerre. Il est épaulé par d'autres officiers subalternes et conseillé par son cabinet, mais le succès ou l'échec de l'armée repose sur ses décisions.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le chef d'état-major général des armées est l'officier qui dirige les forces militaires de son pays, souvent sur tout un front. Il doit à la fois comprendre les enjeux du plan opérationnel de son armée et pouvoir l'adapter en fonction des aléas de la guerre. Il est épaulé par d'autres officiers subalternes et conseillé par son cabinet, mais le succès ou l'échec de l'armée repose sur ses décisions.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le chef d'état-major général des armées est l'officier qui dirige les forces militaires de son pays, souvent sur tout un front. Il doit à la fois comprendre les enjeux du plan opérationnel de son armée et pouvoir l'adapter en fonction des aléas de la guerre. Il est épaulé par d'autres officiers subalternes et conseillé par son cabinet, mais le succès ou l'échec de l'armée repose sur ses décisions.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le chef d'état-major général des armées est l'officier qui dirige les forces militaires de son pays, souvent sur tout un front. Il doit à la fois comprendre les enjeux du plan opérationnel de son armée et pouvoir l'adapter en fonction des aléas de la guerre. Il est épaulé par d'autres officiers subalternes et conseillé par son cabinet, mais le succès ou l'échec de l'armée repose sur ses décisions.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le chef d'état-major général des armées est l'officier qui dirige les forces militaires de son pays, souvent sur tout un front. Il doit à la fois comprendre les enjeux du plan opérationnel de son armée et pouvoir l'adapter en fonction des aléas de la guerre. Il est épaulé par d'autres officiers subalternes et conseillé par son cabinet, mais le succès ou l'échec de l'armée repose sur ses décisions.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le quartier général est l'endroit où sont conçus les plans opérationnels de l'armée à destination du front. Les messages sont acheminés aux commandants subordonnés sur les lignes de bataille grâce au télégraphe et aux messagers. Les missions sont souvent appelées à être modifiées, car le front se déplace constamment et les ordres doivent être parfaitement adaptés pour ne pas perdre du terrain.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Chef d'état-major</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Augmente la résistance de vos défenses extérieures afin qu'elles puissent résister à tous les assauts, sauf les plus ciblés.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Machine de guerre : victoire</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>À la tête de l'Allemagne, vous devez capturer Paris dans le temps imparti. Avec la France, vous devez défendre la capitale jusqu'à la fin du temps imparti.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>[ICON_Strength] Puissance de combat +3 pour les unités terrestres se trouvant dans un rayon de 2 cases.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>[ICON_Strength] Puissance de combat bonus +3 grâce au général illustre.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>PV +100 dans toutes les villes.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>[ICON_Strength] Puissance de combat +6 pour les unités d'artillerie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Permet la formation et l'entraînement des armées.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Octroie 2 [ICON_GreatGeneral] généraux illustres dans votre [ICON_Capital] capitale.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>[ICON_Strength] Puissance de combat +5 pour toutes les unités.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Unité de soutien du Moyen-âge. Sa construction nécessite une armurerie. Peut construire des voies ferrées, des forts et des pistes d'atterrissage.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Contrôle de Paris</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Contrôle de Paris</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Maréchal</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>L'expertise militaire n'est pas prouvée par une campagne sans fin, mais par une victoire décisive.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Général</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Le commandement est l'art de diriger des forces militaires sans heurts et avec succès.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Colonel</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Ce qui fait la différence entre la victoire et l'échec, ce sont l'information et l'intuition.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Major</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Qui dit courage, dit audace. Qui dit audace, dit élan. Qui dit élan, dit victoire.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Capitaine</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>La victoire si possible, mais l'honneur avant tout.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Aéronefs</Text>
      <Gender>masculine:vowel</Gender>
      <Plurality>2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Fortifications</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Artillerie lourde</Text>
      <Gender>feminine:vowel</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Logistique</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>État-major</Text>
      <Gender>masculine:vowel</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Guerre industrielle</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>{1_Day} août 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>{1_Day} septembre 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Guerre industrielle +{1_Amount}.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="fr_FR">
      <Text>Artillerie lourde +{1_Amount}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Festung|Festung|Festung|Festung|Festung</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Hauptquartier|Hauptquartier|Hauptquartier|Hauptquartiers|Hauptquartier</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Lille</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Reims</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Nancy</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Belfort</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Orléans</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Chartres</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Köln</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Koblenz</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Mannheim</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Straßburg</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Colmar</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Antwerpen</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Lüttich</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Namur</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Mons</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Luxemburg</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Deutschen entwickelten spezielle Belagerungswaffen, um die Verteidigungen des belgischen Festungsrings zu durchbrechen. Diese erwiesen sich als äußerst erfolgreich, sodass die Festungen früher fielen, als von den Planern prognostiziert. Die Franzosen entwickelten eine ausgereifte und leistungsstarke 75mm-Artilleriekanone, die sich als langlebig und flexibel erwies. Aber keine dieser Entwicklungen reichte aus, um den Stillstand in den Schützengräben zu überwinden. Das wurde schließlich durch neue Technologien in Panzern und Flugzeugen und den taktischen Einsatz kleiner Einheiten erreicht.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Logistik beschreibt den Prozess der Versorgung einer Armee mit Ressourcen, um Verluste und Aufwendungen zu kompensieren. Obwohl nicht gerade glamourös, hängt der Erfolg in der Kriegsführung davon ab, dass diese Details absolut korrekt sind. Amateure studieren Taktiken, Experten studieren Logistik.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Nach der Napoleonischen Ära begannen Berufsoffiziere, die strategische und operative Planung in ihre Arbeit einzubeziehen. Der professionelle Kommandostab ist der Teil des Militärs, der für die Umwandlung politischer Kriegsziele in militärische Ziele verantwortlich ist.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Im totalen Krieg werden alle Ressourcen des Staates in den Dienst der kriegsrelevanten Ziele gestellt. In einer Industriegesellschaft bedeutet dies eine völlige Umgestaltung der industriellen Infrastruktur zur Waffenherstellung, die Ausbildung großer Teile der Bevölkerung an der Waffe und die Steuerung der Wirtschaft durch offenkundige politische Instrumente. Er kann die Gesellschaft auf eine Weise verändern, die auch noch lange nach Beendigung des Konflikts weiterbesteht.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Mit der Erfindung der Maschinenpistole und der neuen hochexplosiven Artilleriegeschosse veränderten sich auch die Befestigungsanlagen in den Jahren vor dem Ersten Weltkrieg. Die ausgedehnten Grabensysteme der Westfront können als Ausdruck der Überlegenheit der Defensive gegenüber der Offensive für einen Großteil des Krieges angesehen werden. Ebenso können die seit 1916 entwickelten modernen Taktiken für Infanterie und Kampfpanzer als Versuch angesehen werden, diese Vormachtstellung der Defensive zu überwinden.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Zu Beginn des Ersten Weltkriegs steckte die Luftfahrt noch in den Kinderschuhen und Flugzeuge waren teure und unzuverlässige Aufklärungsmaschinen. Zum Ende des Krieges waren sie ein Grundbestandteil aller großen Streitkräfte auf dem Planeten und wurden sowohl für taktische Angriffe als auch für strategische Bombardierungen eingesetzt, nachdem sie eine rasante Entwicklung im Schmelztiegel des Krieges durchlaufen hatten. Die Kosten für Forschung und Entwicklung waren so hoch, dass ein Großteil davon durch staatliche Förderung oder öffentlich-private Partnerschaften finanziert wurde.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Nach der verheerenden Schlacht bei Sedan während des Deutsch-Französischen Krieges von 1870 mussten sich die französischen Militärplaner erst von diesem katastrophalen Verlust und den erniedrigenden politischen Folgen erholen, bevor sie die Armee in eine der besten Europas verwandeln konnten. Im Gegensatz zur deutschen Vorliebe für detaillierte Schlachtpläne begannen französische Offiziere, sich allerdings für eine Doktrin der flexiblen Offensive einzusetzen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Man dachte, dass die Armee durch ständige Angriffe auf die feindlichen Linien und die rücksichtslose Ausnutzung der resultierenden Schwächen ihren Schwung optimal beibehalten könnte. Der Feind sollte nie in der Lage sein, sein Gleichgewicht zu finden. Die Franzosen würden die Initiative sichern und die mühsamen Fortschritte der deutschen Feinde würden durch blitzschnelle Gegenstöße zunichte gemacht werden. Dies würde von der Bataillonsebene bis zu den Kriegsschauplätzen gelten - da, wo der Eindringling schwach war, griffen die Franzosen an.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Es ist einer der größten Widersprüche vom August 1914, dass die Franzosen, selbst als sie an der Front in den Niederlanden taumelten, Erfolge bei ihrem Fortschritt durch Elsaß-Lothringen erzielten, die jedoch nicht weiterverfolgt werden konnten, da Verstärkung beim Kampf um Paris benötigt wurden. Am Ende des Jahres war der Leitspruch des "ständigen Angriffs" nur noch Schall und Rauch und zähe Grabenkämpfe prägten die Westfront.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Siege der Preußischen Armee im Jahre 1870 während des Deutsch-Französischen Krieges untermauerten den Erfolg der methodischen, umfassenden Planung der Armee bis hin zu den Zeitplänen für Truppenmärsche und den Schienenverkehr. Da der deutsche Generalstabschef Graf von Schlieffen einen zukünftigen Krieg mit Frankreich als unvermeidbar ansah, erarbeitete er Pläne für eine Invasion Frankreichs, die durch die Niederlande führte, um im Süden von Paris anzugreifen. Dieser Invasionsplan erforderte eine Konzentration der Streitkräfte an der westlichen Flanke der deutschen Armee - aber der Plan wurde in seiner Gesamtheit nie ausgeführt.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Angesichts des Zweifrontenkrieges verlegte das deutsche Oberkommando einen Teil der für die starke Westflanke bestimmten Streitkräfte zu einer ganz anderen Front (in diesem Fall gegen die Russen). Als sich die deutsche Armee erfolgreich durch die Niederlande kämpfte, schlug sie auch die französische Armee in die Flucht, und eine Schwäche in den französischen Linien stellte für den deutschen Generalstab ein verlockendes Ziel dar. Aber verschiedene Faktoren wie die Reduzierung der Streitkräfte im Schlieffen-Plan, improvisierte Truppenbewegungen der Deutschen als Reaktion auf die Franzosen und der heftige Widerstand der Franzosen und Briten führten dazu, dass der finale Schlag nie ausgeführt werden konnte.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Deutschen gingen ein Risiko ein und verloren - und der Krieg wurde vier Jahre lang in der Hölle der Schützengräben fortgesetzt - da, wo auch der Schlieffen-Plan starb.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Das Britische Expeditionskorps war eine kleine Armee die hastig ins Kriegsgebiet entsendet wurde, um die Briten stärker in die Triple Entente mit den Franzosen einzubinden. Stationiert im äußersten Westen der französischen Linie, wurde das Expeditionskorps zunächst eher als politische Höflichkeitsgeste anstatt als echte Militärmacht angesehen. Als die Deutschen jedoch durch die Niederlande nach Paris vorstießen, kämpfte das Expeditionskorps in der Schlacht von Mons gegen zahlenmäßig überlegene deutsche Truppen, und obwohl das Korps aufgerieben und schließlich zum Rückzug gezwungen wurden, rettete es die französische Fünfte Armee vor der völligen Vernichtung. Die Schlacht bei Mons ist eine der berühmtesten und bedeutendsten militärischen Leistungen Großbritanniens und der Inbegriff des Britischen Expeditionskorps.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Nation Belgien entstand am Ende der Napoleonischen Ära als Teil des Kräfteausgleichs zwischen den europäischen Mächten, war jedoch lange Zeit ein besonders enger Verbündeter von Großbritannien. Für die Invasionspläne nach Frankreich musste die deutsche Armee über Belgien einfallen. Tatsächlich wurde in frühen Versionen des Plans postuliert, die belgische Armee würde eine Ehrengarde für die durchmarschierende deutsche Armee entlang der Straßen aufstellen – eine höchst inkorrekte Annahme, wie sich herausstellen sollte.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Stadt Lüttich war von einer Reihe Befestigungen umgeben und stellte für die deutsche Armee 1914 ein beträchtliches militärisches Hindernis dar. Diese Befestigungen, auch wenn sie sich in vielen Fällen gut schlugen, konnten sich aber nicht gegen die speziell für diese Einnahme solcher Befestigungen gebauten Belagerungskanonen halten. Der Zusammenbruch der Befestigungen Lüttichs und die Grausamkeiten der deutschen Armee an der Bevölkerung führten zu einem Umschwung der öffentlichen Meinung gegen Deutschland, vor allem in Großbritannien.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Das kleine Herzogtum Luxemburg liegt zwischen Frankreich und Deutschland und ist außerdem das Zentrum eines wichtigen Eisenbahnknotenpunktes zwischen diesen Ländern. Die Einnahme der Bahnanlagen war entscheidend für die deutschen Pläne zur Invasion Frankreichs, daher wurde Luxemburg im Jahr 1914 als eine der ersten Kriegshandlungen eingenommen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Seit dem Desaster beim Deutsch-Französischen Krieg im Jahr 1870, bei dem die preußische Armee die französische aufgerieben, den französischen Kaiser gefangen genommen und für den folgenden Frieden erniedrigende Bedingungen gestellt hatte, darunter die Abgabe des Gebiets Elsaß-Lothringen im Osten Frankreichs, hatte sich Frankreich sich auf einen Krieg mit Deutschland vorbereitet. Eine ganze Generation von Politikern und Offizieren war im Schatten dieser Niederlage aufgewachsen und entschlossen, die eigene Ehre wiederherzustellen, wenn nicht gar Vergeltung für die Niederlage zu üben.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Frankreichs wichtigsten militärischen Verbündeten waren Russland und Großbritannien und es war die russische Kriegserklärung an Österreich-Ungarn, die zum Eintritt Frankreichs führte, um den Verbündeten zur Seite zu stehen. Frankreich konzentrierte sich jedoch hauptsächlich auf den eigenen Kampf gegen Deutschland statt gegen Österreich-Ungarn. Zu diesem Zweck galten die primären Anstrengungen Frankreichs bei Kriegsausbruch einem Angriff auf Elsaß-Lothringen, um diese Gebiete schnell zurückzuerobern, weshalb die nördlichen Grenzen zu Belgien und Luxemburg nur schwach verteidigt waren. Die französischen Kriegspläne unterschätzen die Anzahl der deutschen Truppen, die entlang dieser Achse angreifen würden, erheblich (man nahm an, dass die Deutschen über die Ardennen kommen würden). Die Armeen waren so schon direkt zu Beginn des Krieges zu einer abrupten Planänderung gezwungen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Eine Generation vor Ausbruch des Ersten Weltkrieges hatte Preußen Frankreich die größte militärische Niederlage seit dem Ende der Napoleonischen Ära beschert, in deren Folge sich die moderne Nation Deutschland bildete. Deutschen Politikern war durchaus klar, dass die den Franzosen abverlangten Bedingungen den Samen für einen potenziellen neuen Konflikt säten – und machten sich daran, sich auf den nächsten Krieg vorzubereiten.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Unterzeichnung des Triple Entente—einer militärischen Allianz zwischen Frankreich, Großbritannien und Russland — versetzte Deutschland in eine prekäre militärische Lage, da es nun im Osten und Westen von militärischen Widersachern umgeben war. Die Hauptstrategie, die vor dem Ersten Weltkrieg formuliert wurde, war, im Westen Frankreich im einen einzigen, massiven entscheidenden Schlag zu versetzen, bevor Russland die Gelegenheit hatte, seinen enormen Vorteil an Mannstärke im Osten zum Tragen zu bringen. Das wurde zum treibenden politischen Ziel des Schlieffen-Plans.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Im Vorfeld des Ersten Weltkriegs gab es nur wenige Armeen auf der Welt, die so gut ausgebildet und vorbereitet waren wie die deutschen Militärstreitkräfte. Und doch war Vorbereitung und Ausbildung nicht genug, um das schnelle Ende herbeizuführen, das den Planern vorgeschwebt hatte.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Großbritanniens Teilnahme an der Triple Entente (der militärischen Allianz zwischen Frankreich, Großbritannien und Russland) war bei Weitem keine vorhersehbare Entscheidung. Durch die lang anhaltende militärische Konkurrenz zwischen Frankreich und Großbritannien, die bis zu den Zeiten Napoleons zurückreicht, sowie verwandtschaftliche Bande zwischen den Königsfamilien Großbritanniens und Deutschlands, war es gar nicht so abwegig, dass sich Großbritannien stattdessen den Mittelmächten anschließen würde. Letztendlich trat Großbritannien aber der Entente bei, weil viele wegen der sich zuspitzenden Konkurrenz zwischen Deutschland und Großbritannien eine Eindämmung der wachsenden Macht Deutschlands anstrebten.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Vor Ausbruch des Ersten Weltkriegs gab es keine Garantie, dass Großbritannien Streitkräfte nach Kontinentaleuropa entsenden würde. Erst der konstante Druck einer kleinen Gruppe von Offizieren sowohl aus der französischen als auch aus der britischen Armee führte dazu, dass Großbritannien eine kleine Streitmacht auf französischen Boden schickte. Tatsächlich war der Kaiser schockiert, als die Briten Deutschland den Krieg erklärten und verkündete, sie hätten "wegen eines bloßen Papierfetzens" einen "närrischen Fehler" begangen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Nation Belgien entstand am Ende der Napoleonischen Ära als Teil des Kräfteausgleichs zwischen den europäischen Mächten, war jedoch lange Zeit ein besonders enger Verbündeter von Großbritannien. Für die Invasionspläne nach Frankreich musste die deutsche Armee über Belgien einfallen. Tatsächlich wurde in frühen Versionen des Plans postuliert, die belgische Armee würde eine Ehrengarde für die durchmarschierende deutsche Armee entlang der Straßen aufstellen – eine höchst inkorrekte Annahme, wie sich herausstellen sollte.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Die Stadt Lüttich war von einer Reihe Befestigungen umgeben und stellte für die deutsche Armee 1914 ein beträchtliches militärisches Hindernis dar. Diese Befestigungen, auch wenn sie sich in vielen Fällen gut schlugen, konnten sich aber nicht gegen die speziell für diese Einnahme solcher Befestigungen gebauten Belagerungskanonen halten. Der Zusammenbruch der Befestigungen Lüttichs und die Grausamkeiten der deutschen Armee an der Bevölkerung führten zu einem Umschwung der öffentlichen Meinung gegen Deutschland, vor allem in Großbritannien.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ein Feldherr ist ein Offizier, der für einen großen Teil des Militärs einer Nation verantwortlich ist, in der Regel für eine ganze Front. Er muss sowohl den Einsatzplan seiner Armee verstehen als auch bereit sein, diesen an die Veränderungen während des Krieges anzupassen. Auch wenn er mit untergeordneten Kommandanten zusammenarbeitet und der Generalstab ihn berät, hängen Erfolg oder Niederlage seiner Armee von seinem Urteilsvermögen ab.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ein Feldherr ist ein Offizier, der für einen großen Teil des Militärs einer Nation verantwortlich ist, in der Regel für eine ganze Front. Er muss sowohl den Einsatzplan seiner Armee verstehen als auch bereit sein, diesen an die Veränderungen während des Krieges anzupassen. Auch wenn er mit untergeordneten Kommandanten zusammenarbeitet und der Generalstab ihn berät, hängen Erfolg oder Niederlage seiner Armee von seinem Urteilsvermögen ab.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ein Feldherr ist ein Offizier, der für einen großen Teil des Militärs einer Nation verantwortlich ist, in der Regel für eine ganze Front. Er muss sowohl den Einsatzplan seiner Armee verstehen als auch bereit sein, diesen an die Veränderungen während des Krieges anzupassen. Auch wenn er mit untergeordneten Kommandanten zusammenarbeitet und der Generalstab ihn berät, hängen Erfolg oder Niederlage seiner Armee von seinem Urteilsvermögen ab.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ein Feldherr ist ein Offizier, der für einen großen Teil des Militärs einer Nation verantwortlich ist, in der Regel für eine ganze Front. Er muss sowohl den Einsatzplan seiner Armee verstehen als auch bereit sein, diesen an die Veränderungen während des Krieges anzupassen. Auch wenn er mit untergeordneten Kommandanten zusammenarbeitet und der Generalstab ihn berät, hängen Erfolg oder Niederlage seiner Armee von seinem Urteilsvermögen ab.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ein Feldherr ist ein Offizier, der für einen großen Teil des Militärs einer Nation verantwortlich ist, in der Regel für eine ganze Front. Er muss sowohl den Einsatzplan seiner Armee verstehen als auch bereit sein, diesen an die Veränderungen während des Krieges anzupassen. Auch wenn er mit untergeordneten Kommandanten zusammenarbeitet und der Generalstab ihn berät, hängen Erfolg oder Niederlage seiner Armee von seinem Urteilsvermögen ab.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Das Hauptquartier ist der Ort, an dem die Operationspläne der Armee zu Befehlen für das Schlachtfeld ausgearbeitet werden. Es ist durch Boten und Telegraph mit den untergeordneten Kommandanten an der Frontlinie verbunden und oft nur provisorisch aufgebaut, da die sich ständig verschiebenden Schlachtlinien das Oberkommando in Bewegung halten. um immer in der Nähe des Geschehens zu sein.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Feldherr|Feldherrn|Feldherrn|Feldherrn|Feldherr</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Erhöht die Stärke Eurer Außenverteidigungen, um nahezu allen Angriffen zu wiederstehen, mit Ausnahme der geballtesten Anstürme.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Kriegsmaschine-Sieg</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Als Deutschland müsst Ihr Paris innerhalb des Zeitlimits einnehmen. Als Frankreich müsst Ihr Paris gegen die Eroberung verteidigen, bis die Zeit abgelaufen ist.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+3 [ICON_Strength] Kampfstärke für Landeinheiten im Umkreis von 2 Geländefeldern.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+3 [ICON_Strength] Kampfbonus durch Großen General.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+100 Trefferpunkte in allen Städten.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+6 [ICON_Strength] Kampfstärke für Artillerieeinheiten.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Ermöglicht das Bilden und Ausbilden von Armeen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Gewährt 2 kostenlose [ICON_GreatGeneral] Große Generäle in Eurer [ICON_Capital] Hauptstadt.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+5 [ICON_Strength] Kampfstärke für alle Einheiten.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Unterstützungseinheit des Mittelalters. Erfordert zum Produzieren eine Waffenkammer. Kann Eisenbahnen-, Festungs- und Landepisten-Modernisierungen bauen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Kontrolle über Paris</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Kontrolle über Paris</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Feldmarschall</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Militärisches Können beweist man nicht durch langwierige Kampagnen, sondern durch den entscheidenden Sieg.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>General</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Kommandieren ist die Kunst, die Streitkräfte im Krieg erfolgreich und mühelos zu lenken.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Oberst</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Zwischen Information und Intuition stehen Erfolg und Fehlschlag auf Messers Schneide.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Major</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Wo Mut ist, ist auch Kühnheit. Wo Kühnheit ist, ist auch Schwung. Wo Schwung ist, ist der Sieg.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Kapitän</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Sieg, wenn möglich, aber Ehre über alles.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Flugzeuge|Flugzeuge|Flugzeugen|Flugzeuge|Flugzeuge</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Befestigungen|Befestigungen|Befestigungen|Befestigungen|Befestigungen</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Schwere Artillerie|Schwere Artillerie|Schweren Artillerie|Schweren Artillerie|Schwere Artillerie</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Logistik|Logistik|Logistik|Logistik|Logistik</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Kommando|Kommando|Kommando|Kommandos|Kommando</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>Industriel. Kriegsführung|Industriel. Kriegsführung|Industriel. Kriegsführung|Industriel. Kriegsführung|Industriel. Kriegsführung</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>{1_Day}. August 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>{1_Day}. September 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} Industriel. Kriegsführung</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="de_DE">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} schwere Artillerie</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Fortezza|la Fortezza|una Fortezza</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Quartier generale|il Quartier generale|un Quartier generale</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Lille</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Reims</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Nancy</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Belfort</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Orléans</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Chartres</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Colonia</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Coblenza</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Mannheim</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Strassburg</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Colmar</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Anversa</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Liegi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Namur</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Mons</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Lussemburgo</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>I tedeschi avevano progettato cannoni d'assedio speciali per abbattere le difese dell'anello di forti che proteggeva il Belgio. Questi cannoni ebbero un enorme successo, causando la caduta dei forti ancor prima di quanto i progettisti avessero pianificato. I francesi, da parte loro, svilupparono sofisticati cannoni d'artiglieria da 75 mm che si dimostrarono versatili e affidabili. Né gli uni né gli altri, comunque, riuscirono a infrangere lo stallo della guerra di trincea: per far questo sarà necessario attendere gli sviluppi tecnologici nel campo dell'aviazione e dei carri armati e l'introduzione di nuove tattiche per piccole unità.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La logistica è il processo che permette di fornire approvvigionamenti a un esercito per rimpiazzare tutto ciò che è stato consumato o perduto. Non è un'attività romantica, ma il successo in un conflitto dipende in gran parte da questi aspetti, che devono essere curati nei minimi particolari. Come si dice, i dilettanti studiano tattica; gli esperti studiano logistica. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Dopo l'epoca napoleonica gli ufficiali militari cominciarono a incorporare nel loro lavoro una fase di pianificazione strategica e operativa. Il comando militare ha il compito di tradurre gli obiettivi politici che hanno portato la nazione in guerra in obiettivi militari. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>In una guerra totale, tutte le risorse dello stato sono messe al servizio dello sforzo bellico. In una società industriale, questo significa ripensare completamente la struttura industriale perché si dedichi alla produzione di armi, addestrare gran parte della popolazione in preparazione di una leva di massa e indirizzare l'economia attraverso esplicite direttive politiche. Tutto questo può trasformare la società, producendo effetti che perdurano molto dopo la fine del conflitto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Negli anni immediatamente precedenti allo scoppio della Prima guerra mondiale, l'invenzione della mitragliatrice e dei nuovi proiettili d'artiglieria ad alto potenziale esplosivo portò alla parallela evoluzione delle fortificazioni. L'esteso sistema di trincee sul fronte occidentale può essere considerato l'espressione tangibile della preminenza della difesa sull'offesa per gran parte del conflitto. Allo stesso modo, le tattiche moderne sviluppate dal 1916 in poi, con l'utilizzo combinato di fanteria e carri armati, possono essere considerate alla luce della necessità di superare tale supremazia della difesa.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>All'inizio della Prima guerra mondiale, l'aviazione stava ancora muovendo i primi passi e gli aerei erano macchine costose e inaffidabili usate solo per la ricognizione. Alla fine del conflitto erano utilizzati per attacchi tattici e bombardamenti strategici: dopo aver subito una rapidissima evoluzione in quel crogiolo che è la guerra, erano diventati un caposaldo di ogni esercito del pianeta. La ricerca e lo sviluppo erano così costosi che in molti casi richiedevano l'intervento dello stato o una collaborazione pubblico-privato.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Dopo la disastrosa battaglia di Sedan, durante la guerra franco-prussiana del 1870, i militari francesi dovettero riprendersi dalle catastrofiche perdite subite e superare le umilianti conseguenze politiche del conflitto per ricostruire l'esercito francese e farne uno degli apparati militari più potenti d'Europa. Mentre i tedeschi preferivano definire piani operativi di battaglia estremamente dettagliati, i generali francesi cominciarono ad abbracciare la dottrina delle offensive flessibili.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>L'idea era che l'esercito mantenesse l'abbrivio attraverso un attacco costante alle linee nemiche, sfruttando senza pietà ogni punto debole non appena questo dovesse manifestarsi. Il nemico non sarebbe mai stato in grado di riorganizzarsi, l'iniziativa sarebbe rimasta dalla parte francese e le avanzate dei tedeschi sarebbero state contenute da contrattacchi rapidissimi. Quest'approccio avrebbe dovuto applicarsi a tutti i livelli, dal singolo battaglione all'intero teatro di battaglia: laddove l'invasore era debole, i francesi avrebbero attaccato.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Uno dei grandi paradossi dell'agosto del 1914 è che mentre i francesi vacillavano lungo il fronte dei paesi Bassi, nello stesso momento stavano riuscendo ad avanzare in Alsazia e Lorena. Questi progressi però dovettero essere interrotti per inviare i rinforzi a salvare Parigi. Alla fine di quell'anno lo spirito secondo cui occorreva "attaccare sempre" era ormai svanito: il fronte occidentale era definito dalle trincee.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il successo dell'armata prussiana durante la guerra del 1870 dimostrò l'efficacia di una pianificazione metodica, che arrivava a definire con delle tabelle gli orari di marcia delle truppe e gli spostamenti dei vagoni. Considerando inevitabile una guerra futura contro la Francia, il conte von Schlieffen, capo del comando militare tedesco, progettò un piano per un'invasione che sarebbe passata dai Paesi Bassi per arrivare a Parigi da nord. Per essere eseguito con successo questo piano richiedeva una grande concentrazione di truppe all'estremità occidentale del fronte tedesco, ma non riuscì a essere eseguito nella sua interezza.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Con la guerra che premeva su due fronti, l'alto comando tedesco trasferì alcune delle forze che avrebbero dovuto attaccare a ovest su un fronte completamente diverso (specificatamente, verso la Russia). L'esercito tedesco travolse con successo le difese nei Paesi Bassi e le forze francesi dovettero ripiegare, offrendo così al comando della Germania un obiettivo invitante. Tuttavia entrarono in gioco vari fattori, tra cui la riduzione delle truppe destinate al piano Schlieffen, alcuni movimenti improvvisati delle truppe tedesche in risposta alle azioni francesi e, non ultima, la strenua resistenza opposta dai soldati francesi e inglesi. Tutto questo fece sì che quello che avrebbe dovuto essere un colpo di grazia non raggiungesse pienamente il suo obiettivo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>I tedeschi avevano puntato tutto e avevano perduto: la guerra si consolidò in un inferno che durò quattro anni, durante i quali il piano Schlieffen andò in fumo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La British Expeditionary Force era un piccolo esercito dislocato in fretta e furia con lo scopo esplicito di rinsaldare l'alleanza tra Inghilterra e Francia. Posizionata all'estremità occidentale della linea francese, inizialmente fu considerata più una cortesia politica che una forza militare di qualche rilievo. Tuttavia, quando i tedeschi attraversarono i Paesi Bassi per scendere verso Parigi, la BEF si trovò a fronteggiare un nemico numericamente superiore alla battaglia di Mons. Dopo aver subito ingenti perdite alla fine fu costretta a ritirarsi, ma la sua azione salvò la Quinta Armata francese dalla distruzione totale. La battaglia di Mons è rimasta famosa come una delle imprese militari della Gran Bretagna più celebrate, scrivendo per sempre nella storia il nome della BEF.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La nazione del Belgio era stata creata alla fine dell'epoca napoleonica all'interno del bilanciamento delle potenze europee, ma da tempo era legata alla Gran Bretagna da un'alleanza speciale. Il piano d'invasione della Francia prevedeva che l'esercito tedesco passasse dal Belgio. In effetti, le prime versioni del piano ipotizzavano che l'esercito belga avrebbe fornito una guardia d'onore lungo le strade che i tedeschi avrebbero dovuto utilizzare: una supposizione che si sarebbe rivelata del tutto scorretta. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La città di Liegi, circondata da una serie di forti, rappresentò il primo ostacolo militare significativo per l'esercito tedesco nel 1914. I forti combatterono valorosamente, ma non poterono resistere all'assalto portato da armi d'assedio che erano state progettate specificatamente allo scopo di abbatterli. Il crollo delle fortificazioni di Liegi e le crudeltà perpetrate dai tedeschi nei confronti della popolazione belga ebbero l'effetto di orientare l'opinione pubblica contro la Germania, specialmente in Inghilterra.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il piccolissimo principato del Lussemburgo si trova al confine tra Francia e Germania, tanto da rappresentare un fondamentale snodo ferroviario tra le due nazioni. La cattura delle sue linee ebbe un'importanza critica nel piano tedesco di invasione della Francia: di conseguenza, nel 1914 l'invasione del Lussemburgo fu una delle prime azioni della Grande guerra. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La Francia si stava preparando a una guerra contro la Germania sin dalla disastrosa Guerra franco-prussiana del 1870, in cui l'esercito prussiano aveva sbaragliato quello francese, catturato l'imperatore e ottenuto nei successivi accordi di pace delle concessioni umilianti per la Francia, tra cui la cessazione dei suoi territori dell'Alsazia e della Lorena nella parte est del paese. Un'intera generazione di politici e ufficiali francesi era cresciuta all'ombra di questa disfatta ed era assetata di rivincita, se non di una vera e propria vendetta. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Gli alleati militari più importanti della Francia erano la Russia e la Gran Bretagna. In effetti, fu proprio la dichiarazione di guerra contro l'impero Austro-ungarico da parte della Russia a provocare la sua entrata in guerra. La Francia, comunque, più che sull'impero era concentrata soprattutto sulla propria rivalità con la Germania. A questo fine, allo scoppio della guerra la prima azione francese fu attaccare Alsazia e Lorena con l'obiettivo di riconquistare rapidamente quei territori, lasciando relativamente sguarnito il confine settentrionale con Belgio e Lussemburgo. I piani francesi sottovalutarono rovinosamente la quantità di forze tedesche che avrebbero attaccato lungo quell'asse, presumendo che sarebbero arrivate piuttosto dalle Ardenne. Questo obbligò le armate francesi a cambiare rapidamente i piani subito dopo l'inizio del conflitto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Una generazione prima dello scoppio della Prima guerra mondiale, l'esercito prussiano aveva inflitto alla Francia la più grave sconfitta militare dalla fine dell'epoca napoleonica. Una delle conseguenze era stata la formazione della moderna Germania. I politici tedeschi avevano ben chiaro il fatto che i termini imposti ai francesi avevano contribuito a gettare i semi di un conflitto successivo... che cominciarono subito a preparare. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La firma della Triplice intesa, l'alleanza militare tra Francia, Gran Bretagna e Russia, mise la Germania in una posizione precaria, dato che ora si trovava circondata da avversari a est e ovest. La strategia elaborata prima della Prima guerra mondiale prevedeva di sferrare un rapido, durissimo colpo per abbattere la Francia prima che la Russia avesse il tempo di sfruttare l'enorme vantaggio numerico sul fronte orientale. Questo divenne l'obiettivo politico del Piano Schlieffen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Alla vigilia della Prima guerra mondiale, pochi eserciti al mondo potevano dirsi preparati e ben addestrati come quello tedesco. Ma la preparazione e l'addestramento non furono sufficienti a portare il conflitto a una conclusione rapida, come gli autori del piano avevano immaginato.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La partecipazione dell'Inghilterra alla Triplice intesa (l'alleanza militare tra Francia, Gran Bretagna e Russia) non fu affatto un avvenimento scontato. La competizione tra Francia e Gran Bretagna era vecchia di secoli, risalendo a ben prima di Napoleone. Inoltre il legame tra la famiglia reale inglese e quella tedesca rendeva plausibile l'entrata dell'Inghilterra in quella che sarebbe diventata la Quadruplice alleanza. La ragione principale della partecipazione britannica all'Intesa è da ricercare nella rapida ascesa della Germania, che spinse molti inglesi a desiderare che si mettesse un freno al potere tedesco. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Alla vigilia della Prima guerra mondiale non c'era alcuna garanzia che la Gran Bretagna avrebbe inviato forze militari nell'Europa continentale. Fu solo grazie alla pressione costante di un piccolo gruppo di ufficiali sia francesi sia britannici che l'Inghilterra inviò un piccolo contingente sul suolo francese. In realtà, lo stesso Kaiser rimase sbalordito dalla dichiarazione di guerra da parte degli inglesi, dichiarando che avevano commesso "uno sciocco errore" a causa di "un misero pezzo di carta".</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La nazione del Belgio era stata creata alla fine dell'epoca napoleonica all'interno del bilanciamento delle potenze europee, ma da tempo era legata alla Gran Bretagna da un'alleanza speciale. Il piano d'invasione della Francia prevedeva che l'esercito tedesco passasse dal Belgio. In effetti, le prime versioni del piano ipotizzavano che l'esercito belga avrebbe fornito una guardia d'onore lungo le strade che i tedeschi avrebbero dovuto utilizzare: una supposizione che si sarebbe rivelata del tutto scorretta.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La città di Liegi, circondata da una serie di forti, rappresentò il primo ostacolo militare significativo per l'esercito tedesco nel 1914. I forti combatterono valorosamente, ma non poterono resistere all'assalto portato da armi d'assedio che erano state progettate specificatamente allo scopo di abbatterli. Il crollo delle fortificazioni di Liegi e le crudeltà perpetrate dai tedeschi nei confronti della popolazione belga ebbero l'effetto di orientare l'opinione pubblica contro la Germania, specialmente in Inghilterra.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un feldmaresciallo è un ufficiale responsabile di gran parte dell'apparato militare di una nazione, di solito lungo un intero fronte. Un feldmaresciallo deve comprendere i piani operativi del suo esercito ed essere pronto a modificarli qualora lo svolgimento del conflitto dovesse dimostrarne la necessità. Sebbene operi attraverso i comandanti subordinati e sia consigliato dal suo staff, il successo o il fallimento dell'azione militare ricade sulle sue spalle. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un feldmaresciallo è un ufficiale responsabile di gran parte dell'apparato militare di una nazione, di solito lungo un intero fronte. Un feldmaresciallo deve comprendere i piani operativi del suo esercito ed essere pronto a modificarli qualora lo svolgimento del conflitto dovesse dimostrarne la necessità. Sebbene operi attraverso i comandanti subordinati e sia consigliato dal suo staff, il successo o il fallimento dell'azione militare ricade sulle sue spalle.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un feldmaresciallo è un ufficiale responsabile di gran parte dell'apparato militare di una nazione, di solito lungo un intero fronte. Un feldmaresciallo deve comprendere i piani operativi del suo esercito ed essere pronto a modificarli qualora lo svolgimento del conflitto dovesse dimostrarne la necessità. Sebbene operi attraverso i comandanti subordinati e sia consigliato dal suo staff, il successo o il fallimento dell'azione militare ricade sulle sue spalle.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un feldmaresciallo è un ufficiale responsabile di gran parte dell'apparato militare di una nazione, di solito lungo un intero fronte. Un feldmaresciallo deve comprendere i piani operativi del suo esercito ed essere pronto a modificarli qualora lo svolgimento del conflitto dovesse dimostrarne la necessità. Sebbene operi attraverso i comandanti subordinati e sia consigliato dal suo staff, il successo o il fallimento dell'azione militare ricade sulle sue spalle.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Un feldmaresciallo è un ufficiale responsabile di gran parte dell'apparato militare di una nazione, di solito lungo un intero fronte. Un feldmaresciallo deve comprendere i piani operativi del suo esercito ed essere pronto a modificarli qualora lo svolgimento del conflitto dovesse dimostrarne la necessità. Sebbene operi attraverso i comandanti subordinati e sia consigliato dal suo staff, il successo o il fallimento dell'azione militare ricade sulle sue spalle.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il quartier generale è il luogo dove i piani operativi di un esercito sono trasformati in ordini da trasmettere sul campo. Un quartier generale dev'essere collegato ai comandanti di rango inferiore attraverso una rete di messaggeri o di comunicazioni elettriche. Spesso la sua posizione è solo temporanea, dato che la linea del fronte può spostarsi rapidamente e il comando supremo deve sempre trovarsi vicino all'azione.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Feldmaresciallo</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Aumenta la forza delle tue difese esterne in modo che possano resistere a tutti gli attacchi tranne i più concentrati.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Vittoria Macchina da Guerra</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Giocando con la Germania devi catturare Parigi prima che finisca il tempo. Giocando con la Francia devi difendere Parigi dalla cattura finché non finisce il tempo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+3 alla [ICON_Strength] Forza di combattimento delle unità terrestri in un raggio di 2 caselle.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+3 alla [ICON_Strength] Forza di combattimento dal Grande Generale.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+100 punti ferita in tutte le città.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+6 alla [ICON_Strength] Forza di combattimento delle unità di artiglieria.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Permette la formazione e l'addestramento di Eserciti.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Fornisce 2 [ICON_GreatGeneral] Grandi Generali gratuiti nella tua [ICON_Capital] capitale.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+5 alla [ICON_Strength] Forza di combattimento di tutte le unità.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Unità di supporto di epoca medievale. La sua produzione richiede un'Armeria. Può costruire Ferrovie e i miglioramenti Forte e Pista d'atterraggio.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Controllo di Parigi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Controllo di Parigi</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Feldmaresciallo</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La prova della maestria militare non è nelle campagne protratte, ma nelle vittorie decisive.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Generale</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il comando è l'arte di dirigere le forze di guerra con successo e senza sforzo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Colonnello</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Il successo e il fallimento corrono sul filo di una lama tra informazione e intuito.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Maggiore</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Dove c'è coraggio c'è audacia. Dove c'è audacia c'è slancio. Dove c'è slancio c'è la vittoria.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Capitano</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>La vittoria è possibile, ma prima di tutto viene l'onore.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Aerei</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Fortificazioni</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Artiglieria pesante</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Logistica</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Comando militare</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>Guerra industriale</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>{1_Day} agosto 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>{1_Day} settembre 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} Guerra industriale</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="it_IT">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} Artiglieria pesante</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>要塞</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>本営</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>リール</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ランス</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ナンシー</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ベルフォール</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>オルレアン</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>シャルトル</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ケルン</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>コブレンツ</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>マンハイム</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ストラスブルク</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>コルマール</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>アントワープ</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>リエージュ</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ナミュール</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>モンス</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ルクセンブルク</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ベルギーを幾重にも守っていた要塞線に穴を開けるため、ドイツ軍は専用の攻囲砲を開発した。これらは大きな威力を発揮し、要塞は軍上層部の予想より早く陥落した。対するフランス軍も、頑丈で柔軟な運用が可能な、高性能な75mm砲を開発した。しかしどちらも、それだけでは塹壕戦の膠着状態を打破するに至らず、戦車や航空機といった新兵器と小部隊戦術の導入によって、ようやくそれは成し遂げられた。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>兵站とは軍隊に物資を補給して消費分を補うことを言う。華やかな仕事ではないが、戦争の行方はこうしたことがきちんとおこなわれるかどうかに左右されるのだ。「素人は戦術を研究し、専門家は兵站を研究する」と言われるゆえんである</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ナポレオン戦争後、上級将校の職務には、戦略と作戦の策定も含まれるようになった。現在では、戦争の政治的な目標を軍事的な作戦目標に落とし込むことを専門とする司令部付将校も存在している。 </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>総力戦では、国家が保有するすべての資源が戦争に投入される。工業化された社会においてこれは、産業構造を完全に再編し、兵器の増産や国民の徴兵、政府による経済指導などを実施することを意味する。この結果、戦争終結後に社会が元の状態に戻るには、ときとして長い時間を要することになる。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>第一次世界大戦の勃発に先立って機関銃や新型の榴弾が発明されたことは、陣地の構築にも変化をもたらした。大戦の大半の期間、防御側は攻撃側に対して圧倒的優位に立っており、西部戦線に張り巡らされた広大な塹壕網は、これを目に見える形で示したものと言えた。1916年以降は歩兵と戦車による近代的な戦術が発展したが、これも防御側優位の状況をくつがえすための努力と見なすことが可能である。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>第一次世界大戦が勃発した時点では、航空機はまだ生まれてから間もなく、高価な上に信頼性も乏しいため、偵察くらいしか使い道がなかった。しかし過酷な戦争の中で急速な進化を遂げた結果、大戦が終結する頃にはあらゆる主要国の軍隊にとって欠かせない戦力として、戦術攻撃から戦略爆撃まで幅広く用いられるようになっていた。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>1870年に勃発した普仏戦争においてセダンの戦いで大敗を喫した後、軍首脳部はフランス軍をヨーロッパでも一級の軍隊として再建するため、壊滅的な損害と屈辱的な講和条件からの回復を図らねばならなかった。ドイツ軍が事前に綿密な計画を立ててから戦いに臨むことを好んだのに対し、フランス軍が最も重視したのは攻勢の柔軟性であった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>彼らはこう考えた。軍の勢いは、敵戦線を絶えず攻撃し、弱点が生じた場合には容赦なくそこを突くことで維持される。この結果、敵は体勢を立て直すことができず、戦闘の主導権はフランス軍が握りつづけることができる。敵があくまでも前進してこようとした場合には、即座に反撃してそれを阻止すればよい、と。侵略者の弱い部分を突くというこの教義は、大隊レベルから戦域レベルまで適用された。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>だが、1914年8月の状況は彼らが望むようには推移しなかった。フランス軍は低地帯諸国に戦線を構築していたが、アルザス・ロレーヌ地方を敵に突破され、その進軍を押しとどめなければパリを救うための増援は送れない状況にあったのだ。1914年末の時点で、「常に攻撃」の精神は消えうせ、西部戦線は泥沼の塹壕戦と化していた。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>1870年に勃発した普仏戦争におけるプロイセン軍の勝利は、兵士の移動や貨物列車の運行のスケジュールまで定めた、整然とした包括的な計画の有効性を示すものだった。再びフランスと戦争になることは避けられないと考えていたドイツ軍参謀総長シュリーフェン伯爵は、将来に備え、低地帯諸国を通過してパリに南下するというフランス侵攻計画、いわゆるシュリーフェン・プランを策定した。この侵攻計画の達成には、ドイツ軍の最西端に戦力を集中させることが欠かせなかったが、シュリーフェン・プランが完全な形で実施されることはついになかった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>2つの戦線を抱えることになったドイツ軍総司令部は、本来は西部戦線に配置すべき戦力の一部をまったく違う戦線 (つまり対ロシア戦線) に振り向けた。また、ドイツ軍が低地帯諸国の突破に成功したことはフランス軍を狼狽させ、その戦線に突出部を生じさせる結果になったが、これがドイツ参謀本部の目には魅力的な目標と映った。結局、シュリーフェン･プランに投入された戦力の不足、フランス軍の動きに惑わされたドイツ軍の場当たり的な行動、そしてフランス軍とイギリス軍の頑強な抵抗など、さまざまな要因によってドイツ軍の渾身の一撃は目標を達成するにいたらなかった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ドイツ軍は賭けに負けた。戦争はシュリーフェン・プランが頓挫した地点に構築された戦線を挟んで膠着状態に陥り、4年におよぶ地獄の塹壕戦が幕を開けたのだった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>フランスとの同盟関係をより強固にするために戦地に急派されたイギリス海外派遣軍 (BEF) は、けっして大規模なものではなかった。フランス軍の戦線の西端に配置された彼らは、当初、実行力をともなった軍事力というよりは政治的なジェスチャーだと思われていた。しかし、ドイツ軍が低地帯諸国を南下してパリに迫ったとき、彼らはモンスの戦いにおいて数で勝る相手と激戦を展開。大損害を出しつつも最終的には敵軍を後退に追い込み、フランス第5軍を壊滅の危機から救ったのであった。このモンスの戦いは、イギリスにとって最も誇らしい名誉ある勝利のひとつであり、モンスの戦いと言えば誰もがBEFを思い浮かべるほどである。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>国家としてのベルギーは、ナポレオン戦争の後、大国間の勢力均衡策の一環として成立したが、とりわけ深かったのがイギリスとの関係である。フランス侵攻計画を策定した際、ドイツ軍はベルギーを進撃路とすることを考えていた。それどころか初期の計画案では、ベルギー軍を儀仗兵として道路沿いに配置し、通過するドイツ軍を迎えさせることすら検討されていたのだ。これがどれほど的外れな目論見であったかは、歴史書を紐解けば明らかである。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>1914年にドイツ軍の侵攻が開始された当初、多数の要塞線が幾重にも取り巻いているリエージュは、最初の大きな軍事的障壁になると考えられていた。だが善戦はしたものの、これらの要塞線を突破するために開発された特殊な攻囲砲による攻撃を耐え抜くことはできなかった。リエージュ要塞の陥落とその後のドイツ軍によるベルギー国民への暴虐は、ドイツに対する国際世論の潮流を変化させた。とりわけイギリスでは、対独感情の悪化が顕著だった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ルクセンブルク大公国はフランスとドイツに挟まれた小さな国だが、ここには両国を結ぶ鉄道路線の重要な連絡駅が存在している。ドイツがフランス侵攻をくわだてた際、きわめて重要とされたのが、この車両基地の占領であった。結果としてルクセンブルクは、1914年に大戦が勃発すると、最初の侵攻目標とされた。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>1870年に勃発した普仏戦争においてフランス軍はプロイセン軍に大敗を喫した。この結果、皇帝ナポレオン3世は捕虜になり、和平交渉では東部のアルザス・ロレーヌ地方を失うなど、フランスは屈辱的な譲歩を余儀なくされた。以来、フランスは対独戦争の準備に余念がなかった。フランスの政治家と軍人は、誰もがこの敗戦の苦しみを知る世代であり、あからさまな復讐までは望まないにしても、機会さえあれば必ず雪辱を果たすと誓っていたのである。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>フランスの主な同盟国はロシアとイギリスであり、ロシアがオーストリア=ハンガリー帝国に宣戦布告したことにより、フランスも同盟国として参戦することになった。しかしフランスの主な敵は、オーストリア=ハンガリー帝国ではなくドイツ帝国であった。そのため、開戦当初はアルザス・ロレーヌの早期奪回に戦力を集中させ、ベルギーおよびルクセンブルクと接する北部国境地帯にはわずかな守備戦力しか配置していなかった。だが、こうしたフランスの戦争計画は、ドイツ軍の兵力を完全に過小評価していた。やがてドイツ軍がこの方面で攻勢を開始したため (ドイツ軍はアルデンヌ地方の突破を図るものと考えられていた)、フランス軍は開戦直後に慌てて計画を変更する破目に陥ったのだった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>第一次世界大戦勃発の1世代前、プロイセン軍はフランスにナポレオン戦争以降で最大の軍事的勝利をおさめ、これが近代国家ドイツの建国につながった。だがドイツの政治家たちには先見の明があり、フランスから引き出した講和の条件は、次の戦いの火種になることを見抜いていた。そこで彼らは次なる戦争の準備に取りかかった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>三国協商 (フランス、イギリス、ロシアによる軍事同盟) の成立は、ドイツの立場を危うくするものだった。東西を軍事的な敵国に挟まれることになったからである。東部戦線においてロシア軍がその圧倒的兵数に物を言わせる前に、強力な一撃によって西部戦線のフランス軍を撃破するというのが、大戦勃発前に考えられていた戦争全体の戦略であった。これは達成すべき政治的目標として、対仏侵攻計画「シュリーフェン・プラン」にも引き継がれた。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>第一次世界大戦開戦前夜、ドイツ軍ほど練度が高く、準備も整っている軍隊は、世界中を見回してもほとんど存在しなかった。だが、いくら準備と訓練が万全でも、それだけでは作戦立案者が思い描いた戦争の早期決着には十分ではなかった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>イギリスの三国協商 (フランス、イギリス、ロシアによる軍事同盟) への参加は、けっして「当然の帰結」ではなかった。ナポレオン戦争以後、フランスとイギリスは長く軍事的な競争関係にあったし、イギリス王家とドイツ皇家の間には姻戚関係があったので、イギリスが中央同盟側についたとしても不思議ではなかったのである。イギリスが三国協商に加わったのは、ドイツとの利益の不一致が急速に増え、その勢力伸張を抑える必要があると多くの人が考えた結果であった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>第一次世界大戦の開戦前夜、イギリスが大陸に派兵する保証はどこにもなかった。だが、フランスへのイギリスの関与が小規模すぎると考えた英仏双方の少数の将校たちによるさまざまな圧力の結果、イギリスは派兵を決意することになる。実際、ドイツ皇帝はイギリスの宣戦布告に驚愕し、「くだらない紙の束」を信じて「彼らは愚かな間違いをした」と述べたと言われている。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>国家としてのベルギーは、ナポレオン戦争の後、大国間の勢力均衡策の一環として成立したが、とりわけ深かったのがイギリスとの関係である。フランス侵攻計画を策定した際、ドイツ軍はベルギーを進撃路とすることを考えていた。それどころか初期の計画案では、ベルギー軍を儀仗兵として道路沿いに配置し、通過するドイツ軍を迎えさせることすら検討されていたのだ。これがどれほど的外れな目論見であったかは、歴史書を紐解けば明らかである。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>1914年にドイツ軍の侵攻が開始された当初、多数の要塞線が幾重にも取り巻いているリエージュは、最初の大きな軍事的障壁になると考えられていた。だが善戦はしたものの、これらの要塞線を突破するために開発された特殊な攻囲砲による攻撃を耐え抜くことはできなかった。リエージュ要塞の陥落とその後のドイツ軍によるベルギー国民への暴虐は、ドイツに対する国際世論の潮流を変化させた。とりわけイギリスでは、対独感情の悪化が顕著だった。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>野戦軍司令官は、大兵力を指揮する将官であり、通常は1つの戦線全体を統括する。野戦軍司令官は作戦計画を正しく理解しつつ、その一方で戦局の変化に柔軟に対応できる人物でなくてはならない。実際の部隊指揮は隷下の指揮官たちが執り、野戦軍司令官自身も幕僚の補佐を受けるが、軍事行動の成否が彼の判断にかかっていることはまぎれもない事実である。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>野戦軍司令官は、大兵力を指揮する将官であり、通常は1つの戦線全体を統括する。野戦軍司令官は作戦計画を正しく理解しつつ、その一方で戦局の変化に柔軟に対応できる人物でなくてはならない。実際の部隊指揮は隷下の指揮官たちが執り、野戦軍司令官自身も幕僚の補佐を受けるが、軍事行動の成否が彼の判断にかかっていることはまぎれもない事実である。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>野戦軍司令官は、大兵力を指揮する将官であり、通常は1つの戦線全体を統括する。野戦軍司令官は作戦計画を正しく理解しつつ、その一方で戦局の変化に柔軟に対応できる人物でなくてはならない。実際の部隊指揮は隷下の指揮官たちが執り、野戦軍司令官自身も幕僚の補佐を受けるが、軍事行動の成否が彼の判断にかかっていることはまぎれもない事実である。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>野戦軍司令官は、大兵力を指揮する将官であり、通常は1つの戦線全体を統括する。野戦軍司令官は作戦計画を正しく理解しつつ、その一方で戦局の変化に柔軟に対応できる人物でなくてはならない。実際の部隊指揮は隷下の指揮官たちが執り、野戦軍司令官自身も幕僚の補佐を受けるが、軍事行動の成否が彼の判断にかかっていることはまぎれもない事実である。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>野戦軍司令官は、大兵力を指揮する将官であり、通常は1つの戦線全体を統括する。野戦軍司令官は作戦計画を正しく理解しつつ、その一方で戦局の変化に柔軟に対応できる人物でなくてはならない。実際の部隊指揮は隷下の指揮官たちが執り、野戦軍司令官自身も幕僚の補佐を受けるが、軍事行動の成否が彼の判断にかかっていることはまぎれもない事実である。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>戦場で軍をどのように動かすか、そのための計画を策定する場所が本営である。本営とその隷下にある指揮官は、伝令や電報といった手段によって結ばれているが、戦線の変化に応じて司令部も移動する必要があるため (戦場から離れすぎては何かと具合が悪いのだ)、本営は恒久的な施設でない場合が多い。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>野戦軍司令官</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>外郭の防御力が向上し、よほどの攻撃でなければ耐えられるようになる。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>「機械化戦争」での勝利</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>ドイツは時間切れになる前にパリを占領しなくてはなりません。フランスは時間切れになるまでパリを守り抜く必要があります。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>2タイル以内にいる陸上ユニットの [ICON_Strength] 戦闘力+3。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>大将軍による [ICON_Strength] 戦闘ボーナス+3。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>すべての都市のヒットポイント+100。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>砲撃ユニットの [ICON_Strength] 戦闘力+6。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>大軍団の編成と訓練が可能になる。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>[ICON_Capital] 首都に [ICON_GreatGeneral] 大将軍2人が無償で現れる。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>すべてのユニットの [ICON_Strength] 戦闘力+5。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>中世の支援ユニット。生産には武器庫が必要。道路、鉄道、要塞、滑走路を建設できる。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>パリの制圧/防衛</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>パリの制圧/防衛</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>元帥</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>戦いの道を極めた証しは、長期にわたる戦闘にではなく、決定的な勝利にこそある。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>将軍</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>指揮とは戦力を的確に、そして自在に運用する技術である。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>大佐</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>成功か失敗か。情報と直感という刃の上では、どちらに天秤が傾いても不思議ではない。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>少佐</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>勇気あるところ、度胸がある。度胸あるところ、勢いがある。勢いあるところ、勝利がある。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>大尉</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>勝てるなら勝利せよ。しかし名誉はすべてに優先される。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>航空機</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>要塞化陣地</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>重砲</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>兵站</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>幕僚</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>産業戦争</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>1914年8月{1_Day}日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>1914年9月{1_Day}日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>産業戦争+{1_Amount}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="ja_JP">
      <Text>重砲+{1_Amount}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>요새</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>작전 본부</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>릴</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>랭스</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>낭시</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>벨포르</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>오를레앙</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>샤르트르</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>쾰른</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>코블렌츠</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>만하임</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>슈트라스부르크</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>콜마르</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>앤트워프</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>리에주</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>나뮈르</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>몽스</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>룩셈부르크</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>독일군은 벨기에를 둘러싼 수많은 요새의 방어 체계를 부수기 위해 특수한 공성포를 제작했습니다. 이는 계획했던 것보다 더욱 빠르게 요새들을 무너트리면서 성공적인 무기로 증명되었습니다. 프랑스군은 정교하고 강력한 75mm 야포를 개발했는데, 이 무기는 지속성 뿐 아니라 유연성 또한 갖추고 있었습니다. 하지만 이것만으로는 참호에서의 교착 상태를 타개할 수 없었기 때문에, 신기술을 이용한 탱크와 항공기를 개발하고 소부대 전술을 활용했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>병참 지원은 전투 중 손실과 지출을 대체할 물자를 보급하는 임무 절차입니다. 매력적으로 보이는 일은 아니지만, 전쟁에서의 승패는 이 특별한 임무를 얼마나 잘 수행하느냐에 따라 달려있다고 해도 과언이 아닙니다. '아마추어는 전략을 공부하고 전문가는 병참을 공부한다'라는 말도 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>나폴레옹 시대 이후, 전문 군사 장교들은 전략적이면서도 가동이 가능한 전술을 구축하기 시작했습니다. 전문 참모들은 전쟁에서 정치적인 목표를 군사적인 목표로 전환하는 작업을 담당하고 달성하며 군사적 의무를 다했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>총력전에서는 국가의 모든 자원이 전쟁을 목적으로 운용됩니다. 산업 사회에서 이는 즉, 산업 기반 시설을 전부 무기를 제작하고 상당수의 인구를 대규모 징병에 동원하기 위해 무장시키는 작업에 사용할 수 있도록 뜯어고친다는 것을 의미합니다. 공공연하게 경제를 정치적인 도구로 이용하는 것입니다. 이러한 변화를 겪고 나면, 갈등이 종식된 후에도 오랫동안 사회를 재건해야 합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>기관총이 발명되고 고성능 폭발 탄환을 사용할 수 있게 되면서, 제1차 세계대전이 일어날 때까지 방어 시설 또한 많은 변화를 거쳤습니다. 서부 전선에 설치된 대규모 참호들을 보면 대부분의 전투에서 공격보다 방어가 우위를 점했다는 사실을 알 수 있습니다. 마찬가지로, 1916년부터 계속해서 발전해 온 보병대와 탱크를 이용한 현대적 전술 또한 방어 패권주의를 극복하기 위한 노력으로 간주할 수 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>제1차 세계 대전 초반, 항공술은 아직 발달 초창기였으며 항공기는 정찰에 사용하기엔 비싸고 신뢰할 수 없는 기계 정도로 여겨졌습니다. 하지만 전쟁이 끝날 무렵, 항공기는 지구상의 거의 모든 주요 군대에서 주 무기가 되었고 전술 공격 및 전략 폭격에 활용되었습니다. 전쟁의 도가니 속에서 항공술이 급속한 발전을 거듭한 결과였습니다. 연구와 개발 과정에 막대한 비용이 필요했기 때문에, 대부분 국가 지원금을 받거나 정부-민간 합작으로 진행되었습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>1870년 프로이센 프랑스 전쟁 당시 처참히 패배한 스당 전투 이후, 프랑스의 군사 기획자들은 이 치명적인 손실과 굴욕적인 정치적 여파를 수습하고 프랑스 군대를 다시 유럽 내 일류 군대로 재건해야 했습니다. 독일이 매우 상세한 전투 작전 계획을 선호하는 것과 대조적으로, 프랑스 군사 간부들은 한층 더 유연한 형태의 공격 방침을 지지하기 시작했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>군대는 적의 전선을 끊임없이 공격하여 그로 인해 드러나는 약점을 무자비하게 공략해서 기세를 더해가야 한다고 여겼습니다. 그래야만 적이 다시 전열을 가다듬거나 반격할 수 없다는 게 프랑스 측의 생각이었습니다. 끝도 없이 진군하는 독일군에게 번개처럼 반격을 가해서 저지하는 것입니다. 이런 계획은 적이 약세일 때, 즉 프랑스 측에서 공격하려는 적군이 대대급에서 최대 전투 지구급일 경우에 적용될 수 있었습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>1914년 8월에 프랑스가 마주한 가장 역설적인 상황 중 하나는, 프랑스군이 저지대 전선을 따라 힘겹게 나아가던 중 알자스 로렌을 거쳐 오는 독일군을 맞닥뜨렸지만, 파리를 지켜낼 증강 병력을 파견하기 위해서는 이를 저지해야 한다는 것이었습니다. 그해 말, '언제나 공격하기' 정신은 결국 빛이 바랬고 서부 전선에는 참호들이 깔렸습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>1870년 프로이센 군대가 프로이센 프랑스 전쟁에서 거둔 크고 작은 승리는 체계적이고 포괄적인 군사 작전의 효용성을 입증했습니다. 여기에는 행군 부대와 전차의 진격 일정표를 짜는 것도 포함되었습니다. 프랑스와 피할 수 없는 전쟁을 치르게 될 미래를 내다본 폰 슐리펜 백작, 즉 독일 작전 참모는 프랑스 침략 계획을 미리 구상했습니다. 저지대를 지나서 남쪽으로 파리까지 내려가는 계획이었습니다. 이 침략 계획이 성공하기 위해서는 독일군이 극 서부 전선에 병력을 집중적으로 배치해야 했습니다. 하지만 이 계획이 온전히 실행되는 일은 결코 일어나지 않았습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>양쪽 전선에서 전쟁을 치르는 과정에서 독일의 상급 사령부는 서쪽 전선에 배치된 일부 병력을 완전히 다른 쪽 최전선으로 이동시켰습니다. 이때 이동한 병력은 러시아를 상대하게 되었습니다. 독일군이 성공적으로 저지대를 박살 내며 전진하자 프랑스 군대는 크게 당황하며 프랑스 전선을 따라 돌출부를 형성했고, 독일 작전 참모의 눈에 이는 명백한 표적으로 보였습니다. 하지만 슐리펜 계획에서 병력이 축소되었고, 프랑스군을 대적하기 위해 독일 부대들이 계획에 없이 이동해야 했고, 프랑스와 영국이 완강하게 저항하는 등의 여러 이유로 이전에 계획했던 결정타를 날리는 일은 실패로 돌아갔습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>독일의 도박은 실패했고, 슐리펜 계획이 가루가 되면서 전쟁은 무려 4년간 이어지는 지옥으로 변했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>영국 원정군은, 영국이 프랑스와의 협상에 한 발짝 더 가까이 다가가려는 분명한 목적을 지니고 급히 전장에 투입한 작은 규모의 군대였습니다. 프랑스의 먼 서부 전선에 위치하였으며, 처음에는 실질적인 군사력보다는 정치적인 의례에 따라 파견된 군대로 간주되었습니다. 하지만 독일군이 저지대를 따라 내려오며 파리를 향해 진격하자 영국 원정군은 몽스 전투에서 수적으로 우세한 독일군과 맞서 싸웠으며, 결국 심한 타격을 입고 퇴각해야 했음에도 불구하고 프랑스 제5군의 전멸을 막아주었습니다. 몽스 전투는 대영제국 역사상 가장 명성이 높고 명예로운 군사적 업적 중 하나로 여겨지며 영국 원정군(BEF)은 이를 가리키는 대명사가 되었습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>벨기에는 유럽에서 힘의 균형이 재조정되며 나폴레옹 시대 끝 무렵에 정식 국가로 탄생했습니다. 하지만 벨기에는 오랫동안 대영제국의 밀접한 동맹이기도 했습니다. 독일 군대는 프랑스 침략 계획을 세우면서 벨기에를 거쳐서 행군하기로 했습니다. 사실, 독일의 초기 계획에서는 독일 군대가 지나가면 벨기에 군대가 양쪽에서 둘러싸고 의장대 역할을 해 줄 것을 기대했지만, 이러한 생각은 나중에 몹시 잘못된 것으로 밝혀졌습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>리에주는 수많은 요새로 둘러싸인 도시였으며, 1914년 독일 군대가 행군할 때 첫 번째 군사적 장애물로서 방어 작전을 수행했던 곳입니다. 리에주 요새의 군인들은 제법 잘 싸웠지만, 이 요새를 깨부수기 위해 특별히 제작된 공성포를 상대로는 버틸 수가 없었습니다. 리에주의 요새들이 무너지자 독일 군대는 벨기에 국민들을 상대로 잔인한 만행을 저질렀으며, 이 때문에 영국을 필두로 주변국들의 독일에 대한 여론이 급격히 악화되었습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>룩셈부르크 공국은 프랑스와 독일 사이에 있는 조그만 나라로, 두 나라 사이를 이어주는 철도가 교차하는 중심부이기도 합니다. 독일이 프랑스를 침략하기 위해서는 반드시 이 철도역을 점령해야 했기 때문에, 프랑스 침입에 앞서 1914년에 룩셈부르크를 먼저 침략했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>프랑스는 1870년의 처참했던 프로이센 프랑스 전쟁 이후 독일과의 전쟁을 계속해서 준비해 왔습니다. 이 전쟁 당시 프로이센 군대가 프랑스 야전군을 짓밟고, 황제를 포획하고, 알자스 로렌 영토 포기 등 프랑스의 굴욕적인 양보를 요구하며 평화 협약을 끌어낸 바 있습니다. 프랑스의 전 세대 정치인과 장교들이 이러한 패배의 그림자 속에서 성장했으며, 따라서 이들은 전쟁의 정당성을 찾거나 예전의 패배에 대한 노골적인 복수심을 키웠습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>프랑스의 주요 군사 동맹국은 러시아와 영국이었고, 프랑스가 동맹국의 입장으로 전쟁에 개입하게 된 것은 러시아가 오스트리아-헝가리 제국에 대해 전쟁을 선포했기 때문입니다. 하지만, 프랑스는 오스트리아-헝가리 제국보다는 독일을 상대로 싸우는 것에 가장 집중했습니다. 따라서 프랑스는 전쟁 발발 당시 알자스 로렌 지방을 재빠르게 탈환하는 데 총력을 기울였고, 벨기에 및 룩셈부르크와 맞닿아 있는 북쪽 국경의 수비는 소홀히 하는 경향이 있었습니다. 프랑스의 작전은 경계축을 따라서 공격하는 독일 병력의 규모를 심각하게 과소평가하는 실수를 저질렀습니다. 프랑스는 독일군이 아르덴 지방을 넘어 쳐들어올 것으로 추측했지만, 전쟁이 발발하자 급히 계획을 변경해서 군대를 파견해야 했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>제1차 세계대전이 발발하기 한 세대 전, 프로이센 군대는 프랑스가 나폴레옹 시대 이후로는 맛본 적 없는 가장 처참한 패배를 안겨주었으며, 이를 발판삼아 근대 국가로서 독일의 모습을 갖추게 되었습니다. 독일 정치인들은 프랑스로부터 얻어낸 것들이 언젠가 분쟁의 씨앗이 되리라는 사실을 현실적으로 꿰뚫어 보고 있었으며, 따라서 미래의 전쟁을 준비하기 시작했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>프랑스, 영국, 러시아의 군사 동맹인 3자 협상이 체결되자 독일은 동쪽과 서쪽으로 적들에게 둘러싸이면서 군사적으로 불안정한 상황에 놓이게 되었습니다. 독일이 제1차 세계대전 이전에 세워둔 대규모 전략은, 동쪽에서 러시아가 자랑하는 막대한 병력을 보내오기도 전에 서쪽에서 프랑스를 단번에 공격해서 굉장한 치명타를 입히는 계획이었습니다. 이 전략은 슐리펜 계획이라는 강력한 정치적 목표가 되었습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>제1차 세계대전 발발 직전, 세계적으로 독일 군대만큼 잘 훈련되고 준비된 군대는 많지 않았습니다. 하지만 군사적 준비와 훈련에도 불구하고 독일이 계획했던 것만큼 전쟁을 신속하게 종결하는 것은 불가능했습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>영국이 3국 협상(프랑스, 영국, 러시아 간의 군사 동맹)에 가담한 것은 결코 처음부터 예정된 결과는 아니었습니다. 나폴레옹 시절부터 계속된 프랑스와 영국의 오랜 군사 경쟁, 영국과 독일 왕가의 유대를 고려하면 영국이 추축국에 합류하는 것이 더욱 타당한 결론처럼 보였습니다. 결국, 영국이 3국 협상에 참여한 것은 급속하게 세력을 키워가던 독일과의 경쟁에서 비롯된 것으로, 점점 더 강해지는 독일의 힘을 견제하기 위한 결정이었습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>제1차 세계대전이 일어나기 직전, 영국이 유럽 대륙에 군사를 파견할지는 불투명했습니다. 영국이 프랑스 땅에 소규모 병력을 보내기로 약속한 것에 대해서, 프랑스와 영국 양쪽의 군대에서 소수 장교들의 상당히 지속적인 압박이 있었습니다. 독일의 카이저는 실제로 영국이 독일을 상대로 전쟁을 선포한 사실에 충격을 받아서, '휴짓조각과도 같은 조약을 바탕으로 한 어리석은 실수'라고 비난했다고 합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>벨기에는 유럽에서 힘의 균형이 재조정되며 나폴레옹 시대 끝 무렵에 정식 국가로 탄생했습니다. 하지만 벨기에는 오랫동안 대영제국의 밀접한 동맹이기도 했습니다. 독일 군대는 프랑스 침략 계획을 세우면서 벨기에를 거쳐서 행군하기로 했습니다. 사실, 독일의 초기 계획에서는 독일 군대가 지나가면 벨기에 군대가 양쪽에서 둘러싸고 의장대 역할을 해 줄 것을 기대했지만, 이러한 생각은 나중에 몹시 잘못된 것으로 밝혀졌습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>리에주는 수많은 요새로 둘러싸인 도시였으며, 1914년 독일 군대가 행군할 때 첫 번째 군사적 장애물로서 방어 작전을 수행했던 곳입니다. 리에주 요새의 군인들은 제법 잘 싸웠지만, 이 요새를 깨부수기 위해 특별히 제작된 공성포를 상대로는 버틸 수가 없었습니다. 리에주의 요새들이 무너지자 독일 군대는 벨기에 국민들을 상대로 잔인한 만행을 저질렀으며, 이 때문에 영국을 필두로 주변국들의 독일에 대한 여론이 급격히 악화되었습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>야전 사령관은 국가의 군대에서 상당히 막중한 책임을 맡고 있으며 주로 전선 전체를 관리하는 장교입니다. 야전 사령관은 군대의 작전 계획을 잘 이해할 수 있어야 할 뿐 아니라 시시각각 변화하는 전쟁 중 상황에 알맞게 적용할 수 있어야 합니다. 예하 부대 지휘관을 거쳐 업무를 수행하고 작전 참모의 조언을 듣기도 하지만, 전쟁의 승패는 그의 결정에 달려 있다고 해도 과언이 아닙니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>야전 사령관은 국가의 군대에서 상당히 막중한 책임을 맡고 있으며 주로 전선 전체를 관리하는 장교입니다. 야전 사령관은 군대의 작전 계획을 잘 이해할 수 있어야 할 뿐 아니라 시시각각 변화하는 전쟁 중 상황에 알맞게 적용할 수 있어야 합니다. 예하 부대 지휘관을 거쳐 업무를 수행하고 작전 참모의 조언을 듣기도 하지만, 전쟁의 승패는 그의 결정에 달려 있다고 해도 과언이 아닙니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>야전 사령관은 국가의 군대에서 상당히 막중한 책임을 맡고 있으며 주로 전선 전체를 관리하는 장교입니다. 야전 사령관은 군대의 작전 계획을 잘 이해할 수 있어야 할 뿐 아니라 시시각각 변화하는 전쟁 중 상황에 알맞게 적용할 수 있어야 합니다. 예하 부대 지휘관을 거쳐 업무를 수행하고 작전 참모의 조언을 듣기도 하지만, 전쟁의 승패는 그의 결정에 달려 있다고 해도 과언이 아닙니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>야전 사령관은 국가의 군대에서 상당히 막중한 책임을 맡고 있으며 주로 전선 전체를 관리하는 장교입니다. 야전 사령관은 군대의 작전 계획을 잘 이해할 수 있어야 할 뿐 아니라 시시각각 변화하는 전쟁 중 상황에 알맞게 적용할 수 있어야 합니다. 예하 부대 지휘관을 거쳐 업무를 수행하고 작전 참모의 조언을 듣기도 하지만, 전쟁의 승패는 그의 결정에 달려 있다고 해도 과언이 아닙니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>야전 사령관은 국가의 군대에서 상당히 막중한 책임을 맡고 있으며 주로 전선 전체를 관리하는 장교입니다. 야전 사령관은 군대의 작전 계획을 잘 이해할 수 있어야 할 뿐 아니라 시시각각 변화하는 전쟁 중 상황에 알맞게 적용할 수 있어야 합니다. 예하 부대 지휘관을 거쳐 업무를 수행하고 작전 참모의 조언을 듣기도 하지만, 전쟁의 승패는 그의 결정에 달려 있다고 해도 과언이 아닙니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>작전 본부는 전투에서 쓰일 군사 작전 계획이 조직되는 장소입니다. 전선에 나가 있는 예하 부대 지휘관에게 전령을 보내거나 전보를 통해 주로 일시적으로 작전을 전달합니다. 전선이 수시로 바뀔 때마다 상급 사령부와 긴밀하게 협조해야 하기 때문입니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>야전 사령관</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>집중 공격을 제외한 모든 공격을 견딜 수 있도록 외곽 방어 시설의 방어력이 증가합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>전쟁 기계 승리</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>독일의 입장에서, 제한 시간 내에 파리 시를 점령해야 합니다. 프랑스의 입장에서, 제한 시간이 끝날 때까지 파리가 점령되지 않도록 방어해야 합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>2타일 이내에 있는 지상 유닛에 [ICON_Strength] 전투력 +3.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>위대한 장군으로부터 [ICON_Strength] 전투력 보너스 +3.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>모든 도시에 체력 +100.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>포병 유닛에 [ICON_Strength] 전투력 +6.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>군대 구성 및  훈련이 가능합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>[ICON_Capital] 수도에 [ICON_GreatGeneral] 위대한 장군 2명을 무료로 제공합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>모든 유닛에 [ICON_Strength] 전투력 +5.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>중세 시대의 지원 유닛입니다. 생산하려면 무기고가 필요합니다. 도로, 요새 및 활주로 시설을 지을 수 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>파리 장악</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>파리 장악</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>원수</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>군사적 지배력의 증거는 지속되는 전쟁이 아닌 결정적인 승리를 통해 확인됩니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>대장</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>명령은 전쟁 병력을 수월하고 성공적으로 지휘할 수 있는 능력입니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>대령</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>정보와 직관력 사이의 예리한 균형에 따라 성공이나 실패가 갈립니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>소령</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>용기가 있는 곳에 강인함이 있고 강인함이 있는 곳에 탄력이 있으며 탄력이 있는 곳에 승리가 있습니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>대위</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>가능하면 승리도 좋지만 무엇보다도 명예가 중요합니다.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>항공기</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>요새화</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>중포</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>병참 지원</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>사령부</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>산업 전쟁</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>1914년 8월 {1_Day}일</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>1914년 9월 {1_Day}일</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>산업 전쟁 +{1_Amount}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="ko_KR">
      <Text>중포 +{1_Amount}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Forteca|Fortecy|Fortecy|Fortecę|Fortecą|Fortecy|forteca|fortecy|fortecy|fortecę|fortecą|fortecy</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Sztab|Sztabu|Sztabowi|Sztab|Sztabem|Sztabie|sztab|sztabu|sztabowi|sztab|sztabem|sztabie</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Lille</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Reims</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Nancy</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Belfort</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Orlean|Orleanu|Orleanowi|Orlean|Orleanem|Orleanie</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Chartres</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Kolonia|Kolonii|Kolonii|Kolonię|Kolonią|Kolonii</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Koblencja|Koblencji|Koblencji|Koblencję|Koblencją|Koblencji</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Mannheim</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Strasburg|Strasburga|Strasburgowi|Strasburg|Strasburgiem|Strasburgu</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Colmar|Colmara|Colmarowi|Colmar|Colmarem|Colmarze</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Antwerpia|Antwerpii|Antwerpii|Antwerpię|Antwerpią|Antwerpii</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Liège</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Namur|Namuru|Namurowi|Namur|Namurem|Namurze</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Mons</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Luksemburg|Luksemburga|Luksemburgowi|Luksemburg|Luksemburgiem|Luksemburgu</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Niemcy stworzyli wyspecjalizowane działa oblężnicze do przełamania umocnień fortyfikacji otaczających Belgię. Okazały się one bardzo skuteczne i sprawiły, że forty padły szybciej, niż zakładali niemieccy stratedzy. Francuzi również stworzyli wyrafinowane i potężne działa artyleryjskie o kalibrze 75 mm, które były trwałe i wszechstronne. Jednak francuskie i niemieckie działa nie wystarczyły, by przełamać impas, do jakiego doszło po okopaniu się obu armii – doprowadziło do tego dopiero zastosowanie małych jednostek taktycznych oraz nowych technologii w postaci samolotów i czołgów.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Logistyka to proces dostarczania zasobów dla armii w celu uzupełnienia strat i zaspokojenia zapotrzebowania. Choć nie jest to najbardziej widowiskowa część działań wojennych, od sprawnej logistyki zależą losy wojny. Amatorzy studiują taktykę, eksperci logistykę. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Po epoce napoleońskiej oficerowie wojskowi zaczęli włączać do swojej pracy zarówno planowanie strategiczne, jak i operacyjne. Profesjonalna kadra dowódcza to część wojska odpowiedzialna za przekładanie celów politycznych wojny na cele militarne. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Podczas wojny totalnej wszystkie zasoby państwa wykorzystywane są do realizacji celów wojennych. W społeczeństwie industrialnym oznacza to całkowitą przebudowę infrastruktury przemysłowej, by uruchomić produkcję zbrojeniową, szkolenie wojskowe ogromnych rzesz ludności objętych poborem wojskowym oraz polityczne sterowanie gospodarką. Zmiany te mogą być tak głębokie, że ich skutki będą odczuwane długo po zakończeniu konfliktu, który je wymusił.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wynalezienie karabinu maszynowego i nowych wybuchowych pocisków artyleryjskich sprawiło, że w latach poprzedzających I wojnę światową zmianom uległa również konstrukcja fortyfikacji. Rozległe systemy okopów na froncie zachodnim mogą być postrzegane jako fizyczny wyraz przewagi obrony nad atakiem, jaka zdominowała większość działań wojennych. Podobnie nowoczesne taktyki dla piechoty i wojsk pancernych opracowywane po 1916 r. mogą być postrzegane jako próba przezwyciężenia tej tendencji.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Na początku I wojny światowej lotnictwo znajdowało się jeszcze w powijakach, a samoloty były drogimi i zawodnymi maszynami wykorzystywanymi do przeprowadzania zwiadu. Gdy wojna dobiegała końca, lotnictwo przeszło przyśpieszoną ewolucję, a samoloty stanowiły istotny element każdej liczącej się armii na planecie – wykorzystywano je do ataków taktycznych i strategicznych nalotów bombowych. Badania i rozwój lotnictwa były tak drogie, że wiele z nich finansowano z budżetów państw lub realizowano na zasadzie partnerstwa publiczno-prywatnego.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Po katastrofalnej bitwie pod Sedanem podczas wojny francusko-pruskiej w 1870 r. francuscy stratedzy musieli otrząsnąć się ze skutków klęski i jej upokarzających politycznych konsekwencji, aby przebudować swoją armię w jedną z czołowych sił wojskowych Europy. W przeciwieństwie do niemieckiego zamiłowania do szczegółowych planów operacyjnych walki francuscy oficerowie wojskowi zaczęli stosować doktrynę elastycznych ofensyw.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dzięki ciągłym atakom na linie wroga francuska armia miała zachować swój impet oraz bezwzględnie wykorzystywać każdą zauważoną słabość. Wytrąceni z równowagi Niemcy nie mieliby szansy na przejęcie inicjatywy, a napór ich wojsk byłby kontrolowany błyskawicznymi kontratakami. Metodę tę stosowano zarówno na poziomie batalionu, jak i całego teatru działań wojennych – Francuzi atakowali wszędzie tam, gdzie najeźdźca był najsłabszy.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Jeden z wielkich paradoksów sierpnia 1914 r. polegał na tym, że nawet gdy Francuzom nie wiodło się na froncie wzdłuż granicy z Belgią i Luksemburgiem, nadal prowadzili ofensywę w Alzacji i Lotaryngii, którą ostatecznie musieli jednak ograniczyć, aby zapewnić posiłki obronie Paryża. Z końcem roku zapał do „nieustannych ataków” uleciał i zachodni front zdominowały okopy.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Sukcesy pruskiej armii podczas wojny francusko-pruskiej w 1870 r. dowiodły skuteczności metodycznego, kompleksowego planowania funkcjonowania wojska, które w swojej drobiazgowości sięgało aż do rozkładów kolejowych i harmonogramów przemarszów. Uznając przyszłą wojnę z Francją za prawdopodobnie nieuniknioną, hrabia von Schlieffen, szef Niemieckiego Sztabu Generalnego, opracował plany przyszłej inwazji na ten kraj, które zakładały przemarsz przez Belgię i Luksemburg, a następnie atak od północy na Paryż. Powodzenie tej strategii wymagało skoncentrowania sił na zachodniej flance, ale plan nigdy nie został zrealizowany w pełni.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Prowadząc wojnę na dwóch frontach, dowództwo niemieckie przeniosło część sił przeznaczonych na ciężkie skrzydło zachodnie na zupełnie inny front (w tym wypadku przeciwko Rosjanom). Gdy armia niemiecka z powodzeniem przebiła się przez Belgię i Luksemburg, zmusiła francuskie siły do mobilizacji, a ich klin stał się w oczach Niemieckiego Sztabu Generalnego kuszącym celem. Jednak różne czynniki, w tym redukcja sił zaangażowanych w realizację planu Schlieffena, improwizowane ruchy niemieckich wojsk będące odpowiedzią na francuskie ataki oraz silny opór Francuzów i Brytyjczyków sprawiły, że nokautujący cios nigdy nie trafił w cel.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Niemcy zaryzykowali i przegrali, a wojna zmieniła się w cztery lata piekła w okopach wzdłuż linii, na której plan Schlieffena dokonał żywota.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Brytyjski Korpus Ekspedycyjny to niewielka część brytyjskiej armii, którą wydzielono i wysłano do walki, by zacieśnić sojusz z Francuzami. Stacjonujący w zachodniej części francuskiego frontu oddział postrzegano początkowo bardziej jako polityczną kurtuazję niż liczącą się siłę wojskową. Jednak gdy Niemcy przemierzali Niderlandy i zbliżali się do Paryża, Korpus Ekspedycyjny stawił czoła przeważającemu liczebnie przeciwnikowi w bitwie pod Mons i mimo że poniósł poważne straty oraz został zmuszony do wycofania się, uratował przed zagładą 5 Armię Francuską. Bitwa pod Mons to jedno z największych militarnych osiągnięć Wielkiej Brytanii, dzięki któremu Brytyjski Korpus Ekspedycyjny przeszedł do historii.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Chociaż niepodległa Belgia powstała pod koniec epoki napoleońskiej jako element mechanizmu zapewniającego równowagę między europejskimi potęgami, to bardzo długo pozostawała bliskim sojusznikiem Wielkiej Brytanii. Inwazja na Francję wymagała przemarszu niemieckiej armii przez terytorium Belgii. Wczesne plany zakładały nawet, że belgijska armia będzie pełniła wartę honorową wzdłuż szlaków, którymi poruszać się miały niemieckie oddziały – jak się później okazało, było to wyjątkowo błędne założenie. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Miasto Liège, otoczone szeregiem fortyfikacji, było pierwszą znaczącą przeszkodą, na jaką natknęła się niemiecka armia w 1914 r. Choć w wielu przypadkach obsady fortów walczyły dzielnie, nie miały szans w starciu z działami oblężniczymi skonstruowanymi specjalnie z myślą o skruszeniu murów belgijskich twierdz. Przełamanie umocnień Liège oraz okrucieństwo, z jakim najeźdźcza armia traktowała obywateli Belgii, sprawiły, że opinia publiczna – zwłaszcza brytyjska – zwróciła się przeciwko Niemcom.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Niewielkie księstwo Luksemburga leży między Francją a Niemcami. Znajduje się tam ważny węzeł kolejowy łączący te kraje. Przejęcie luksemburskiej infrastruktury kolejowej było kluczowym elementem niemieckiego planu ataku na Francję, więc inwazja na Luksemburg była jednym z pierwszych działań wojennych w 1914 r. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Francja przygotowywała się do starcia z Niemcami od czasu katastrofalnej wojny francusko-pruskiej w 1870 r., podczas której pruska armia zmiażdżyła francuskie siły, pojmała cesarza i wymusiła podpisanie upokarzającego traktatu pokojowego powodującego utratę Alzacji i Lotaryngii leżących na wschodzie kraju. Całe pokolenie francuskich polityków i oficerów dorastało w cieniu tej porażki i było zdeterminowane, by uzyskać rehabilitację lub po prostu zemścić się za tę przegraną. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Głównymi sojusznikami wojskowymi Francji były Rosja oraz Wielka Brytania i to rosyjska deklaracja wojny przeciwko cesarstwu austro-węgierskiemu spowodowała włączenie się jej do tego konfliktu w ramach wsparcia sprzymierzeńców. Francja skoncentrowała się jednak przede wszystkim na walce z Niemcami, a nie z Austro-Węgrami. Tuż po wybuchu wojny główne siły francuskiej armii zaatakowały Alzację i Lotaryngię w celu szybkiego odzyskania utraconego niegdyś terytorium, pozostawiając na północnej granicy z Belgią i Luksemburgiem niewielkie oddziały obronne. Francuscy stratedzy znacznie pomylili się w swoich szacunkach dotyczących liczebności niemieckich sił atakujących na tym odcinku (zakładano, że Niemcy przekroczą Ardeny), co zmusiło ich armie do nagłej zmiany planów tuż po wybuchu wojny.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Niewiele ponad czterdzieści lat przed wybuchem I wojny światowej pruska armia zadała Francji największą militarną klęskę od czasów napoleońskich. Zwycięstwo to przyczyniło się do powstania nowoczesnego niemieckiego państwa. Niemieccy politycy dobrze wiedzieli, że upokarzające warunki pokoju narzuconego Francji staną się zarzewiem kolejnego konfliktu, i zaczęli się do niego przygotowywać. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zawiązanie ententy, czyli wojskowego sojuszu Francji, Wielkiej Brytanii i Rosji, sprawiło, że Niemcy otoczone od wschodu i zachodu wrogimi siłami znalazły się w niepewnej sytuacji. Wielka strategia opracowana przed I wojną światową zakładała zadanie jednego potężnego ciosu Francji na zachodzie, zanim Rosja na wschodzie zdołałaby wykorzystać swoją ogromną przewagę liczebną. Stało się to głównym celem politycznym planu Schlieffena.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Tuż przed wybuchem I wojny światowej niewiele armii mogło dorównać armii niemieckiej pod względem wyszkolenia i przygotowania. Nie wystarczyło to jednak, by zrealizować plany niemieckich strategów zakładające odniesienie szybkiego zwycięstwa.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Przystąpienie Wielkiej Brytanii do ententy (wojskowego sojuszu Francji, Wielkiej Brytanii i Rosji) nie było w żadnym razie z góry przesądzone. Długoletnia rywalizacja wojskowa między Francją i Wielką Brytanią sięgająca czasów Napoleona oraz więzi łączące królewskie rody Wielkiej Brytanii i Niemiec sprawiały, że bardziej prawdopodobny był jej udział w porozumieniu mocarstw centralnych. Ostatecznie jednak zaostrzająca się konkurencja ze strony Niemiec i potrzeba ograniczenia ich rosnącej potęgi skłoniły Wielką Brytanię do dołączenia do ententy. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>W przededniu I wojny światowej nie było gwarancji, że Wielka Brytania wyśle swoje siły zbrojne do Europy kontynentalnej. Do umieszczenia niewielkiego oddziału na terytorium Francji w dużej mierze przyczyniły się nieustanne naciski niewielkiej grupy oficerów francuskiej i brytyjskiej armii. Gdy Wielka Brytania wypowiedziała wojnę Niemcom, zaskoczony Kaiser nazwał ten ruch „niemądrą pomyłką” spowodowaną „skrawkiem papieru”.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Chociaż niepodległa Belgia powstała pod koniec epoki napoleońskiej jako element mechanizmu zapewniającego równowagę między europejskimi potęgami, to bardzo długo pozostawała bliskim sojusznikiem Wielkiej Brytanii. Inwazja na Francję wymagała przemarszu niemieckiej armii przez terytorium Belgii. Wczesne plany zakładały nawet, że belgijska armia będzie pełniła wartę honorową wzdłuż szlaków, którymi poruszać się miały niemieckie oddziały – jak się później okazało, było to wyjątkowo błędne założenie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Miasto Liège, otoczone szeregiem fortyfikacji, było pierwszą znaczącą przeszkodą, na jaką natknęła się niemiecka armia w 1914 r. Choć w wielu przypadkach obsady fortów walczyły dzielnie, nie miały szans w starciu z działami oblężniczymi skonstruowanymi specjalnie z myślą o skruszeniu murów belgijskich twierdz. Przełamanie umocnień Liège oraz okrucieństwo, z jakim najeźdźcza armia traktowała obywateli Belgii, sprawiły, że opinia publiczna – zwłaszcza brytyjska – zwróciła się przeciwko Niemcom.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dowódca polowy to oficer odpowiedzialny za ogromną część armii swojego narodu, zazwyczaj nadzorujący cały front. Musi rozumieć plan operacyjny armii i być gotowym do wprowadzania w nim zmian wymuszanych przebiegiem działań wojennych. Choć pracuje za pośrednictwem podległych mu dowódców i doradza mu sztab generalny, sukces i porażka armii zależą wyłącznie od jego osądu. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dowódca polowy to oficer odpowiedzialny za ogromną część armii swojego narodu, zazwyczaj nadzorujący cały front. Musi rozumieć plan operacyjny armii i być gotowym do wprowadzania w nim zmian wymuszanych przebiegiem działań wojennych. Choć pracuje za pośrednictwem podległych mu dowódców i doradza mu sztab generalny, sukces i porażka armii zależą wyłącznie od jego osądu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dowódca polowy to oficer odpowiedzialny za ogromną część armii swojego narodu, zazwyczaj nadzorujący cały front. Musi rozumieć plan operacyjny armii i być gotowym do wprowadzania w nim zmian wymuszanych przebiegiem działań wojennych. Choć pracuje za pośrednictwem podległych mu dowódców i doradza mu sztab generalny, sukces i porażka armii zależą wyłącznie od jego osądu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dowódca polowy to oficer odpowiedzialny za ogromną część armii swojego narodu, zazwyczaj nadzorujący cały front. Musi rozumieć plan operacyjny armii i być gotowym do wprowadzania w nim zmian wymuszanych przebiegiem działań wojennych. Choć pracuje za pośrednictwem podległych mu dowódców i doradza mu sztab generalny, sukces i porażka armii zależą wyłącznie od jego osądu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dowódca polowy to oficer odpowiedzialny za ogromną część armii swojego narodu, zazwyczaj nadzorujący cały front. Musi rozumieć plan operacyjny armii i być gotowym do wprowadzania w nim zmian wymuszanych przebiegiem działań wojennych. Choć pracuje za pośrednictwem podległych mu dowódców i doradza mu sztab generalny, sukces i porażka armii zależą wyłącznie od jego osądu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Sztab to miejsce, w którym wojskowe plany operacyjne przyjmują postać rozkazów przekazywanych armii. Konieczność wykorzystywania posłańców i telegrafu, by utrzymać stały kontakt z dowódcami działającymi na linii frontu, sprawia, że sztaby są budowlami tymczasowymi, często przenoszonymi wraz ze zmianami sytuacji na froncie.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dowódca polowy|Dowódcy polowego|Dowódcy polowemu|Dowódcę polowego|Dowódcą polowym|Dowódcy polowym|dowódca polowy|dowódcy polowego|dowódcy polowemu|dowódcę polowego|dowódcą polowym|dowódcy polowym</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zwiększa siłę twoich zewnętrznych umocnień tak, aby przełamać je mogły wyłącznie najbardziej skoncentrowane ataki.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wojenna machina – zwycięstwo</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Jako Niemcy musisz zdobyć Paryż przed upływem czasu. Grając jako Francja, musisz chronić Paryż przed przejęciem aż do upływu wyznaczonego czasu.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+3 do [ICON_Strength] siły bojowej jednostek lądowych znajdujących się w promieniu 2 pól.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+3 do [ICON_Strength] premii bojowej dzięki wielkiemu generałowi.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+100 do punktów żywotności we wszystkich miastach.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+6 do [ICON_Strength] siły bojowej wszystkich jednostek artylerii.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Umożliwia tworzenie i szkolenie armii.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zapewnia twojej [ICON_Capital] stolicy 2 darmowych [ICON_GreatGeneral] wielkich generałów.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+5 do [ICON_Strength] siły bojowej wszystkich jednostek.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Średniowieczna jednostka wsparcia. Do jej produkcji potrzebna jest zbrojownia. Możliwość tworzenia ulepszeń: linii kolejowych, fortów i lądowisk.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Kontrola nad Paryżem</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Kontrola nad Paryżem</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Marszałek polny</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dowodem wojskowego mistrzostwa nie są przedłużające się kampanie, lecz zdecydowane zwycięstwo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Generał</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dowództwo to sztuka kierowania siłami wojny w sposób skuteczny i niewymagający wysiłku.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Pułkownik</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Sukces i porażka zależą od umiejętnego balansowania na krawędzi noża między informacją a intuicją.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Major</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Odwadze towarzyszy zuchwałość, zuchwałości rozmach, a rozmachowi zwycięstwo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Kapitan</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Zwycięstwo, gdy możliwe, lecz honor ponad wszystko.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Samoloty|Samolotów|Samolotom|Samoloty|Samolotami|Samolotach|samoloty|samolotów|samolotom|samoloty|samolotami|samolotach</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Fortyfikacje|Fortyfikacji|Fortyfikacjom|Fortyfikacje|Fortyfikacjami|Fortyfikacjach|fortyfikacje|fortyfikacji|fortyfikacjom|fortyfikacje|fortyfikacjami|fortyfikacjach</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Ciężka artyleria|Ciężkiej artylerii|Ciężkiej artylerii|Ciężką artylerię|Ciężką artylerią|Ciężkiej artylerii|ciężka artyleria|ciężkiej artylerii|ciężkiej artylerii|ciężką artylerię|ciężką artylerią|ciężkiej artylerii</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Logistyka|Logistyki|Logistyce|Logistykę|Logistyką|Logistyce|logistyka|logistyki|logistyce|logistykę|logistyką|logistyce</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Dowództwo|Dowództwa|Dowództwu|Dowództwo|Dowództwem|Dowództwie|dowództwo|dowództwa|dowództwu|dowództwo|dowództwem|dowództwie</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>Wojna przemysłowa|Wojny przemysłowej|Wojnie przemysłowej|Wojnę przemysłową|Wojną przemysłową|Wojnie przemysłowej|wojna przemysłowa|wojny przemysłowej|wojnie przemysłowej|wojnę przemysłową|wojną przemysłową|wojnie przemysłowej</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>{1_Day} sierpnia 1914 r.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>{1_Day} września 1914 r.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} dzięki wojnie przemysłowej</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="pl_PL">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} ciężkiej artylerii</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Крепость|Крепости|Крепости|Крепость|Крепостью|Крепости</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Штаб|Штаба|Штабу|Штаб|Штабом|Штабе</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Лилль|Лилля|Лиллю|Лилль|Лиллем|Лилле</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Реймс|Реймса|Реймсу|Реймс|Реймсом|Реймсе</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Нанси|Нанси|Нанси|Нанси|Нанси|Нанси</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Бельфор|Бельфора|Бельфору|Бельфор|Бельфором|Бельфоре</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Орлеан|Орлеана|Орлеану|Орлеан|Орлеаном|Орлеане</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Шартр|Шартра|Шартру|Шартр|Шартром|Шартре</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Кельн|Кельна|Кельну|Кельн|Кельном|Кельне</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Кобленц|Кобленца|Кобленцу|Кобленц|Кобленцем|Кобленце</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Мангейм|Мангейма|Мангейму|Мангейм|Мангеймом|Мангейме</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Германский Страсбург|Германского Страсбурга|Германскому Страсбургу|Германский Страсбург|Германским Страсбургом|Германском Страсбурге</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Кольмар|Кольмара|Кольмару|Кольмар|Кольмаром|Кольмаре</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Антверпен|Антверпена|Антверпену|Антверпен|Антверпеном|Антверпене</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Льеж|Льежа|Льежу|Льеж|Льежем|Льеже</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Намюр|Намюра|Намюру|Намюр|Намюром|Намюре</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Монс|Монса|Монсу|Монс|Монсом|Монсе</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Люксембург|Люксембурга|Люксембургу|Люксембург|Люксембургом|Люксембурге</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Немецкие инженеры создали специальные осадные пушки для разрушения фортов, из которых состояла оборонительная система Бельгии. Эти пушки зарекомендовали себя с самой лучшей стороны: под их огнем бельгийские форты держались намного меньше, чем было предусмотрено проектом. Французы, в свою очередь, разработали мощную 75-мм пушку. Но артиллерии так и не удалось прорвать эшелонированную траншейную оборону. Для этого потребовались принципиально новые рода войск: танки и авиация.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Логистика – это система снабжения армии, обеспечивающая восполнение потерь личного состава, техники и материалов. Успех любой военной операции во многом зависит от незаметных тружеников тыла. Любители изучают тактику, профессионалы – логистику. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>После наполеоновских войн полководцы всех стран научились сочетать принципы тактического и стратегического планирования. Теперь функция командования – превращать политические цели в боевые задачи. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В условиях тотальной войны все силы и ресурсы государства подчиняются одной цели – достижению победы. В индустриальном обществе это означает перевод всей промышленности на военные рельсы, массовую военную подготовку населения, мобилизацию и подчинение экономики политическим целям. Все общество меняется, и порой эти изменения необратимы.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Изобретение пулемета и фугасных артиллерийских снарядов внесло существенные изменения в устройство оборонительных сооружений. Развитая система траншей на Западном фронте является убедительной демонстрацией превосходства оборонительной тактики над наступательной. Современная тактика боя пехотных и бронетанковых подразделений – очередная попытка преодолеть это превосходство.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В начале Первой мировой войны авиация была еще в пеленках. Аэропланы были дорогостоящими и не очень надежными машинами и использовались в основном для разведки. Уже к концу войны летательные аппараты стали грозной военной силой и широко применялись для тактических операций и стратегических бомбардировок. Авиационные разработки требовали столько средств, что финансировались государством целиком либо совместно с частными инвесторами.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>После битвы при Седане (также известной как «Седанская катастрофа») в 1870 г. французской армии пришлось пройти трудный период восстановления, чтобы в конце концов превратиться в одну из мощнейших военных сил Европы. В противовес германской традиции к подробному планированию французские полководцы развивали доктрину гибкой атаки.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Согласно этой доктрине, задача армии состояла в том, чтобы непрерывно атаковать позиции неприятеля и использовать любую его слабость. Противник не успеет перехватить инициативу, и преимущество всегда будет на стороне французов, а неуклонное продвижение германской армии будет сдержано молниеносными контрударами. Основная тактика армейских подразделений и соединений от батальона и выше была проста: искать слабые места противника и атаковать.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Одной из главных неожиданностей августа 1914 года было то, что фронт в Бельгии трещал по всем швам, а в то же время приходилось сдерживать наступление противника на Эльзас и Лотарингию и собирать подкрепления, чтобы спасти Париж. К концу года тактика «непрерывной атаки» себя исчерпала, и на Западном фронте началась позиционная война.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Успехи прусской армии во время франко-прусской войны 1870–1871 г. были обусловлены детальным планированием военных операций, вплоть до точного расписания войск на марше и движения железнодорожных составов. Предвидя неизбежность новой войны, начальник германского генштаба Альфред фон Шлиффен составил план будущего вторжения во Францию через Бельгию и Люксембург с последующим продвижением на юг, к Парижу. Этот план требовал сосредоточения всех германских сил на западных границах, но ему так и не суждено было исполниться.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Ведя войну на два фронта, германское командование перебросило часть сил на восток. Успешное продвижение немцев в Бельгии вынудило французов перейти к обороне, а выступающая часть французского фронта показалась германскому генштабу легкой добычей. По ряду причин – в том числе и из-за переброски части сил на Восточный фронт, необходимости импровизировать в ответ на вылазки французов и ожесточенного сопротивления французских и британских войск – немцам так и не удалось нанести предполагаемый быстрый нокаутирующий удар.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Германия рискнула и проиграла. План Шлиффена был сорван, а война превратилась в растянутый на четыре года кошмар.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Британские экспедиционные силы (БЭС) – часть британской армии, принимавшая участие в боевых действиях во время Первой мировой войны. Располагавшиеся на Западном фронте британские части поначалу воспринимались как некий политический реверанс, а не как реальная военная сила. Но в ходе продвижения немцев через Бельгию к Парижу БЭС нанесли германской армии значительные потери в битве при Монсе и, хоть и были вынуждены отступить (также понеся большие потери), спасли французскую армию от полного уничтожения. Битва при Монсе – предмет особой гордости британских военных, знаковое событие для БЭС.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Бельгия как самостоятельное государство возникла в 1830 г. в результате политических изменений, вызванных наполеоновскими войнами, и долгое время была верным союзником Великобритании. Германия напала на Францию через бельгийскую территорию. В первоначальном варианте плана нападения на Францию германский штаб отводил бельгийской армии роль почетного караула при прохождении германских войск через Бельгию. Как показали дальнейшие события, такой подход оказался ошибочным. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Город Льеж, защищенный мощными укреплениями, был первым значительным препятствием на пути германской армии. Но хотя форты хорошо зарекомендовали себя в войнах старого типа, они не смогли устоять перед новейшими образцами осадной артиллерии. Взятие Льежа и жестокость немецкой армии по отношению к бельгийскому населению настроило общественное мнение – особенно в Великобритании – против Германии.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Великое Герцогство Люксембург – европейское карликовое государство, расположенное между Бельгией, Францией и Германией, крупный железнодорожный узел. Захват железных дорог был важной частью германского плана в войне с Францией, поэтому оккупация Люксембурга в 1914 г. стала одним из первых событий мировой войны. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Франция начала готовиться к новой войне с Германией сразу после сокрушительного поражения во франко-прусской войне в 1871 г., когда прусская армия фактически уничтожила французские вооруженные силы, взяла в плен императора и навязала мир на унизительных условиях. По условиям мирного договора Франция потеряла Эльзас и Лотарингию. Целое поколение французских военных выросло в тени этой катастрофы и жаждало мести. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Главными союзниками Франции были Россия и Великобритания. Именно объявление Россией войны Австро-Венгрии ускорило вступление Франции в войну. Но Франция фактически вела свою собственную войну против Германии. Французская армия сразу начала наступление на Эльзас и Лотарингию, чтобы скорее отвоевать эти территории. Северная граница с Бельгией и Люксембургом осталась практически не защищенной. Французское командование недооценило силы германской армии и не предусмотрело возможности удара с этого направления (предполагалось, что немцы пойдут через Арденны). Из-за этого уже на первом этапе войны пришлось кардинально менять планы.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Менее чем за полвека до Первой мировой прусская армия нанесла французам величайшее со времен Наполеона военное поражение. В этот период сформировалась современная немецкая нация. Германские политики ясно понимали, что в побежденной Франции зреют семена реваншизма, и готовились к войне. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Образование Антанты (военного союза Франции, Великобритании и России) поставило Германию в невыгодное положение: теперь она была окружена врагами и с запада, и с востока. Основой разработанной стратегии было нанесение резкого, ошеломляющего удара по Франции, пока Россия не успела собрать свою мощную армию. Такой подход лег в основу плана Шлиффена.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В преддверии Первой мировой войны немногие армии могли сравниться с германской. И все же ни отличная подготовка, ни прекрасное обеспечение не помогли германскому командованию осуществить свои планы.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Участие Великобритании в Антанте (военном союзе Франции, Великобритании и России) было дальновидным решением. Давнее соперничество между Англией и Францией, династические связи между Англией и Германией – все это должно было привести Великобританию в союз Центральных держав. Но рост напряженности в германо-британских отношениях и стремление обуздать стремительный рост германского могущества в итоге привели Великобританию к решению об участии в Антанте. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Накануне Первой мировой войны не было уверенности, что Великобритания пошлет свои войска в континентальную Европу. Небольшие, но активные группировки в британском и французском штабах распространяли мнение о том, что Великобритания ограничится отправкой во Францию небольшого контингента. Даже кайзер был удивлен, когда Британия объявила войну Германии, и назвал это «глупой ошибкой».</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Бельгия как самостоятельное государство возникла в 1830 г. в результате политических изменений, вызванных наполеоновскими войнами, и долгое время была верным союзником Великобритании. Германия напала на Францию через бельгийскую территорию. В первоначальном варианте плана нападения на Францию германский штаб отводил бельгийской армии роль почетного караула при прохождении германских войск через Бельгию. Как показали дальнейшие события, такой подход оказался ошибочным.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Город Льеж, защищенный мощными укреплениями, был первым значительным препятствием на пути германской армии. Но хотя форты хорошо зарекомендовали себя в войнах старого типа, они не смогли устоять перед новейшими образцами осадной артиллерии. Взятие Льежа и жестокость немецкой армии по отношению к бельгийскому населению настроило общественное мнение – особенно в Великобритании – против Германии.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Командующий армией – это военачальник, в подчинении которого находится значительная часть вооруженных сил страны. Он должен быть готов разрабатывать оперативные планы для своей армии и оперативно вносить в них изменения. Ему помогают в этом офицеры штаба и другие подчиненные, но в целом успех или провал операции зависит от личных решений командующего. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Командующий армией – это военачальник, в подчинении которого находится значительная часть вооруженных сил страны. Он должен быть готов разрабатывать оперативные планы для своей армии и оперативно вносить в них изменения. Ему помогают в этом офицеры штаба и другие подчиненные, но в целом успех или провал операции зависит от личных решений командующего.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Командующий армией – это военачальник, в подчинении которого находится значительная часть вооруженных сил страны. Он должен быть готов разрабатывать оперативные планы для своей армии и оперативно вносить в них изменения. Ему помогают в этом офицеры штаба и другие подчиненные, но в целом успех или провал операции зависит от личных решений командующего.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Командующий армией – это военачальник, в подчинении которого находится значительная часть вооруженных сил страны. Он должен быть готов разрабатывать оперативные планы для своей армии и оперативно вносить в них изменения. Ему помогают в этом офицеры штаба и другие подчиненные, но в целом успех или провал операции зависит от личных решений командующего.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Командующий армией – это военачальник, в подчинении которого находится значительная часть вооруженных сил страны. Он должен быть готов разрабатывать оперативные планы для своей армии и оперативно вносить в них изменения. Ему помогают в этом офицеры штаба и другие подчиненные, но в целом успех или провал операции зависит от личных решений командующего.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Штаб – это центр управления войсками. Здесь разрабатываются планы операций, отсюда отдают приказы действующей армии. Распоряжения из штаба на передовую доставляются с помощью средств связи или через вестовых. В условиях изменяющейся боевой обстановки важно, чтобы штаб находился вблизи линии фронта и был мобильным.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Командующий армией|командующего армией|командующему армией|командующего армией|командующим армией|командующем армией</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Повышает обороноспособность внешних укреплений – теперь их можно взять только массированным штурмом.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Победа в «Военной машине»</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Играя за Германию, вы должны захватить Париж за ограниченное число ходов. Играя за Францию, вы должны удержать Париж и не допустить его захвата.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+3 к [ICON_Strength] боевой мощи наземных юнитов Информационной эры в пределах 2 клеток.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Боевой бонус +3 [ICON_Strength] от великого полководца.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+100 ОЗ во всех городах.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+6 [ICON_Strength] к боевой мощи артиллерийских юнитов.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Позволяет создавать и готовить армии.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>В [ICON_Capital] столице бесплатно появляются 2 [ICON_GreatGeneral] великих полководца.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+5 к [ICON_Strength] боевой мощи всех юнитов.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Юнит поддержки Средневековья. Для создания требуется оружейная. Строит железные дороги, форты и взлетные полосы.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Контроль над Парижем</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Контроль над Парижем</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Фельдмаршал</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Военное мастерство выражается не в затяжных кампаниях, а в решительной победе.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Генерал</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Командование – это искусство успешного и непринужденного управления военной силой.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Полковник</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Тонкую грань, отделяющую победу от поражения, легко нащупает тот, кто доверяет своей интуиции и умело пользуется информацией.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Майор</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Храбрость – основа дерзости. Дерзость – основа натиска. Натиск – основа победы.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Капитан</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Победа важна, но честь превыше всего.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Самолеты|самолетов|самолетам|самолеты|самолетами|самолетах</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Укрепления|укреплений|укреплениям|укрепления|укреплениями|укреплениях</Text>
      <Gender>neuter</Gender>
      <Plurality>2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Тяжелая артиллерия|тяжелой артиллерии|тяжелой артиллерии|тяжелую артиллерию|тяжелой артиллерией|тяжелой артиллерии</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Логистика|логистики|логистике|логистику|логистикой|логистике</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Командование|командования|командованию|командование|командованием|командовании</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Промышленная война|промышленной войны|промышленной войне|промышленную войну|промышленной войной|промышленной войне</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>{1_Day} августа 1914 г.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>{1_Day} сентября 1914 г.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>Промышленная война: +{1_Amount}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="ru_RU">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} к тяжелой артиллерии</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>要塞</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>司令部</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>里尔</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>兰斯</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>南锡</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>贝尔福</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>奥尔良</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>沙尔特</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>科隆</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>科布伦茨</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>曼海姆</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>斯特拉斯堡（德）</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>科尔马</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>安特卫普</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>列日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>那慕尔</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>蒙斯</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>卢森堡</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>德军发展出了专用于破坏比利时堡垒防御的攻城枪炮。这些武器极其成功，堡垒陷落的速度远远快于计划所想。法国人也研发出了一种复杂且强大的75毫米火炮，以耐用与灵活著称。但是无论是哪一方都无法打破横在他们自己面前的那一道道战壕。而新科技加身的飞机坦克和小规模作战体系最终还是达成了这项目标。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>后勤是向军队补给物资，弥补其损失与开销的过程。虽然不如作战那样荣耀，但在战争取得胜利却离不开后勤部门的细致操作。兵家之道有言：菜鸟才谈论战术，高手皆通晓后勤。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>在拿破仑时代之后，职业军官便开始将战略与行动纳入工作之中。在军队里，职业指挥官需要负责将战争的政治目标转换到军事对象之中。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>发生全面战争时，参战国家会将所有资源全部投入战争。在工业国家，这意味着政府会将所有工业设施重新打造为兵工厂，同时大规模征兵训练武装人员，并公开利用政治工具指导经济发展。其将改变整个社会的所有层面，在冲突结束后的很长一段时间中仍会持续影响。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>机枪和新式高爆炮弹的出现意味着防御工事在一战之前的几年里也发生了相应变化。遍布在西线的壕沟系统可以被视为战争中防御至上理念碾压主动进攻的有形表现。同样地，1916年起开始发展的现代步兵与坦克战术体系可以视为突破这种防御至上理念的努力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>第一次世界大战开始时，航空科技还处于襁褓之中，用于侦查的飞机造价十分昂贵且极不可靠。但到战争结束时，飞机已成世界上所有强大军事国家的主要武器，被用于战术攻击与战略轰炸，其在战火的洗礼下发生了急速变革。用于研究与发展航空科技的费用十分高昂，主要是由国家或公私合伙人提供赞助。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>在1870年的普法战争中，法军惨败于色当战役。在这之后，法国军事规划者必须设法从灾难性的损失和屈辱的政治结果中恢复过来，以便将军队重振为欧洲顶级军队之一。与德国人热衷于制定详细的作战计划形成鲜明对比，法国军官开始倾向于使用灵活的攻击手段。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>法军通过不断攻击敌人的防线，并抓住随之而来的破绽来无情地撕开防线，从而保持自身优势。敌军因此无法进行喘息、保持平衡，法军将采取先发制人的手段，德军再猛烈的进攻都将被闪电般的反击所遏制。无论是小规模的营级战斗还是战区的大规模进攻都很适用这一招。侵略者哪里有弱点，法军就会攻击哪里。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>1914年8月的一个大悖论是，虽然法国人在低地国家的前线步履蹒跚，他们还是在阿尔萨斯和洛林取得了进展。但这些行动都必须停止，以提供增援解放巴黎。到了1914年底，“无限进攻”的计划失败了，而西线成为了战壕的天下。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>1870年普法战争期间，普鲁士军队取得的成功证明了一支利用铁路行军、有条不紊、计划周全的军队将所向无敌。德国总参谋长冯·施利芬伯爵认为，在未来与法国必有一战，于是他制定了未来入侵法国的计划，军队将穿越低地国家，然后南下夺取巴黎。而这个计划需要在远西战线集结兵力才能取得成功。可惜这个计划从未被彻底执行。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>在两线作战的情况下，德军最高司令部将一些原本用于西线侧翼激战的部队转移到了一个完全不同的战场（以对付俄军）。当德军一路冲破低地国家时，他们成功地迫使法军向后撤退，而法军战线上的突出部分便成为了德军参谋长眼中的诱人目标。但由于各种因素，包括施利芬计划中军力的减弱、德军应对法国的临时行动，以及英法两国顽强的抵抗，导致这记重拳没有达到预期效果。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>然而德军最终还是赌输了这场博弈。噩梦般的战争持续了四年，以施利芬计划破灭而告终。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>英国远征军是英国投入至战场的一支小规模军队，目的是为了使英国更紧密地与法国在协约国中合作。一开始他们被部署在西线战场，更多是作为礼节性的支持而非实质性的军事力量。然而，当德国人沿着低地国家直捣巴黎时，英国远征军便在蒙斯战役中与拥有数量占优的德军发生了激烈战斗。尽管他们遭到重创并最终被迫撤退，但还是使法国第五军团免遭歼灭。蒙斯战役是英军取得的最著名、最受尊敬的军事成就之一，让英国远征军声名远扬。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>比利时是拿破仑时代末期作为欧洲力量平衡计划的一部分而建立的，但长期以来其一直都是英国的特殊盟友。德军想要入侵法国便需要首先侵入并通过比利时。事实上，该计划的早期版本曾经假设比利时军队会派遣仪仗队在路边夹道欢迎德军的到来——到头来这是一个彻头彻尾的错误幻想。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>列日市外围满布堡垒，也是1914年行经至此的德军所遇到的第一个重大军事阻碍。尽管这些堡垒在许多情况下都能提供良好的防御，但面对专为对付堡垒而设计的特殊枪炮时便显得无能为力。列日防御工事的崩塌和德军对比利时人民的残酷镇压点燃了各地区（尤其是英国）反对德国的舆论风潮。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>小小的卢森堡公国位于法国与德国之间，更是各国重要的铁路交通枢纽。占领这些铁路枢纽对德军入侵法国的计划至关重要。因此，1914年入侵卢森堡便是德国早期战争行动之一。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>自从在1870年的普法战争中惨败后，法国一直在积极备战，准备与德国再次一决雌雄。普鲁士军队在战争中摧毁了法国陆军，俘虏了法兰西皇帝，并在之后的和谈中迫使法国做出屈辱的让步，包括将法国东部阿尔萨斯和洛林割让予普鲁士。从战争失败的阴影中成长出了一代法国政客与军官，他们决心不仅要为这次失败复仇，还要洗刷国家的耻辱。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>法国的主要军事同盟是俄国与英国，正是俄国对奥匈帝国的宣战，才促使法国以盟友身份参战。而法国更主要的是对抗老对手德国，而非奥匈帝国。因此，法国在战争爆发后的首要目标便是对阿尔萨斯与洛林发动攻击，以便迅速夺回领土。然而这也使得其与比利时、卢森堡交界的北方边境的防守孱弱。法军的战斗计划严重低估了计划沿轴线进攻的德军数量（他们预计德国人会直接穿越阿登地区），因此在战争初期便被迫唐突地改变作战计划。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>在一战爆发前的上一代人心中，普鲁士军队为法国带来了自拿破仑时代结束以来最为重大的军事失败，而这也逐渐形成了现代德国的雏形。德国的政客们头脑清晰，十分了解与法国的和谈条约会为下一次冲突埋下祸根，然后便是为下场战争做好万全准备。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>法国、英国与俄国之间签署的三国协约将德国放置在了一个危险的军事境地，其自西向东皆被敌对军事势力所包围。德军在一战中的大战略是趁俄国还未将主要军事力量从东方部署到西方前就先行对法国进行大规模打击。这也成为了施里芬计划的主要政治目标。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>在一战爆发前夕，世界上鲜有如德军这般训练有素、备战得当的军事力量。然而，积极备战和训练有素还不足以实现策划者所构想的迅速终结战争的策略。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>英国加入协约国（法国、英国与俄国之间的军事联盟）实属意外。法国与英国之间的长期军事竞赛可以追溯到拿破仑时代，况且英国王室与德国王室之间拥有血缘关系，这些因素使得英国加入同盟国看似是十分合理的结果。但英国与德国之间的竞争迅速加剧，各方都在寻求方案制约崛起的德国，因此其最终选择加入协约国。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>第一次世界大战前夕，没有谁能保证英国一定会向欧洲大陆派遣军队。然而在英法两军中一直有一小撮军官不断向上级施加压力，最终迫使英国派遣少量军队前往法国。事实上，德皇曾因为英国向德国宣战而备受震惊，宣称英国当局在“一团废纸”中犯下了一个“愚蠢的错误”。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>比利时是拿破仑时代末期作为欧洲力量平衡计划的一部分而建立的，但长期以来其一直都是英国的特殊盟友。德军想要入侵法国便需要首先侵入并通过比利时。事实上，该计划的早期版本曾经假设比利时军队会派遣仪仗队在路边夹道欢迎德军的到来——到头来这是一个彻头彻尾的错误幻想。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>列日市外围满布堡垒，也是1914年行经至此的德军所遇到的第一个重大军事阻碍。尽管这些堡垒在许多情况下都能提供良好的防御，但面对专为对付堡垒而设计的特殊枪炮时便显得无能为力。列日防御工事的崩塌和德军对比利时人民的残酷镇压点燃了各地区（尤其是英国）反对德国的舆论风潮。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>战地指挥官是一类肩负国家军队命运的军官，通常需要指挥整条战线。战地指挥官必须充分了解军队的作战计划，同时敢于在瞬息万变的战场上做出应对措施。虽然他的指令需要由下级指挥官进行实施，并需要得到参谋长的指示，但军队的成败仍需仰赖他的判断。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>战地指挥官是一类肩负国家军队命运的军官，通常需要指挥整条战线。战地指挥官必须充分了解军队的作战计划，同时敢于在瞬息万变的战场上做出应对措施。虽然他的指令需要由下级指挥官进行实施，并需要得到参谋长的指示，但军队的功败仍需仰赖他的判断。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>战地指挥官是一类肩负国家军队命运的军官，通常需要指挥整条战线。战地指挥官必须充分了解军队的作战计划，同时敢于在瞬息万变的战场上做出应对措施。虽然他的指令需要由下级指挥官进行实施，并需要得到参谋长的指示，但军队的功败仍需仰赖他的判断。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>战地指挥官是一类肩负国家军队命运的军官，通常需要指挥整条战线。战地指挥官必须充分了解军队的作战计划，同时敢于在瞬息万变的战场上做出应对措施。虽然他的指令需要由下级指挥官进行实施，并需要得到参谋长的指示，但军队的功败仍需仰赖他的判断。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>战地指挥官是一类肩负国家军队命运的军官，通常需要指挥整条战线。战地指挥官必须充分了解军队的作战计划，同时敢于在瞬息万变的战场上做出应对措施。虽然他的指令需要由下级指挥官进行实施，并需要得到参谋长的指示，但军队的功败仍需仰赖他的判断。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>司令部是军方制定军事行动与计划的场所。司令部通常使用通讯员及电报与前线的下级指挥官保持联络。但此类举措一般都是临时性措施，因为战线上的情况瞬息万变，大多时候都需要高级指挥官亲临前线。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>战地指挥官</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>提高外部防御力以抵御所有进攻，高集中攻击除外。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>战争机器胜利</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>作为德军，您必须在时限内占领巴黎。作为法军，您必须在时限内保卫巴黎，阻止德军的占领。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>2个单元格内所有陆地单位+3 [ICON_Strength] 战斗力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>大将军提供+3 [ICON_Strength] 战斗力加成。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>所有城市+100生命值。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>所有火炮单位+6 [ICON_Strength] 战斗力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>可以编队并训练军队。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>[ICON_Capital] 首都免费获得2名 [ICON_GreatGeneral] 大将军。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>所有单位+5 [ICON_Strength] 战斗力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>中世纪支援单位。要求在军械库进行生产。能建造铁路、堡垒、飞机跑道改良设施。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>占领巴黎</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>占领巴黎</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>元帅</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>高超的军事技巧并非体现在旷日持久的战争中，而是决定性的胜利中。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>将军</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>成功有效地运用战争之力的艺术即是指挥。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>上校</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>胜或败，不亦于信息与直觉的刀尖上舔血。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>少校</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>哪里有勇气，哪里就有无畏；哪里有胆识，哪里就有冲劲；哪里有冲劲，哪里就有胜利。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>上尉</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>胜利甜如蜜，荣耀价更高。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>飞机</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>防御工事</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>重型火炮</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>后勤</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>指挥所</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>工业战争</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>1914年8月{1_Day}日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>1914年9月{1_Day}日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>+{1_Amount}工业战争</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
      <Text>重型火炮+{1_Amount}</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Fortaleza|Fortalezas</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Cuartel general|Cuarteles generales</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Lille</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Reims</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Nancy</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Belfort</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Orleans</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Chartres</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Colonia</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Coblenza</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Mannheim</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Estrasburgo</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Colmar</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Amberes</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Lieja</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Namur</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Mons</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Luxemburgo</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los alemanes desarrollaron cañones de asedio especiales para atravesar las defensas del anillo de fuertes que rodeaba Bélgica. Estos cañones resultaron ser muy útiles, pues provocaron que las estructuras cayesen incluso antes de lo pensado. Los franceses desarrollaron un cañón de artillería de 75 mm, muy sofisticado y potente, que demostró ser duradero y flexible. Sin embargo, nada de eso sirvió para inutilizar las trincheras; eso solo sería posible en el futuro con carros de combate, aeronaves y pelotones de pocas unidades.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La logística es el proceso de abastecer a un ejército para sustituir las pérdidas y los gastos. Aunque no es elegante, el éxito de las conflictos armados depende en gran medida de este proceso. Los aficionados estudian estrategia; los expertos, logística. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Tras el periodo napoleónico, los oficiales militares profesionales empezaron a incorporar planes estratégicos y operativos en su trabajo. El mando es la parte del ejército responsable de transformar los objetivos políticos de la guerra en objetivos militares. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>En una guerra total, todos los recursos del estado se ponen a disposición de la guerra. En una sociedad industrial, toda la infraestructura industrial pasaría a crear armamento, entrenar a la población en el uso de las armas para realizar levas masivas y dirigir la economía mediante herramientas políticas. Los cambios sociales podrían ser tan profundos que transformarían la sociedad hasta bastante después del fin del conflicto.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La invención de la ametralladora y de los proyectiles explosivos de artillería hizo necesaria la adaptación de las fortificaciones durante los años previos a la Primera Guerra Mundial. El gran sistema de trincheras del frente occidental se puede entender como una expresión física de la superioridad de la estrategia defensiva frente a la ofensiva. Del mismo modo, las tácticas modernas de infantería y los carros de combate desarrollados a partir de 1916 se pueden entender como un intento de acabar con la superioridad de esas estrategias defensivas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Al principio de la Primera Guerra Mundial, la aviación aún estaba en pañales y las aeronaves eran máquinas caras y poco fiables que se usaban en tareas de reconocimiento. Para el final de la guerra ya eran una unidad esencial de cualquier ejército importante del planeta y se usaban para realizar ataques o bombardeos estratégicos. La guerra hizo que estos vehículos evolucionasen con mucha rapidez, pero la investigación y el desarrollo eran tan caros que la mayoría se llevó a cabo con el respaldo del estado o de colaboraciones público-privadas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Después de la desastrosa batalla de Sedán durante la guerra franco-prusiana de 1870, los estrategas del ejército francés se vieron obligados a recuperarse de la catastrófica derrota y de la humillante situación política para reconstruir el ejército y convertirlo en uno de los mejores de Europa. Al contrario que los alemanes, que preferían planes de batalla detallados, el ejército francés optó por emplear estrategias ofensivas más flexibles.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El ejército mantendría su impulso atacando constantemente las líneas enemigas y aprovechándose sin piedad de los consiguientes momentos de flaqueza. El enemigo no podría recobrar el aliento, la iniciativa quedaría en manos de los franceses y los pírricos avances de los enemigos alemanes se sofocarían con rápidos contrataques. Esto iría desde batallas pequeñas hasta batallas de grandes dimensiones; Francia se aprovecharía de todos los puntos débiles mostrados por el invasor.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Una de las grandes paradojas de agosto de 1914 es que, mientras los franceses se tambaleaban por el frente de los Países Bajos, la situación en Alsacia y Lorena no hacía sino mejorar, aunque era necesario seguir muy de cerca esos avances para poder enviar refuerzos y salvar París. Para fin de año, la filosofía del "ataque constante" había desaparecido y el frente occidental estaba lleno de trincheras.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los éxitos del ejército prusiano durante la guerra franco-prusiana de 1870 demostraron la importancia de organizar el ejército de una manera metódica y detallada, desde los horarios de las tropas en movimiento hasta los de los vagones en las vías. Al ver que una guerra contra Francia era prácticamente inevitable, el conde von Schlieffe, jefe del Estado Mayor alemán, trazó planes para la futura invasión de Francia: descenderían por los Países Bajos hasta llegar a París. Para que el plan saliese bien, se necesitaría una gran concentración de fuerzas en el flanco extremo occidental del ejército alemán, pero en realidad esto nunca se llevó a cabo en su totalidad.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Con dos frentes en guerra, el alto mando alemán envió a algunas fuerzas del flanco occidental pesado a un frente de batalla totalmente diferente (en este caso, contra los rusos). El ejército alemán que atravesaba los Países Bajos sorprendió al francés; además, un grupo residual de las líneas francesas hizo que el Estado Mayor alemán se viese muy tentado de atacarlo. Sin embargo, el golpe decisivo nunca se llegó a asestar debido a varios factores, como la reducción de las fuerzas del plan Schlieffen, los movimientos improvisados de tropas alemanas como respuesta al ataque francés, o la firme resistencia francesa y británica.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los alemanes habían apostado y perdido, y la guerra dio paso a unos cuatro años devastadores en las zonas en las que el plan Schlieffen había fracasado.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La Fuerza Expedicionaria Británica era un pequeño ejército que se adentraba en el campo de batalla para cumplir con el pacto firmado con los franceses. Se situaban en el extremo occidental de las líneas francesas, y al principio se consideraban más una cortesía política que una fuerza militar importante. Sin embargo, cuando los alemanes descendieron por los Países Bajos y se acercaron a París, la Fuerza Expedicionaria plantó cara a un ejército alemán numéricamente superior en la batalla de Mons. No consiguieron repeler las acometidas y se vieron obligados a retirarse, pero sí evitaron la aniquilación del Quinto Ejército francés. La batalla de Mons es uno de los logros militares más celebrados y respetados por los británicos, y no habría sido posible sin la Fuerza Expedicionaria Británica.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La nación de Bélgica se creó al final del periodo napoleónico para equilibrar a las potencias europeas, pero siempre fue una gran aliada de Gran Bretaña. Para invadir Francia, el ejército alemán tenía que atravesar Bélgica. De hecho, las primeras versiones del plan daban por sentado que el ejército belga ofrecería una guardia de honor al ejército alemán, algo que, al final, resultó no ser así. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La ciudad de Lieja estaba rodeada por una serie de fuertes y fue el gran primer obstáculo militar para el ejército alemán en 1914. Esos fuertes, aunque habían demostrado ser útiles en muchas ocasiones, no pudieron resistir los cañones de asedio construidos específicamente para derribarlos. La caída de las fortificaciones de Lieja y la crueldad del ejército alemán contra la población belga hizo que la opinión popular se volviese en contra de los alemanes, sobre todo en Gran Bretaña.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El diminuto principado de Luxemburgo se encuentra entre Francia y Alemania, y es el centro de un cruce ferroviario muy importante entre ambos países. Para invadir Francia, Alemania debía capturar esos patios de maniobras, por lo que la invasión de Luxemburgo fue una de las primeras acciones bélicas de la guerra de 1914. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Francia se estaba preparando para ir a la guerra contra Alemania desde el desastre de la guerra franco-prusiana de 1870, cuando el ejército prusiano acometió contra el ejército de operaciones francés, capturó al emperador y obtuvo unas concesiones humillantes en la consiguiente paz, incluyendo la cesión de los territorios de Alsacia y Lorena, al este de Francia. Una generación entera de políticos y oficiales franceses creció bajo la vergüenza de esa derrota y estaba decidida a conseguir una compensación o directamente a cobrarse la venganza. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Los principales aliados militares de Francia eran Rusia y Gran Bretaña, y lo que precipitó la participación de Francia en el conflicto, en nombre de sus aliados, fue la guerra que Rusia le declaró al Imperio Austrohúngaro. Francia, sin embargo, se centró en su guerra contra Alemania, en lugar de contra el Imperio Austrohúngaro. Así, lo primero que hicieron los franceses nada más iniciarse el conflicto fue atacar Alsacia y Lorena para recuperar el territorio rápidamente, con lo que la frontera con Bélgica y Luxemburgo quedó poco defendida. La estrategia de guerra francesa subestimó ampliamente el número de fuerzas alemanas que atacarían a lo largo de ese eje (pues creían que los alemanes entrarían a través de la región de las Ardenas), lo que provocó que los ejércitos tuviesen que cambiar de plan nada más estallar la guerra.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Una generación antes del estallido de la Primera Guerra Mundial, el ejército prusiano hizo sufrir a Francia su mayor derrota militar desde el fin de la época napoleónica y, como consecuencia, se formaría la Alemania moderna. Los políticos alemanes tenían claro que los términos que habían acordado con Francia no hacían sino plantar las semillas de un posible conflicto en el futuro, y por eso se empezaron a preparar para la siguiente guerra. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La firma de la Triple Entente (una alianza militar entre Francia, Gran Bretaña y Rusia) hizo que Alemania quedase en una situación militar precaria, pues se encontraba rodeada de rivales militares de este a oeste. La gran estrategia planeada antes de la Primera Guerra Mundial consistía en asestarle un único golpe a Francia por el oeste, antes de que Rusia pudiese mover su enorme capacidad bélica hacia el este. Este se convirtió en el objetivo político que conformaba el plan Schlieffen.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Antes de la Primera Guerra Mundial, pocos ejércitos del mundo estaban tan bien entrenados y preparados como el alemán. Y aun así, el entrenamiento y la preparación no fueron suficientes para conseguir el rápido desenlace que los estrategas habían planeado.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La participación de Gran Bretaña en la Triple Entente (una alianza militar entre Francia, Gran Bretaña y Rusia) no era algo que se pudiese dar por sentado. La antigua rivalidad militar existente entre Francia y Gran Bretaña desde la época napoleónica, así como los vínculos entre las familias reales británicas y alemanas, podrían haber hecho que Gran Bretaña se uniese a las Potencias Centrales. Sin embargo, la repentina rivalidad que surgió entre Gran Bretaña y Alemania provocó que aquella quisiese ajustar cuentas con el creciente poder alemán y decidiera unirse a la Triple Entente. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Antes de la Primera Guerra Mundial no se sabía si Gran Bretaña iba a enviar fuerzas militares a la Europa continental. Si el país envió una pequeña fuerza a suelo francés fue, en gran parte, gracias a la constante presión que ejerció un pequeño grupo de oficiales de los ejércitos franceses y británicos. De hecho, hasta el mismo káiser se sorprendió de que los británicos declarasen la guerra a Alemania, e incluso declaró que habían cometido un "error absurdo" en un "simple trozo de papel".</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La nación de Bélgica se creó al final del periodo napoleónico para equilibrar a las potencias europeas, pero siempre fue una gran aliada de Gran Bretaña. Para invadir Francia, el ejército alemán tenía que atravesar Bélgica. De hecho, las primeras versiones del plan daban por sentado que el ejército belga ofrecería una guardia de honor al ejército alemán, algo que, al final, resultó no ser así.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La ciudad de Lieja estaba rodeada por una serie de fuertes y fue el gran primer obstáculo militar para el ejército alemán en 1914. Esos fuertes, aunque habían demostrado ser útiles en muchas ocasiones, no pudieron resistir los cañones de asedio construidos específicamente para derribarlos. La caída de las fortificaciones de Lieja y la crueldad del ejército alemán contra la población belga hizo que la opinión popular se volviese en contra de los alemanes, sobre todo en Gran Bretaña.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Un comandante de campo es un oficial responsable de una gran parte del ejército de una nación, normalmente de un frente entero. Debe entender la estrategia que llevará a cabo el ejército y estar preparado para adaptarla a medida que avance el conflicto. Aunque trabaja con comandantes subalternos y recibe el consejo del Estado Mayor, el éxito o fracaso del ejército depende de su juicio. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Un comandante de campo es un oficial responsable de una gran parte del ejército de una nación, normalmente de un frente entero. Debe entender la estrategia que llevará a cabo el ejército y estar preparado para adaptarla a medida que avance el conflicto. Aunque trabaja con comandantes subalternos y recibe el consejo del Estado Mayor, el éxito o fracaso del ejército depende de su juicio.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Un comandante de campo es un oficial responsable de una gran parte del ejército de una nación, normalmente de un frente entero. Debe entender la estrategia que llevará a cabo el ejército y estar preparado para adaptarla a medida que avance el conflicto. Aunque trabaja con comandantes subalternos y recibe el consejo del Estado Mayor, el éxito o fracaso del ejército depende de su juicio.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Un comandante de campo es un oficial responsable de una gran parte del ejército de una nación, normalmente de un frente entero. Debe entender la estrategia que llevará a cabo el ejército y estar preparado para adaptarla a medida que avance el conflicto. Aunque trabaja con comandantes subalternos y recibe el consejo del Estado Mayor, el éxito o fracaso del ejército depende de su juicio.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Un comandante de campo es un oficial responsable de una gran parte del ejército de una nación, normalmente de un frente entero. Debe entender la estrategia que llevará a cabo el ejército y estar preparado para adaptarla a medida que avance el conflicto. Aunque trabaja con comandantes subalternos y recibe el consejo del Estado Mayor, el éxito o fracaso del ejército depende de su juicio.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El cuartel general es el lugar en donde se trazan las estrategias que luego llevarán a cabo los ejércitos. Aunque están conectados a los comandantes que se encuentran en los frentes mediante mensajeros y un sistema de telegrafía, no permanecen mucho tiempo en un mismo sitio debido al cambio constante de las líneas de combate y a la obligación del alto mando a permanecer cerca de la acción.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Comandante de campo</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Aumenta la fuerza de tus defensas externas para resistir todos los asaltos, excepto los más violentos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Victoria de Maquinaria bélica</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Como Alemania debes capturar la ciudad de París antes de que se acabe el tiempo. Como Francia debes defender París de los invasores hasta que se acabe el tiempo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+3 a la Fuerza de combate [ICON_Strength] a las unidades terrestres a 2 casillas o menos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+3 de bonificación al Combate [ICON_Strength] por Gran general.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+100 a los puntos de golpe de todas las ciudades.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+6 a la Fuerza de combate [ICON_Strength] de las unidades de artillería.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Permite formar y entrenar Ejércitos.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Otorga 2 Grandes generales [ICON_GreatGeneral] gratis en tu capital [ICON_Capital].</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+5 a la Fuerza de combate [ICON_Strength] de todas las unidades.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Unidad de apoyo de la Edad Media. Necesita un Arsenal para producir. Puede construir mejoras de Ferrocarriles, Fuertes y Pistas de aterrizaje.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Control de París</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Control de París</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Mariscal de campo</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La prueba del dominio militar no se halla en campañas prolongadas, sino en las victorias decisivas.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>General</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Comandar es el arte de dirigir las fuerzas bélicas con éxito y sin esfuerzo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Coronel</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>El éxito y el fracaso dependen completamente de la información y la intuición.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Mayor</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Donde hay coraje, hay audacia. Donde hay audacia, hay impulso. Donde hay impulso, hay victoria.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Capitán</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>La victoria, a ser posible, pero el honor ante todo.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Aeronave</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Fortificaciones</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>2</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Artillería pesada</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Logística</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Mando</Text>
      <Gender>masculine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>Guerra industrial</Text>
      <Gender>feminine</Gender>
      <Plurality>1</Plurality>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>{1_Day} de agosto de 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>{1_Day} de septiembre de 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} de Guerra industrial</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="es_ES">
      <Text>+{1_Amount} de Artillería pesada</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>要塞</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>軍事總部</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>里耳</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>漢斯</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>南錫</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>貝爾福</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>奧爾良</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>沙特爾</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>科隆</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>科布倫茨</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>曼海姆</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>史特拉斯堡</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>科爾馬</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>安特衛普</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>列日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>那慕爾</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>芒斯</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>盧森堡</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>為了攻破圍繞比利時的堡壘防線，德軍開發出專門的攻城大砲。這些大砲收到了極為成功的效果，在規劃者預估的時間前便拿下這些堡壘。法軍也開發出精密且強大的75毫米火砲，其持久靈活的設計讓其一時成為戰爭的圭臬。但就算有如此先進的火砲，也無法打破壕溝戰所造成的僵持局面。一直到發明坦克、飛機和小隊戰略等新軍事技術後局勢才有所改變。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>後勤是將物資供應至軍隊處，藉以補充戰事耗損的過程。雖然說不上是極為光彩的工作，然而是否能正確執行這些細節，將成為決定戰爭勝敗的關鍵。門外漢才會鑽研戰術，高手都鑽研後勤。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>拿破崙時代後，專業軍官開始將戰略和行動規劃納入考量。專業參謀便是軍隊中專職將戰爭的政治目標轉化為軍事行動目標的軍官。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在全面戰爭期間，國家的全數資源皆會投入戰爭之用。在工業化的社會中，這代表將整個工業基礎設施改造為武器工廠，透過大量徵兵來將人民訓練成兵員，並且透過公開的政治工具來引導國內經濟。戰爭對社會所造成的深遠影響，甚至可能會在衝突結束之後仍縈繞不去。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在一次大戰爆發前，由於機關槍和高爆砲彈等新發明，防禦工事的建立也有所變化。從蔓延西方戰線的壕溝系統上，我們能看見當防禦優勢大大壓過進攻優勢時會發生什麼事：兩軍在戰爭期間大多僵持不下。同樣的，1916年後開始發展的現代化步兵及坦克戰術也能視為是試圖克服此防禦優勢的舉措。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>一次大戰爆發時，飛行技術仍在初步階段，當時飛機不僅造價昂貴，還極不可靠，僅能作為偵查機使用。經過無數戰火洗禮與改良後，等到一戰進入尾聲時，飛機已經成為全球主要勢力執行戰術攻擊和戰略轟炸時的必備軍備。由於當時研究開發的費用太過昂貴，許多飛機的開發都必須由政府贊助，或者透過公用事業民營化來取得資金。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>於1870年普法戰爭的色當會戰慘敗之後，法軍主理者必須從災難般的戰敗和喪權辱國的政治後果中走出，才能重建一支歐洲首屈一指的軍隊。和追求精密戰鬥行動規畫的德國人不同，法軍軍官開始採用彈性化進攻的概念。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>當時的想法是，軍隊能透過持續攻擊敵方戰線來維持進攻勢頭，然後便能把握住進攻所揭露的弱點。敵軍將無法重新站穩腳步，法軍便能一直掌握主動權，屆時德軍的推進將會遭到閃電般的反擊。這個策略不只適用於軍團層面，也適用於戰場層面，只要來犯者有弱點，法軍就會往那裡打。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>1914年8月，在低地國戰線的法軍已搖搖欲墜，他們後來卻在亞爾薩斯和洛林取得進展，但此時必須回去增援北方，以避免巴黎淪陷。到了同年年底，隨著西部戰線陷入壕溝戰，「持續進攻」的精神也已經蕩然無存。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>採用著精細到包含行軍和鐵路運輸時間表的戰略規劃，普魯士軍隊在1870年的普法戰爭中驗證了全面且按部就班的軍事規劃能帶來勝利。在擔任總參謀長時，馮‧施里芬預期未來將不免和法國一戰，於是便開始規劃入侵法國的計劃，此計劃史稱「施里芬計劃」。這個入侵計劃的要點為於西方部署大量德軍兵力，並且透過從低地國一路挺進南方的巴黎，來快速結束西部戰局，然而德軍未有機會完全執行此計劃。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在兩側戰線的夾攻下，德軍高層將某些原本打算強攻西面的軍隊轉移到完全不同的戰線去（在這案例中是打算迎擊俄軍）。德軍成功突破低地國並且逼退法軍後，戰線上的突出部引起了德軍總參謀長的興趣。但由於執行施里芬計劃的兵力不足，德軍也必須因應法軍的攻勢進行便宜行事的調整，在加上法軍和英軍的強硬抵抗，種種的因素終究導致施里芬計劃無法達到原本預計的一擊斃命效果。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>德軍豪賭了一把，但是輸了，而隨著施里芬計劃的失敗，西方戰線也開始陷入延續了四年的漫長戰火。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>英國遠征軍是一小支倉促成軍的部隊，其主要目的是為明確表達英國和法國等協約之間的緊密關係。原本部署在遠離法國戰線的西方，這支部隊在當時被視為一種政治禮節，而非實質的戰力。然而，就在德軍透過低地國開往巴黎時，英國遠征軍也在芒斯戰役裡對上了具備人數優勢的德軍，儘管後來遭到大敗且被迫撤退，他們仍拯救了法國第五軍團，使其免於遭到全殲。芒斯戰役是大英帝國最受尊崇的軍事成就之一，也是英國遠征軍的代表作。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>比利時是在拿破崙時代尾聲時為了平衡歐洲各大勢力而建立的國家，但他們長期以來都是英國的特別盟友。德軍當時對法國的入侵計畫需要途經比利時來執行。這個計畫的早期方案認為，比利時軍隊會門戶大開地歡迎德軍經過，但這樣的假設結果大錯特錯。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>列日這座城市週邊圍繞著一系列的堡壘，這成為德軍在1914年入侵時碰到的第一個重大軍事阻礙。雖然這些堡壘在許多戰事中戰果豐碩，但還是承受不住專用的攻城火砲。列日防禦工事的崩潰，以及德軍對比利時人民的殘酷對待，讓全世界群起反抗德國，其中反對最力者便是英國。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>盧森堡這個小國位於法國與德國之間，而且是多個國家之間主要鐵路網的中心。在德國入侵法國的計畫當中，攻佔這些機廠是非常關鍵的一件事，因此盧森堡的入侵行動是1914年戰事的首波行動之一。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>自從普魯士軍隊於1870年的普法戰爭重創法國陸軍、俘虜法皇且逼迫法國以喪權辱國的條約（包括割讓法國東部的亞爾薩斯和洛林）來換取和平後，法國便開始勵精圖治、積極備戰，期待能和德意志帝國再次一決雌雄。一整個世代的法國政客和軍官都在普法戰爭戰敗的陰影下長大，並且決心雪恥，報復過去喪權辱國之仇恨。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>法國的主要軍事盟友為俄國及大英帝國，而也是因為俄國正式向奧匈帝國宣戰，才促成法國以盟友身分投入戰局之中。然而法國在主要還是將重心放在和德意志帝國間的戰鬥上，並未打算花太多心力對抗奧匈帝國。為達此目的，法國在戰爭爆發時，將主要的軍力投入亞爾薩斯和洛林的攻勢上，期待能迅速收復故土，卻也因此僅投入薄弱的兵力防守和比利時及盧森堡接壤的北方邊境。法軍的戰爭規劃中嚴重低估了會從北方邊境進攻的德軍人數（法軍本預計德軍會從阿登高地突破），也因此在戰爭爆發之初便需要急忙改變計畫。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在一次世界大戰爆發前數十年，普魯士軍隊讓法國吞下拿破崙時代終結後的最大敗仗，也因為這場敗仗，現代德國的前身才得以建立。德意志的政客早已心知肚明於普法戰後逼迫法國所簽署的條約將種下下一次衝突的根源，於是也開始為此積極備戰。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>三國協約（法國、大英帝國和俄國間的軍事同盟）的簽署讓德意志陷入尷尬的軍事立場，如今德國在東部和西部都有強敵環伺。德意志在一次大戰前所構思的戰略是希望能在俄國動員大量人力投入東方戰線前先行以迅猛的攻勢盡速擊敗西方的法國。而這也成為施里芬計劃的主要政治目標。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在一次大戰爆發前夕，世界上少有像德意志軍隊如此訓練有素且裝備精良的軍隊。然而跌破計畫者眼鏡的是，充足的準備和訓練仍不足以帶來如預期般的迅捷勝利。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>大英帝國加入三國協約（法國、大英帝國和俄國間的軍事同盟）一事可說跌破眾人眼鏡。法國和大英帝國間有著可追溯至拿破崙時代的軍備競賽淵源，而英國皇室和德意志間的關係也讓外界認為英國很可能會加入同盟國的行列。在德意志和大英帝國快速升高的競爭局勢下，大英帝國最終還是加入其他忌憚德意志崛起的陣營之中，成為三國協約的一員。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在一次世界大戰開戰前夕，大英帝國從未承諾過會派遣軍隊前往歐洲大陸。但在一小群法軍和英軍軍官的持續推波助瀾下，大英帝國最終派遣一小支軍隊前往法國本土。德皇本人對於英國向德意志宣戰一事感到驚訝，宣稱英國用「一張小廢紙」犯下了「愚蠢的錯誤」。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>比利時是在拿破崙時代尾聲時為了平衡歐洲各大勢力而建立的國家，但他們長期以來都是英國的特別盟友。德軍當時對法國的入侵計畫需要途經比利時來執行。這個計畫的早期方案認為，比利時軍隊會門戶大開地歡迎德軍經過，但這樣的假設結果大錯特錯。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>列日這座城市週邊圍繞著一系列的堡壘，這成為德軍在1914年入侵時碰到的第一個重大軍事阻礙。雖然這些堡壘在許多戰事中戰果豐碩，但還是承受不住專用的攻城火砲。列日防禦工事的崩潰，以及德軍對比利時人民的殘酷對待，讓全世界群起反抗德國，其中反對最力者便是英國。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>戰地指揮官是負責協調大部分國軍調度的軍官，往往需要統領整個戰線的行動。他必須了解軍隊的行動方針，並且願意在戰事發生變化時進行調整。雖然他會透過從屬的指揮官引導戰事進行，並且有參謀單位為其出謀劃策，但軍隊的成敗與否還是要仰賴他的判斷。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>戰地指揮官是負責協調大部分國軍調度的軍官，往往需要統領整個戰線的行動。他必須了解軍隊的行動方針，並且願意在戰事發生變化時進行調整。雖然他會透過從屬的指揮官引導戰事進行，並且有參謀單位為其出謀劃策，但軍隊的成敗與否還是要仰賴他的判斷。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>戰地指揮官是負責協調大部分國軍調度的軍官，往往需要統領整個戰線的行動。他必須了解軍隊的行動方針，並且願意在戰事發生變化時進行調整。雖然他會透過從屬的指揮官引導戰事進行，並且有參謀單位為其出謀劃策，但軍隊的成敗與否還是要仰賴他的判斷。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>戰地指揮官是負責協調大部分國軍調度的軍官，往往需要統領整個戰線的行動。他必須了解軍隊的行動方針，並且願意在戰事發生變化時進行調整。雖然他會透過從屬的指揮官引導戰事進行，並且有參謀單位為其出謀劃策，但軍隊的成敗與否還是要仰賴他的判斷。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>戰地指揮官是負責協調大部分國軍調度的軍官，往往需要統領整個戰線的行動。他必須了解軍隊的行動方針，並且願意在戰事發生變化時進行調整。雖然他會透過從屬的指揮官引導戰事進行，並且有參謀單位為其出謀劃策，但軍隊的成敗與否還是要仰賴他的判斷。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在軍事總部中，軍隊的行動計畫會以軍令的形式在戰場上實現。軍事總部將透過傳令兵與電報和戰線上的指揮官進行聯繫；而這些設施通常是暫時性措施，因為戰線會移動，讓最高統帥部需要持續密切關注行動狀況。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>戰地指揮官</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>提高對外防禦的強度，除非遭到集中攻擊，否則能擋住一切攻勢。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>戰爭機械勝利</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>作為德國，你必須在時限內佔領巴黎。作為法國，則必須在時限結束前守住巴黎。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>2個單元格內所有陸地單位+3 [ICON_Strength] 戰鬥力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>來自大將軍的 [ICON_Strength] 戰鬥加成+3。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>所有城市+100生命值。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>所有大炮單位+6 [ICON_Strength] 戰鬥力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>允許編隊和生產軍隊。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>在你的 [ICON_Capital] 首都處獲得2名免費的 [ICON_GreatGeneral] 大將軍。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>所有單位+5 [ICON_Strength] 戰鬥力。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>中世紀支援單位。要求在軍械庫進行生產。能修建鐵路、堡壘、飛機跑道改良設施。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>巴黎的控制權</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>巴黎的控制權</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>元帥</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>真正的軍事才能不是在漫長的戰役中運籌帷幄，而是決勝於千里之外。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>將軍</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>號令之道，便是一門能成功並輕鬆引導戰爭情勢的藝術。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>中校</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>行動的成敗，維繫在資訊和直覺所構成的一絲平衡上。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>少校</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>有了勇氣，就能膽大心細。有了膽大心細，就能掌握局勢。掌握了局勢，就能拿下勝利。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>上尉</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>如果可能便奪得勝利，但榮譽才是一切。</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>飛機</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>防禦工事</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>重型火砲</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>後勤</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>司令部</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>工業化戰爭</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>1914年8月{1_Day}日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>1914年9月{1_Day}日</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>+{1_Amount}工業時代戰爭</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="zh_Hant_HK">
      <Text>+{1_Amount}重型火砲</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_NAME]Headquarters</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_DESCRIPTION]Raises the strength of your outer defenses to withstand all but the most concentrated assaults.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_BUILDING_STAR_FORT_NAME]Fortress</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_ANTWERP]Antwerp</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_BELFORT]Belfort</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_CHARTES]Chartes</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_COLMAR]Colmar</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_KOBLENZ]Koblenz</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_KOLN]Köln</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_LIEGE]Liège</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_LILLE]Lille</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_LUXEMBOURG]Luxembourg</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_MANNHEIM]Mannheim</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_MONS]Mons</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_NAMUR]Namur</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_NANCY]Nancy</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_ORLEANS]Orleans</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_REIMS]Reims</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_CITY_NAME_STRASSBURG]Strassburg</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_DEFAULT_NAME]Field Commander</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT]+{1_Amount} Heavy Artillery</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_PREVIEW_TEXT]+{1_Amount} Industrial Warfare</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_HEADQUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]The headquarters is the place where the operational plans of the army are put into orders for the field. Connected to subordinate commanders along the battle line through messengers and telegraph, these are often temporary affairs, as the shifting battle lines require high command to stay close to the action.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_LUXEMBOURG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]The tiny principality of Luxembourg lies between France and Germany, and moreover is the center of a major rail junction between the countries. Capture of these railyards was critical for the German plan to invade France, and consequently the invasion of Luxembourg was one of the first actions of the war in 1914. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]The nation of Belgium had been created at the end of the Napoleonic Era as part of the balance of European powers but had long been a special ally of Great Britain. The invasion plan of France called for the German Army to invade through Belgium. Indeed, early versions of the plan posited the Belgian Army would provide an honor guard along the roads for the passing German Army—a highly incorrect assumption, as it turned out.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2]The city of Liege was surrounded by a series of forts and represented the first significant military obstacle to the German Army in 1914. The forts, although they fought well in many cases, were unable to hold out against special siege guns constructed specifically for the purposes of breaking these forts. The collapse of the Liege fortifications and the cruelty of the German army against the population of Belgium turned the tide of popular opinion against Germany, especially in Great Britain.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]Great Britain’s participation in the Triple Entente (the military alliance between France, Great Britain, and Russia) was by no means a foregone conclusion. Longstanding military competition between France and Great Britain dating back to the time of Napoleon, as well as ties between the royal families of Great Britain and Germany made British participation in the Central Powers a plausible outcome. Ultimately Great Britain joined the Entente due to a quick rise in competition between Germany and Great Britain that saw many people seek checks on rising German power. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2]On the eve of World War I, there was no guarantee that Great Britain would send military forces into continental Europe. It was largely through the constant pressure of a small group of officers in both the French and British armies that saw Great Britain commit a small force to French soil. Indeed, the Kaiser himself was shocked that the British declared war on Germany, declaring that they had made a “foolish mistake” over a “mere scrap of paper.”</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]France had been preparing for war with Germany since the disaster of the Franco-Prussian War in 1870, when the Prussian army had mauled the French field army, captured the Emperor, and extracted humiliating concessions in the peace that had followed, including the cessation of the territories of Alsace and Lorraine in the east of France.  An entire generation of French politicians and officers had grown up in the shadow of this defeat, and were determined to seek vindication, if not outright vengeance for the loss. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2]France’s main military allies were Russia and Great Britain, and it was the Russian declaration of war against The Austro-Hungarian Empire that precipitated France’s entry into the war on behalf of the allies. France, however, was focused primarily on their own fight against Germany than that against Austro-Hungary. To that end, the primary French effort at the outbreak of the war was an attack into Alsace and Lorraine to recapture that territory quickly, leaving the northern border with Belgium and Luxembourg only lightly defended. The French war plans critically underestimated the number of German forces who would be attacking along that axis (it presumed the Germans would come through the Ardennes), forcing the armies to abruptly shift plans at the very outbreak of the war.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]A generation before the outbreak of World War I, the Prussian army had handed France its greatest military defeat since the end of the Napoleonic Era, and in the aftermath had formed the modern nation of Germany. German politicians were clear-eyed about how the terms extracted from the French were contributing the seeds to the next potential conflict—and then went about preparing for the next war. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2]The signing of the Triple Entente—the military alliance of France, Great Britain, and Russia—put Germany in a precarious military position, as it was now surrounded by military adversaries to the east and west. The grand strategy formulated prior to World War I was to deliver a single, massive knockout blow to France in the west before Russia would have a chance to bring its enormous manpower advantage to bear in the east. This became the driving political goal of the Schlieffen Plan.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3]On the eve of World War I, there were few armies in the world that were as well-trained and as prepared as the German military forces. And yet preparation and training were not enough to bring about the quick end the planners had envisioned.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_1_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]A field commander is an officer responsible for a huge portion of his nation’s military, usually along an entire front. He must understand both the operational plan of his army and be willing to adapt these as changes warrant in the course of the war. Although he works through subordinate commanders and is advised by the general staff, the success or failure of the army rests on his judgement.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_2_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]A field commander is an officer responsible for a huge portion of his nation’s military, usually along an entire front. He must understand both the operational plan of his army and be willing to adapt these as changes warrant in the course of the war. Although he works through subordinate commanders and is advised by the general staff, the success or failure of the army rests on his judgement.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_3_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]A field commander is an officer responsible for a huge portion of his nation’s military, usually along an entire front. He must understand both the operational plan of his army and be willing to adapt these as changes warrant in the course of the war. Although he works through subordinate commanders and is advised by the general staff, the success or failure of the army rests on his judgement.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_GENERAL_4_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]A field commander is an officer responsible for a huge portion of his nation’s military, usually along an entire front. He must understand both the operational plan of his army and be willing to adapt these as changes warrant in the course of the war. Although he works through subordinate commanders and is advised by the general staff, the success or failure of the army rests on his judgement.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]The nation of Belgium had been created at the end of the Napoleonic Era as part of the balance of European powers but had long been a special ally of Great Britain. The invasion plan of France called for the German Army to invade through Belgium. Indeed, early versions of the plan posited the Belgian Army would provide an honor guard along the roads for the passing German Army—a highly incorrect assumption, as it turned out. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BELGIUM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2]The city of Liege was surrounded by a series of forts and represented the first significant military obstacle to the German Army in 1914. The forts, although they fought well in many cases, were unable to hold out against special siege guns constructed specifically for the purposes of breaking these forts. The collapse of the Liege fortifications and the cruelty of the German army against the population of Belgium turned the tide of popular opinion against Germany, especially in Great Britain.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_BRITAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]The British Expeditionary Force was a small army rushed into the field with the express purpose of drawing the British more closely into the entente with the French. Positioned on the far west of the French line, they were initially seen more as a political courtesy than a substantial military force. However, as the Germans descended through the Low Countries towards Paris, the BEF fought a numerically superior German force in the Battle of Mons, and despite being mauled and eventually forced to retreat, they saved the French Fifth Army from annihilation. The Battle of Mons is one of Great Britain’s most celebrated and honored military achievements, and synonymous with the BEF.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]After the disastrous Battle of Sedan during the Franco-Prussian War of 1870, French military planners had to recover from that catastrophic loss and the humiliating political aftermath in order to rebuild the army into one of the first-rate armies of Europe. In contrast to the German penchant for detailed operational plans of battle, French military officers began to espouse a doctrine of flexible offensives.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2]The army, it was thought, would retain its momentum through constant attack of the enemy lines, and ruthlessly exploiting any weakness that followed. The enemy would never be able to catch their balance, initiative would stay on the part of the French, and the grinding advances of the German enemies would be checked by lightning counter-thrusts. This would apply from the battalion level up to the theater level – where the invader was weak, there the French would attack.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_FRANCE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3]It is one of the great paradoxes of August 1914 that even as the French staggered along the front in the Low Countries, they were meeting with advances through Alsace and Lorraine, but these had to be checked to provide reinforcements to save Paris. By the end of that year, the spirit of “always attack” had faded, and the trenches defined the Western Front.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]The successes of the Prussian Army in 1870 during the Franco-Prussian War vindicated the methodical, comprehensive planning of the army, down to timetables of marching troops and railcars on tracks. Seeing a future war with France as probably inevitable, Count von Schlieffen, chief of the German General Staff, drew up plans for a future invasion of France, passing through the Low Countries and descending on Paris to the south. This invasion plan demanded a concentration of forces on the far western flank of the German army for success – but the full plan was never executed in its entirety.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2]With war on two fronts, the German high command transferred some of the forces intended for the heavy west flank to an entirely different battlefront (in this case, against the Russians). As the German army successfully smashed through the Low Countries, it set the French Army back on its heels as well, and a salient forming in the French lines presented the German General Staff with a tempting target. But various factors, including the reduction in forces in the Schlieffen plan, improvisational movements of German troops in response to the French, and the stiff resistance of the French and British meant that the knockout blow never achieved its goals.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_GERMANY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3]The Germans had gambled and lost, and the war settled into four years of hell along the lines where the Schlieffen plan died.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_AIRCRAFT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]At the start of the First World War, aviation was still in its infancy, and aircraft were expensive and unreliable machines for reconnaissance. By the end of the war, they were a staple of every major military on the planet and employed for tactical attacks and strategic bombing, having undergone rapid evolution in the crucible of the war. Research and development was so expensive that much of it was done through state sponsorship or public-private partnership.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_COMMAND_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]After the Napoleonic era, professional military officers began to incorporate both strategic and operational planning into their work. The professional command staff is the part of the military responsible for achieving translating political goals for war into military objectives. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]The invention of the machinegun and the new high explosive artillery rounds meant that fortifications changed as well in the years leading up to the first World War. The extensive trench systems of the Western Front can be seen as physical expression of the supremacy of defense over offense for much of the war. Likewise, the modern tactics for infantry and tanks developed from 1916-oneward can be seen as an effort to overcome this supremacy of defense.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]The Germans developed specialized siege guns to crack the defenses of the ring of forts surrounding Belgium. These proved to be very successful, causing the forts to fall sooner than the planners projected. The French developed a sophisticated and powerful 75mm artillery cannon which proved to be long-lasting and flexible. But neither was enough to break the stalemate of the trenches by themselves—new technologies in the tank and aircraft and small-unit tactics would eventually do that.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]In total war, all the resources of the state are put in service of the war aims. In an industrial society, this means a total reworking of the industrial infrastructure into creating weaponry, training swaths of the population under arms for mass conscription, and directing the economy through overt political tools. It can transform the society in ways that redound long after the conflict ends.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_TECHNOLOGIES_PAGE_TECH_LOGISTICS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]Logistics is the process of supplying material to an army to replace losses and expenditure. Although not glamorous, success in warfare depends on getting these details absolutely right. Amateurs study tactics; experts study logistics. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_GREAT_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1]A field commander is an officer responsible for a huge portion of his nation’s military, usually along an entire front. He must understand both the operational plan of his army and be willing to adapt these as changes warrant in the course of the war. Although he works through subordinate commanders and is advised by the general staff, the success or failure of the army rests on his judgement. </Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_SCENARIO_CATEGORY_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME]Control of Paris</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_SCENARIO_LINE_ITEM_CONTROL_OF_PARIS_NAME]Control of Paris</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH]+3 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength to land units within 2 tiles.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_SCENARIO_WARMACHINE_GREAT_GENERAL_STRENGTH_MODIFIER]+3 [ICON_Strength] Combat Bonus from Great General.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_AIRCRAFT_NAME]Aircraft</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_COMMAND_DESCRIPTION]Grants 2 free [ICON_GreatGeneral] Great Generals in your [ICON_Capital] Capital.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_COMMAND_NAME]Command</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_DESCRIPTION]+100 hit points in all cities.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_FORTIFICATIONS_NAME]Fortifications</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_DESCRIPTION]+6 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength for Artillery units.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_HEAVY_ARTILLERY_NAME]Heavy Artillery</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_DESCRIPTION]+5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength for all units.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_INDUSTRIAL_WARFARE_NAME]Industrial Warfare</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_DESCRIPTION]Allows the formation and training of Armies.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_TECH_LOGISTICS_NAME]Logistics</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_WARMACHINE_DESCRIPTION]Medieval era support unit. Requires an Armory to produce. Can construct Railroads, Forts, and Airstrips improvements.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_AUGUST]August {1_Day}, 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_CALENDAR_SEPT]September {1_Day}, 1914</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_NAME]Field Marshall</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_1_QUOTE]The proof of military mastery is not found in protracted campaigns, but in decisive victory.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_NAME]General</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_2_QUOTE]Command is the art of successfully and effortlessly directing the forces of war.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_NAME]Colonel</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_3_QUOTE]Success or failure balances on the knife edge of information and intuition.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_NAME]Major</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_4_QUOTE]Where there is courage, there is audacity. Where there is audacity, there is momentum. Where there is momentum, there is victory.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_NAME]Captain</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WARMACHINE_SCENARIO_ENDGAME_RANK_5_QUOTE]Victory if possible, but honor above all.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_DETAILS]As Germany you must capture the city of Paris within the time limit. As France, you must defend Paris against capture until the time runs out.</Text>
    </Replace>
    <Replace Tag="LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY" Language="zh_Hans">
      <Text>[COLOR_RED]TRANSLATION MISSING[ENDCOLOR][LOC_WORLD_RANKINGS_SCORE_VICTORY]War Machine Victory</Text>
    </Replace>
  </LocalizedText>
</GameData>