<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Ed Beach (Firaxis Games) -->
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<Row Tag="LOC_EXPANSION2_NAME">
			<Text>Expansion: Gathering Storm</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>This is a game using the Gathering Storm Expansion, which includes the World Congress, environmental effects and disasters, power, and more. Can you deal with the unpredictability of a changing world to make a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Setup Parameters -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_GAME_REALISM">
			<Text>Disaster Intensity</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_GAME_REALISM_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Set natural disaster intensity. Choose from a setting of 0 (less frequent and intense natural disasters) to 4 (frequent and intense natural disasters). Note that on settings of 3 and 4, severe volcanic eruptions may damage tiles two hexes away.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Front End-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_VICTORY_DIPLOMATIC_NAME">
			<Text>Diplomatic Victory</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_VICTORY_DIPLOMATIC_TT">
			<Text>You show the world that cooperation among nations is the only way to a lasting and just peace. Earn this victory through respect and the World Congress.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_VICTORY_DIPLOMATIC_TEXT">
			<Text>Harmony and peace replace war and violence. The differences and disagreements between people can always be resolved through goodwill. With conflict behind us, what glories will our shared future hold?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- New Maps  -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_MAP_CONTINENTS_ISLANDS_NAME">
			<Text>Continents and Islands</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MAP_PRIMORDIAL_NAME">
			<Text>Primordial</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MAP_SPLINTERED_FRACTAL_NAME">
			<Text>Splintered Fractal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MAP_TILTED_AXIS_NAME">
			<Text>Tilted Axis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MAP_CONTINENTS_ISLANDS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A few large landmasses surrounded by islands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MAP_PRIMORDIAL_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A map from early time with unpredictable continents and islands. More volatile conditions exist with extra coastal lowlands and volcanoes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MAP_SPLINTERED_FRACTAL_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A highly random map that will often form thin, snaky continents and islands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_MAP_TILTED_AXIS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A polar centered continents map.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--America-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_FOUNDING_FATHERS_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>All Diplomatic policy slots in the current government are converted to Wildcard slots. +1 [ICON_FAVOR] Diplomatic Favor per turn for every Wildcard slot in their government.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Canada-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_CANADA_NAME">
			<Text>Canada</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_CANADA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Canadian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_CANADA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Canadian Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_LAURIER_NAME">
			<Text>Wilfrid Laurier</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ICE_HOCKEY_RINK_NAME">
			<Text>Ice Hockey Rink</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_ICE_HOCKEY_RINK_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unlocks the Builder ability to construct an Ice Hockey Rink, unique to Canada.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+1 [ICON_AMENITIES] Amenity. +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture for each adjacent Tundra, Tundra Hills, Snow, and Snow Hills tile. Provides [ICON_Tourism] Tourism from Culture once Flight is unlocked. +2 [ICON_FOOD] Food and [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production once the Professional Sports civic is unlocked. +4 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture if adjacent to a Stadium building. Can be built on Tundra, Tundra Hills, Snow, and Snow Hills. One per city. +2 Appeal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_FACES_OF_PEACE_NAME">
			<Text>Four Faces of Peace</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_FACES_OF_PEACE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Cannot declare war on City-States or surprise wars. Surprise wars cannot be declared on Canada. For every 100 [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism per turn earn 1 [ICON_Favor] Diplomatic Favor per turn. Receive +100% [ICON_Favor] Diplomatic Favor from successfully completing an Emergency or Scored Competition.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LAST_BEST_WEST_NAME">
			<Text>The Last Best West</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_LAST_BEST_WEST_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Allows Farms to be built on Tundra terrain. After Civil Engineering is unlocked Farms can be built on Tundra Hills. In Snow, Tundra, Snow Hills, and Tundra Hills all Mines provide +1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production, Lumber Mills provide +1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production, Camps provide +1 [ICON_FOOD] Food, and strategic resource accumulation rate is +100%. Reduces the purchase cost of tiles in these terrain types by 50%.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_CANADA_MOUNTIE_NAME">
			<Text>Mountie</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_CANADA_MOUNTIE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Canadian unique Modern era unit. Can create a National Park. +5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength when fighting within 2 tiles of a National Park. Additional +5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength when fighting within 2 tiles of a National Park you own.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--England-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_INDUSTRIAL_REVOLUTION_NAME">
			<Text>Workshop of the World</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_INDUSTRIAL_REVOLUTION_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Iron and Coal Mines accumulate 2 more resources per turn. +100% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production towards Military Engineers. Military Engineers receive +2 charges. Buildings that provide additional yields when [ICON_POWER] Powered receive +4 of that yield. +20% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production towards Industrial Zone buildings. Harbor buildings increase Strategic Resource Stockpiles by +10 on Standard Speed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_PAX_BRITANNICA_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Each time you found your first city on a continent other than your home continent receive a free melee unit and a [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Route capacity. Constructing any Royal Navy Dockyard grants you a copy of the strongest naval unit you can build. Gain the Redcoat unique unit when the Military Science technology is researched.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Egypt-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_ITERU_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>+15% [ICON_Production] Production towards districts and wonders if placed next to a River. Does not receive damage from Floods.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Eleanor-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_ELEANOR_NAME">
			<Text>Eleanor of Aquitaine</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_ELEANOR_LOYALTY_NAME">
			<Text>Court of Love</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_ELEANOR_LOYALTY_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Great Works in Eleanor’s cities each cause -1 Loyalty per turn in foreign cities within 9 tiles. A city that leaves another civilization due to a loss of Loyalty and is currently receiving the most Loyalty per turn from Eleanor's civilization skips the Free City step to join this civilization.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Georgia-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_GOLDEN_AGE_QUESTS_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>When making Dedications at the beginning of a Golden Age or Heroic Age, receive the Normal Age bonus towards improving Era Score in addition to the other bonus. +50% [ICON_Production] Production towards defensive buildings.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Hungary-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_HUNGARY_NAME">
			<Text>Hungary</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_HUNGARY_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Hungarian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_HUNGARY_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Hungarian Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_MATTHIAS_CORVINUS_NAME">
			<Text>Matthias Corvinus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_THERMAL_BATH_NAME">
			<Text>Thermal Bath</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_THERMAL_BATH_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A building unique to Hungary. +2 [ICON_AMENITIES] Amenities and +2 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production extends to each city center within 6 tiles. These bonuses apply once to a city, and multiple copies of this building within 6 tiles of a city center do not provide additional bonuses.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]This city receives +3 [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism and +2 additional [ICON_AMENITIES] Amenities if there is at least one Geothermal Fissure in this city's borders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_PEARL_DANUBE_NAME">
			<Text>Pearl of the Danube</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_PEARL_DANUBE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>+50% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production to Districts and Buildings constructed across a river from a City Center.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_RAVEN_KING_NAME">
			<Text>Raven King</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_RAVEN_KING_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Levied units gain an ability giving them +2 [ICON_Movement] Movement and +5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength. It costs 75% less [ICON_GOLD] Gold and resources to upgrade Levied units. If you Levy troops from a City-State receive 2 [ICON_ENVOY] Envoys with that City-State. Gain the Black Army unique unit when the Castles technology is researched.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_HUNGARY_BLACK_ARMY_NAME">
			<Text>Black Army</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_HUNGARY_BLACK_ARMY_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Hungarian unique Medieval Era unit that replaces the Courser. +3 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength for each adjacent Levied unit.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_HUNGARY_HUSZAR_NAME">
			<Text>Huszár</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_HUNGARY_HUSZAR_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Hungarian unique Industrial era unit that replaces Cavalry. +3 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength for every active Alliance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Inca-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_INCA_NAME">
			<Text>Inca</Text>
			<Gender>Masculine:the</Gender>
			<Plurality>2</Plurality>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_INCA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Incan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_INCA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Incan Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_GREAT_MOUNTAINS_NAME">
			<Text>Mit’a</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_GREAT_MOUNTAINS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Citizens may work Mountain tiles. Mountain tiles provide +2 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production. +1 [ICON_FOOD] Food to Mountain tiles for every adjacent Terrace Farm.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_PACHACUTI_NAME">
			<Text>Pachacuti</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_TERRACE_FARM_NAME">
			<Text>Terrace Farm</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_TERRACE_FARM_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unlocks the Builder ability to construct a Terrace Farm, unique to the Inca.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+1 [ICON_FOOD] Food. Provides +1 [ICON_Housing] Housing for every two Terrace Farms. +1 [ICON_FOOD] Food for each adjacent Mountain Tile. Gain +2 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production for each adjacent Aqueduct district. Receive +1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production if adjacent to Fresh Water and not an Aqueduct district. Additional [ICON_FOOD] Food as you advance through the Civics and Technology Tree for adjacency with other Terrace Farms. Can be placed on Grassland Hills, Plains Hills, and Desert Hills.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_INCA_WARAKAQ_NAME">
			<Text>Warak’aq</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_INCA_WARAKAQ_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Incan unique Medieval Era unit that replaces the Skirmisher. Stronger at ranged combat than the Skirmisher and +1 additional attack per turn.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_PACHACUTI_QHAPAQ_NAN_NAME">
			<Text>Qhapaq Ñan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_PACHACUTI_QHAPAQ_NAN_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Domestic [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes gain +1 [ICON_Food] Food for every Mountain tile in the origin city. Gain the Qhapaq Ñan improvement when Foreign Trade civic is discovered.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MOUNTAIN_ROAD_NAME">
			<Text>Qhapaq Ñan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MOUNTAIN_ROAD_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unlocks the Builder ability to construct a Qhapaq Ñan, unique to Pachacuti.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Acts as a movement portal on a mountain range, allowing units to move into it and exit from another portal at the cost of 2 [ICON_Movement] Movement. [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes traveling through it can multiply the [ICON_Gold] Gold they get from districts at their destination. Can only be built on an adjacent Mountain tile. Cannot be pillaged or removed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Mali-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_MALI_NAME">
			<Text>Mali</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_MALI_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Malian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_MALI_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Mali Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_MALI_GOLD_DESERT_NAME">
			<Text>Songs of the Jeli</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_MALI_GOLD_DESERT_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>City Centers gain +1 [ICON_FAITH] Faith and +1 [ICON_FOOD] for every adjacent Desert and Desert Hills tiles. Mines receive -1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production and +4 [ICON_GOLD] Gold. May purchase Commercial Hub district buildings with [ICON_Faith] Faith. -30% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production toward constructing buildings or training units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_MANSA_MUSA_NAME">
			<Text>Mansa Musa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SAHEL_MERCHANTS_NAME">
			<Text>Sahel Merchants</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SAHEL_MERCHANTS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>International [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes gain +1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold for every flat Desert tile in the origin city. Receive +1 [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Capacity every time you enter a Golden Age.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_SUGUBA_NAME">
			<Text>Suguba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_SUGUBA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A district unique to Mali specializing in finance and trade that replaces the Commercial Hub. Units, Buildings, and Districts are 20% cheaper to purchase with [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_FAITH] Faith in this City.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+2 [ICON_Gold] Gold bonus for each adjacent Holy Site. +2 [ICON_Gold] Gold bonus from a tile containing a River edge. +1 [ICON_Gold] Gold bonus for every two adjacent district tiles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_MALI_MANDEKALU_CAVALRY_NAME">
			<Text>Mandekalu Cavalry</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_MALI_MANDEKALU_CAVALRY_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Mali unique Medieval Era unit that replaces the Knight. Trader units are immune to being plundered if they are within 4 tiles of a Mandekalu Cavalry and on a land tile. Combat victories provide [ICON_GOLD] Gold equal to 100% that unit's base [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Maori-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_MAORI_NAME">
			<Text>Māori</Text>
			<Gender>Masculine:the</Gender>
			<Plurality>2</Plurality>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_MAORI_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Māori</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_MAORI_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Māori Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_MAORI_MANA_NAME">
			<Text>Mana</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_MAORI_MANA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Begin the game with the Sailing and Shipbuilding technologies unlocked and with the ability to enter Ocean tiles. Embarked units gain +2 [ICON_Movement] Movement. Unimproved Woods and Rainforest are +1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production. Additional +1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production from Mercantilism and +2 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production from Conservation. Fishing Boats provide +1 [ICON_FOOD] Food and a Culture Bomb to adjacent tiles. Resources cannot be harvested. [ICON_GreatWriter] Great Writers cannot be earned.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_KUPE_NAME">
			<Text>Kupe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_KUPES_VOYAGE_NAME">
			<Text>Kupe's Voyage</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_KUPES_VOYAGE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Begin the game in an Ocean tile. Gain a free Builder and +1 [ICON_Citizen] Population when settling your first city. The Palace receives +3 [ICON_HOUSING] Housing and +1 [ICON_AMENITIES] Amenity. +2 [ICON_SCIENCE] Science and +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture per turn before you settle your first city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_MARAE_NAME">
			<Text>Marae</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_MARAE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A building unique to the Māori. +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture and [ICON_FAITH] Faith to all of this city's tiles with a passable feature or natural wonder. After Flight is researched receive +1 [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism to all of this city's tiles with a feature or natural wonder. Costs no maintenance. Has no Great Work slots.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_MAORI_TOA_NAME">
			<Text>Toa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_MAORI_TOA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Māori unique Classical era melee unit. Adjacent enemy units receive -5 [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength. Can build the unique Pā improvement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_NAME">
			<Text>Pā</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MAORI_PA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unlocks the Toa ability to construct a Pā, unique to Māori.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Occupying unit receives +4 [ICON_Strength] Defense Strength, and automatically gains 2 turns of fortification. A Māori unit occupying a Pā heals even if they just moved or attacked. Must be built on a Hill tile.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Netherlands-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_GROTE_RIVIEREN_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Major adjacency bonus for Campuses, Theater Squares, and Industrial Zones if next to a river. Culture Bomb adjacent tiles when completing a Harbor. +50% [ICON_Production] Production toward the Dam district and Flood Barrier building.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Ottomans-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_OTTOMAN_NAME">
			<Text>Ottomans</Text>
			<Gender>Masculine:the</Gender>
			<Plurality>2</Plurality>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_OTTOMAN_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Ottoman</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_OTTOMAN_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Ottoman Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_GREAT_TURKISH_BOMBARD_NAME">
			<Text>Great Turkish Bombard</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_GREAT_TURKISH_BOMBARD_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>+50% [ICON_Production] Production toward siege units. All siege units gain +5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength against district defenses. Conquered cities do not lose [ICON_Citizen] Population. Cities not founded by the Ottomans gain +1 [ICON_AMENITIES] Amenity and +4 Loyalty per turn.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_SULEIMAN_NAME">
			<Text>Suleiman</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_GRAND_BAZAAR_NAME">
			<Text>Grand Bazaar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_GRAND_BAZAAR_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A building unique to the Ottomans. Accumulate 1 extra Strategic resource for every different type of Strategic resource this city has improved. Receive 1 [ICON_AMENITIES] Amenity for every Luxury resource this city has improved.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_OTTOMAN_BARBARY_CORSAIR_NAME">
			<Text>Barbary Corsair</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_OTTOMAN_BARBARY_CORSAIR_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Ottoman unique Medieval era naval unit that replaces the Privateer. It costs no [ICON_Movement] Movement to coastal raid. Can only be seen by other Naval Raiders unless adjacent to it. Reveals Naval Raiders within sight range.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_SULEIMAN_JANISSARY_NAME">
			<Text>Janissary</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_SULEIMAN_JANISSARY_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Ottoman unique Renaissance Era unit that replaces the Musketman. Starts with a free promotion. Stronger and cheaper than the Musketman. To train a Janissary a city must have a population of at least 2. If a city is founded by the Ottomans and trains a Janissary it loses a population.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SULEIMAN_GOVERNOR_NAME">
			<Text>Grand Vizier</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SULEIMAN_GOVERNOR_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Exclusive unique Governor with military and diplomatic abilities. Gain the Janissary unique unit when the Gunpowder technology is researched.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Phoenicia-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_PHOENICIA_NAME">
			<Text>Phoenicia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_PHOENICIA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Phoenician</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_PHOENICIA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Phoenician Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_MEDITERRANEAN_COLONIES_NAME">
			<Text>Mediterranean Colonies</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_MEDITERRANEAN_COLONIES_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Begin the game with the Writing technology [ICON_TechBoosted] Eureka. Coastal cities founded by Phoenicia and located on the same continent as the Phoenician [ICON_Capital] Capital are 100% Loyal. Settlers gain +2 [ICON_Movement] Movement and +2 sight range while embarked. Settlers ignore additional [ICON_Movement] Movement costs from embarking and disembarking.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_DIDO_NAME">
			<Text>Dido</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_FOUNDER_CARTHAGE_NAME">
			<Text>Founder of Carthage</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_FOUNDER_CARTHAGE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Can move their original [ICON_Capital] Capital to any city with a Cothon they founded by completing a unique project in that city. +1 [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Route capacity for each Government Plaza building and the Government Plaza district. +50% [ICON_Production] Production toward districts in the city with the Government Plaza.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_COTHON_NAME">
			<Text>Cothon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_COTHON_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A district unique to Phoenicia for naval activity in your city. Replaces the Harbor district and cheaper to build. Must be built on Coast or Lake Terrain adjacent to land.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+50% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production towards naval units and Settlers in this city. All wounded naval units in this city’s borders heal +100 HP each turn.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_PHOENICIA_BIREME_NAME">
			<Text>Bireme</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_PHOENICIA_BIREME_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Phoenician unique Ancient Era unit that replaces the Galley. Increased [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength and [ICON_Movement] Movement. Trader units are immune to being plundered if they are within 4 tiles of a Bireme and on a water tile.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--India-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_DHARMA_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Receives Follower Belief bonuses in a city from each Religion that has at least 1 Follower. Cities gain an [ICON_Amenities] Amenity for every Religion with at least 1 Follower. Missionaries have +2 spreads. +100% Religious pressure from your [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_STEPWELL_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unlocks the Builder ability to construct a Stepwell, unique to India.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+1 [ICON_Food] Food and +1 [ICON_Housing] Housing. +1 [ICON_Faith] Faith if adjacent to a Holy Site district. +1 [ICON_Food] Food if adjacent to a Farm. Additional [ICON_Housing] Housing, [ICON_Faith] Faith, and [ICON_Food] Food as you advance through the Technology and Civics Tree. Prevents [ICON_Food] Food loss during Drought. Cannot be built on Hills or adjacent to another Stepwell.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Japan-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_DIVINE_WIND_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Land units receive +5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength in land tiles adjacent to Coast; naval units receive +5 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength in shallow water tiles. Builds Encampment, Holy Site and Theater Square districts in half the time. Units do not receive damage from Hurricanes. Civilizations that are at war with Japan receive +100% unit damage from Hurricanes in Japanese territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_SATYAGRAHA_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>+5 [ICON_Faith] Faith and +1 [ICON_Favor] Diplomatic Favor per turn for each civilization (including India) they have met that has founded a Religion and is not currently at war. Opposing civilizations receive double the war weariness for fighting against Gandhi.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_ELECTRONICS_FACTORY_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A building unique to Japan. Provides +4 [ICON_Culture] Culture to this city after researching the Electricity technology. Its [ICON_Production] Production bonus is extended to all City Centers within 6 tiles that do not already have a bonus from this building type.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Qin-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_FIRST_EMPEROR_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>When building Ancient and Classical wonders you may spend Builder charges to complete 15% of the original wonder cost. Builders receive an additional charge. Canals are unlocked with the Masonry technology.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Rome-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_BATH_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A district unique to Rome for city growth. Replaces the Aqueduct district and cheaper to build.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It provides this city with a source of fresh water from an adjacent River, Lake, Oasis, or Mountain. Cities that do not yet have existing fresh water receive up to 6 [ICON_Housing] Housing. Cities that already have existing fresh water will instead get +2 [ICON_Housing] Housing. If built adjacent to a Geothermal Fissure +1 [ICON_Amenities] Amenity. In all cases the Bath provides an additional bonus of +2 [ICON_Housing] Housing and +1 [ICON_Amenities] Amenity. Prevents [ICON_Food] Food loss during Drought. Must be built adjacent to the City Center.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_BATH_EXPANSION2_ALT_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A district unique to Rome for city growth. Replaces the Aqueduct district and cheaper to build.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It provides this city with a source of fresh water from an adjacent River, Lake, Oasis, or Mountain. Cities that do not yet have existing fresh water receive up to 6 [ICON_Housing] Housing. Cities that already have existing fresh water will instead get +2 [ICON_Housing] Housing. If built adjacent to a Geothermal Fissure +1 [ICON_Amenities] Amenity. In all cases the Bath provides an additional bonus of +2 [ICON_Housing] Housing and +1 [ICON_Amenities] Amenity. Prevents [ICON_Food] Food loss during Drought. Must be built adjacent to the City Center. Military Engineers can spend a charge to complete 20% of a Bath's production.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Russia-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_MOTHER_RUSSIA_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Extra territory upon founding cities. +1 [ICON_Faith] Faith and +1 [ICON_Production] Production from Tundra. Units do not receive damage from Blizzards. Civilizations that are at war with Russia receive +100% unit damage from Blizzards in Russian territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Sweden-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_SWEDEN_NAME">
			<Text>Sweden</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_SWEDEN_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Swedish</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_SWEDEN_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Swedish Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_NOBEL_PRIZE_NAME">
			<Text>Nobel Prize</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_NOBEL_PRIZE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Sweden gains 50 [ICON_Favor] Diplomatic Favor when earning a Great Person (on Standard Speed). Sweden receives +1 [ICON_GreatEngineer] Great Engineer point from Factories and +1 [ICON_GreatScientist] Great Scientist point from Universities. Having Sweden in the game adds three unique World Congress competitions starting in the Industrial Era.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_KRISTINA_NAME">
			<Text>Kristina</Text>
		</Row>.
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_KRISTINA_AUTO_THEME_NAME">
			<Text>Minerva of the North</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_KRISTINA_AUTO_THEME_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Buildings with at least three Great Work slots and wonders with at least two Great Work slots are automatically themed when they have all their slots filled. She may construct the Queen's Bibliotheque in the Government Plaza.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_OPEN_AIR_MUSEUM_NAME">
			<Text>Open-Air Museum</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_OPEN_AIR_MUSEUM_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unlocks the Builder ability to construct an Open-Air Museum, unique to Sweden.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Provides +2 Loyalty per turn in this city. +2 [ICON_Culture] Culture and +2 [ICON_Tourism] Tourism for each type of terrain (Snow, Tundra, Desert, Plains or Grassland) in which at least one Swedish city is founded. One per city. Tiles with Open-Air Museums cannot be swapped.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_QUEENS_BIBLIOTHEQUE_NAME">
			<Text>Queen's Bibliotheque</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_QUEENS_BIBLIOTHEQUE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A building unique to Sweden. This building provides 2 slots of [ICON_GreatWork_WRITING] Writing, [ICON_GreatWork_MUSIC] Music, and any type of [ICON_GreatWork_Landscape] Art.[NEWLINE]Awards +1 [Icon_Governor] Governor Title.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_SWEDEN_CAROLEAN_NAME">
			<Text>Carolean</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_SWEDEN_CAROLEAN_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Swedish unique Renaissance Era unit that replaces the Pike and Shot. Faster than the Pike and Shot. +3 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength per unused [ICON_Movement] Movement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_ERA_FUTURE_NAME">
			<Text>Future Era</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_ERA_FUTURE_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>The world contains marvels beyond the dreams of ancient prophets, and terrors more fearsome than any apocalypse. Machines search for meaning and new matter weaves dream-like forms. Choices made long ago bear grave consequences in this age and demand resolute answers. Go now, and achieve your vision for the future of civilization.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_VICTORY_SCIENCE_TT_XP2">
			<Text>Be the first to complete the Exoplanet Expedition to another star system to win a Science victory. This victory is straight-forward, but can be difficult to achieve before time runs out.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Configuration Changes that are Shared between XP1 and XP2. -->
		<!-- District Config Text -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_WATER_STREET_CARNIVAL_EXPANSION2_NAME">
			<Text>Copacabana</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_WATER_STREET_CARNIVAL_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A district unique to Brazil. Replaces the Water Park district, and provides +2 [ICON_Amenities] Amenities. Also unlocks the Carnival project, which grants an additional +1 [ICON_Amenities] Amenity when underway and a variety of [ICON_GreatPerson] Great People points once completed. Cannot be built in a city with a Street Carnival. Cannot be built on Reef.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_STREET_CARNIVAL_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A district unique to Brazil. Replaces the Entertainment Complex district, and provides +2 [ICON_Amenities] Amenities. Also unlocks the Carnival project, which grants an additional +1 [ICON_Amenities] Amenity when underway and a variety of [ICON_GreatPerson] Great People points once completed. Cannot be built in a city with a Copacabana.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- China -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_GREAT_WALL_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unlocks the Builder ability to construct the Great Wall, unique to China.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+2 [ICON_GOLD] Gold. Provides an increase to [ICON_Strength] Defense. Bonus to [ICON_Gold] Gold if adjacent to other segments. Additional [ICON_Culture] Culture and [ICON_Tourism] Tourism as you advance through the Technology Tree for adjacent segments. Must be built in a line along the borders of your empire. Can only be pillaged (never destroyed) by natural disasters.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_DYNASTIC_CYCLE_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>[ICON_TechBoosted] Eurekas and [ICON_CivicBoosted] Inspirations provide 50% of civics and technologies instead of 40%.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Cleopatra -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_MEDITERRANEAN_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Your [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes to other civilizations provide +4 [ICON_Gold] Gold for Egypt. Other civilizations' [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes to Egypt provide +2 [ICON_Food] Food for them and +2 [ICON_Gold] Gold for Egypt. Trading with Allies earns twice as many bonus Alliance Points.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_SPHINX_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unlocks the Builder ability to construct a Sphinx, unique to Egypt.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+1 [ICON_Faith] Faith and +1 [ICON_Culture] Culture. +2 Appeal. +2 [ICON_Faith] Faith if next to a wonder. +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture if built on Floodplains. Additional [ICON_CULTURE] Culture once Natural History is discovered. Provides [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism after researching Flight. Cannot be built next to another Sphinx. Cannot be built on Snow or Snow Hills.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_EGYPTIAN_CHARIOT_ARCHER_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Egyptian unique Ancient era ranged unit. 4 [ICON_Movement] Movement when starting in open terrain.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- England -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_ROYAL_NAVY_DOCKYARD_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A district unique to England for naval activity in your city. Replaces the Harbor district. Also removes the [ICON_Movement] Movement penalty for embarking and disembarking to and from this tile. Must be built on Coast or Lake Terrain adjacent to land.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+1 [ICON_Movement] Movement for all naval units built in Dockyard[NEWLINE]+2 [ICON_Gold] Gold and +4 Loyalty per turn when built on a foreign continent. Cannot be built on Reef</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- France -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_CHATEAU_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unlocks the Builder ability to construct a Chateau, unique to France.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+2 [ICON_Culture] Culture. +1 Appeal. +1 [ICON_Culture] Culture for every adjacent wonder (becomes +2 after researching Flight). +1 [ICON_Gold] Gold for every adjacent Luxury resource. Provides [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism after researching Flight. Can only be built adjacent to Rivers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Gilgamesh-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_ADVENTURES_ENKIDU_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>When at war with a common foe, they and their allies share pillage rewards and share combat experience gains if within 5 tiles. Their Alliances gain Alliance Points for being at war with a common foe.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Mongolia -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_ORDU_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A building unique to Mongolia. Grants an ability that gives +1 [ICON_MOVEMENT] Movement to Heavy and Light Cavalry trained in this city. +25% combat experience for all cavalry class units trained in this city.[NEWLINE]Strategic Resource Stockpiles increased +10 (on Standard Speed).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]May not be built in an Encampment district that already has a Barracks.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Norway -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_THUNDERBOLT_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Allows coastal raiding for all naval melee units and +50% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production toward all naval melee units. Receive [ICON_SCIENCE] Science from pillaging and coastal raiding Mines in addition to [ICON_GOLD] Gold. Pillaging or coastal raiding Quarries, Pastures, Plantations, and Camps provide [ICON_CULTURE] Culture in addition to [ICON_FAITH] Faith. Gain the Viking Longship unique unit with Sailing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spain -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_TREASURE_FLEET_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>May form Fleets and Armadas earlier than usual (Mercantilism). [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes between multiple continents receive bonus [ICON_Gold] Gold for routes to other civilizations, and bonus [ICON_Food] Food and [ICON_Production] Production for routes between your own cities. +2 Loyalty per turn for cities with a Mission improvement adjacent to the City Center and not on your original [ICON_Capital] Capital's continent.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_EL_ESCORIAL_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Inquisitors can Remove Heresy one extra time. Inquisitors eliminate 100% of the presence of other Religions. Combat units have a bonus of +4 [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength against players following other Religions.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_MISSION_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unlocks the Builder ability to construct a Mission, unique to Spain.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+2 [ICON_Faith] Faith. +2 [ICON_Faith] Faith, +1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production, and +1 [ICON_FOod] Food if on a different continent than your [ICON_Capital] Capital. +1 [ICON_Science] Science for every adjacent Campus and Holy Site district. Additional [ICON_SCIENCE] Science once Cultural Heritage is discovered.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Germany-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_HANSA_EXPANSION2_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>A district unique to Germany for industrial activity. Replaces the Industrial Zone district and cheaper to build.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+ 2[ICON_Production] Production bonus for each adjacent Commercial Hub, Aqueduct, Canal, and Dam districts. +1 [ICON_Production] Production bonus for each adjacent resource. +1 [ICON_Production] Production bonus for every two adjacent district tiles.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
