<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<!-- Natural Wonders -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_FEATURE_CHOCOLATEHILLS_QUOTE">
			<Text>“The wicked king pursued the lovers Juan and Maria on his swiftest horse. As he overtook them, Maria flung down her ring, and at once rose up seven tall hills, and the king was slowed.”[NEWLINE] - Filipino Folk Tale</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_FEATURE_DEVILSTOWER_QUOTE">
			<Text>“Seven girls were chased by bears. The bears were just about to catch them when the girls jumped on a low rock. One of the girls prayed to the rock, "Rock take pity on us, rock save us!" The rock heard them and began to grow upwards, pushing the girls higher and higher.”[NEWLINE] - Kiowa Legend</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_FEATURE_GOBUSTAN_QUOTE">
			<Text>“Then weave the web of the mystic measure;[NEWLINE]From the depths of the sky and the ends of the earth,[NEWLINE]Come, swift Spirits of might and of pleasure,[NEWLINE]Fill the dance and the music of mirth.”[NEWLINE] - Percy Bysshe Shelley</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_FEATURE_IKKIL_QUOTE">
			<Text>“Son, have you seen the rain of God? It passed and entered beneath the mountains of God... There will be a ring in the sky where the water of God has passed.”[NEWLINE] - Books of Chilam Balam</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_FEATURE_PAMUKKALE_QUOTE">
			<Text>“Near the Mesogis, opposite Laodicea, is Hierapolis, where are hot springs, and the Plutonium, both of which have some singular properties. The water of the springs is so easily consolidated and becomes stone, that if it is conducted through water-courses dams are formed consisting of a single piece of stone.”[NEWLINE] - Strabo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_FEATURE_VESUVIUS_QUOTE">
			<Text>“The sea seemed to roll back upon itself, and to be driven from its banks by the convulsive motion of the earth; it is certain at least the shore was considerably enlarged, and several sea animals were left upon it. On the other side, a black and dreadful cloud, broken with rapid, zigzag flashes, revealed behind it variously shaped masses of flame...”[NEWLINE] - Pliny the Younger</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_FEATURE_WHITEDESERT_QUOTE">
			<Text>“I have filled a water-bag from my people and gone to the desert,[NEWLINE]And walked empty wastes while the wolf howled, like a gambler whose family starves.”[NEWLINE] - Imru-ul-Quais</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Technologies -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_BUTTRESS_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“An architect should live as little in cities as a painter. Send him to our hills, and let him study there what nature understands by a buttress, and what by a dome.”[NEWLINE] – John Ruskin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_BUTTRESS_QUOTE_2">
			<Text>“Him that overcometh will I make a pillar in the temple of my God, and he shall go no more out.”[NEWLINE] – Revelation 3:12</Text>
		</Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TECH_REFINING_QUOTE_1">
      <Text>"Engineering is the art of directing the great sources of power in nature for the use and convenience of man."[NEWLINE] - Thomas Tredgold</Text>
    </Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_SEASTEADS_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“I must go down to the seas again, to the vagrant gypsy life, To the gull’s way and the whale’s way where the wind’s like a whetted knife;”[NEWLINE] – John Masefield</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_SEASTEADS_QUOTE_2">
			<Text>“Then you drive out where the storm-clouds swallow, And the sound of your oar-blades, falling hollow, As all we have left through the months to follow.”[NEWLINE] – Rudyard Kipling</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_ADVANCED_AI_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“Will no entreaties cause thee to turn a favourable eye upon thy creature, who implores thy goodness and compassion?”[NEWLINE] – Mary Shelley</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_ADVANCED_POWER_CELLS_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“The incomplete becomes complete; the crooked becomes straight; the empty becomes full; the worn out becomes new.”[NEWLINE] - Tao Te Ching, Lao Tzu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_CYBERNETICS_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“If there is any work in the afterlife, you must do it. Behold me whenever you are called. Be watchful at any moment to work there. Plough my fields, carry water and sand to the east and west. Behold me whenever you are called.”[NEWLINE] – Inscription on an Egyptian Ushabti</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_SMART_MATERIALS_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“It ascends from the earth to the heaven, and it again descends to the earth and receives the force of things superior and inferior.”[NEWLINE] – Hermes Trismegistus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_PREDICTIVE_SYSTEMS_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“If the enemy know not where he will be attacked, he must prepare in every quarter, and so be everywhere weak.”[NEWLINE] – Sun Tzu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_OFFWORLD_MISSION_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“No, my friends, we have not fallen back upon the earth; no, nor are we submerged in the Gulf of Mexico. Yes! we are mounting into space. See those stars shining in the night, and that impenetrable darkness heaped up between the earth and us!”[NEWLINE] – Jules Verne</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TECH_OFFWORLD_MISSION_QUOTE_2">
			<Text>“After eleven Days Passage in this violent Flight, I perceived we began to approach another Earth (if I may so call it) being the Globe or very Body of that Star which we call the Moon.”[NEWLINE] – Francis Godwin</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Civics -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_DIGITAL_DEMOCRACY_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“Multitudes, multitudes in the valley of decision: for the day of the Lord is near in the valley of decision.”[NEWLINE] – Joel 3:14</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_SYNTHETIC_TECHNOCRACY_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“We find every where men of mechanical genius, of great general acuteness, and discriminative understanding, who make no scruple in pronouncing the Automaton a pure machine, unconnected with human agency in its movements, and consequently, beyond all comparison, the most astonishing of the inventions of mankind.”[NEWLINE] – Edgar Allen Poe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_CORPORATE_LIBERTARIANISM_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“Over himself, over his own body and mind, the individual is sovereign.”[NEWLINE] – John Stuart Mill</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_NEAR_FUTURE_GOVERNANCE_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“Justice is the bond of men in states, for the administration of justice, which is the determination of what is just, is the principle of order in political society.”[NEWLINE] – Aristotle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_EXODUS_IMPERATIVE_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“This, O Best Beloved, is another story of the High and Far Off Times.”[NEWLINE] – Rudyard Kipling</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_CULTURAL_HEGEMONY_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“Ah, my Belovéd, fill the cup that clears[NEWLINE]To-day of past Regrets and future Fears—[NEWLINE]To-morrow?—Why, To-morrow I may be[NEWLINE]Myself with Yesterday’s Sev’n Thousand Years.”[NEWLINE] – Edward FitzGerald</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_INFORMATION_WARFARE_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“It has been said aforetime that he who knows both sides has nothing to fear in a hundred fights...”[NEWLINE] – Sun Tzu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_INFORMATION_WARFARE_QUOTE_2">
			<Text>“If the enemy know not where he will be attacked, he must prepare in every quarter, and so be everywhere weak.”[NEWLINE] – Sun Tzu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_GLOBAL_WARMING_MITIGATION_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“Fetter this malefactor to the jagged rocks[NEWLINE]In adamantine bonds infrangible.”[NEWLINE] – Aeschylus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_SMART_POWER_DOCTRINE_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>“The time will come and is inevitably coming when all institutions based on force will disappear through their uselessness, stupidity, and even inconvenience becoming obvious to all.”[NEWLINE] – Leo Tolstoy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVIC_ENVIRONMENTALISM_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>"I shall return again to the light of the sun, to prepare a home for thy descendants."[NEWLINE] –Argonautica, Apollonius Rhodius</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- World Wonders -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_GOLDEN_GATE_BRIDGE_QUOTE">
			<Text>“The golden gates of Sleep unbar[NEWLINE]Where Strength and Beauty, met together,[NEWLINE]Kindle their image like a star[NEWLINE]In a sea of glassy weather!”[NEWLINE] - Percy Bysshe Shelley</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_GREAT_BATH_QUOTE">
			<Text>“Yet in this captious and intenible sieve[NEWLINE]I still pour in the waters of my love[NEWLINE]And lack not to lose still: thus, Indian-like,[NEWLINE]Religious in mine error, I adore[NEWLINE]The sun, that looks upon his worshipper,[NEWLINE]But knows of him no more.”[NEWLINE] - William Shakespeare</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_MACHU_PICCHU_QUOTE">
			<Text>“...Eagles fly, The turrets round, and seem to flout the sky;[NEWLINE]They eye those walls now crumbling in decay,[NEWLINE]And scare from quiet rest their destined prey.”[NEWLINE] - Samuel Prout Hill</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_MEENAKSHI_TEMPLE_QUOTE">
			<Text>“We greet you, Devi Meenakshi, she who shines like a thousand-million suns, adorned with bracelets and garlands... She who is auspicious, she who embodies existence. I always bow to you, whose compassion is an ocean.”[NEWLINE] - Adi Shankara</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_ORSZAGHAZ_QUOTE">
			<Text>“With self-government is freedom, and with freedom is justice and patriotism.”[NEWLINE] - Lajos Kossuth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_PANAMA_CANAL_QUOTE">
			<Text>“Therefore will not we fear, though the earth be removed, and though the mountains be carried into the midst of the sea; Though the waters thereof roar and be troubled, though the mountains shake with the swelling thereof.”[NEWLINE] - Psalms 46:2-3</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_UNIVERSITY_SANKORE_QUOTE">
			<Text>“Scholars are the heirs of the prophets, for the prophets did not leave behind a legacy of wealth but that of knowledge.”[NEWLINE] - Musnad al-Bazzar 10/68</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
