<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Ed Beach (Firaxis Games) -->
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FIRST_TIME_MEGADISASTERS">
      <Text>Our world has turned against us! With Apocalypse Mode enabled, droughts, storms, floods, and volcanic eruptions are more frequent and more dangerous.  Luckily, you can train a Soothsayer who might be able to turn these calamities onto your enemies. Keep an eye on the climate; with a final temperature increase, the world will enter the Apocalypse, and disasters will strike every turn!</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_FOREST_FIRES">
      <Text>Lightning or human error has sparked a forest fire! The flames will spread to any adjacent forest or jungle. While the smoke will cause us some trouble, the ash will provide good fertilizer. After the flames die down, of course.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_METEOR_SHOWERS">
      <Text>Meteors have fallen from the sky! Let's see what they've brought with them. </Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_COMET_IMPACT">
      <Text>A comet has struck the Earth! Comet strikes destroy anything that they hit.[NEWLINE]‘From the very beginning nothing at all has lasted.’</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOLAR_FLARES">
      <Text>The world is experiencing a solar flare, damaging all of our electrical equipment. Our power-generating buildings and improvements, and even our electricity-using units have been damaged!</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_SOOTHSAYERS">
      <Text>Soothsayers are now available to us through Faith. Soothsayers may call disasters onto your enemies. Through competing with other civilizations, you can increase their power by sacrificing your combat units to volcanoes.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TUTORIAL_APOCALYPSE">
      <Text>The world is ending! Disasters are beginning on a scale that we have never seen before! Rush to victory before you are destroyed!</Text>
    </Row>
  </EnglishText>
</GameData>
