<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<!-- civs -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_MAYA_LOCATION">
			<Text>Central America, including parts of present-day Mexico, Guatemala, Honduras, Belize, and El Salvador.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_MAYA_SIZE">
			<Text>120,000 square miles at its peak (about 200 thousand square km). For comparison, this is about twice the size of medieval England.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_MAYA_POPULATION">
			<Text>Generally assumed to be about 5 million at its height, but new archaeological discoveries suggest that the real number might be closer to 10 or 15 million. There are about 5 million present-day Maya speakers. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_MAYA_CAPITAL">
			<Text>Never unified into one empire, the Maya had a series of important cities, including Tikal, Caracol, Mayapan, Calakmul, and, later, Chichen Itza.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The early Mayas rose in the Yucatán Peninsula and established city-states between 2000 BC and 250 AD. These city-states were governed and ruled by divinely-blessed rulers, and ranged from both small settlements to metropolises, such as the city-state known today as El Mirador. The city-states were never united politically in the same way as other Mesoamerican cultures, but they still shared a common language and culture. They competed with as much as they relied on each other for growth and the projection of power.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The Mayas chose a unique (and rather brave) place to settle. The Yucatán Peninsula wasn’t good for the kind of agriculture that most other civilizations practiced. Rather than settling around river valleys, the Maya built in tropical rainforests, with thin soil atop limestone foundations. A lack of a river meant that transportation was difficult, and finding drinking water problematic. But adversity can often lead to innovation. Where the water was too saline, the early Maya learned how to filter water through the limestone to make it drinkable, and where the jungle was too dense, they created raised earthen mounds on which to grow crops. One of the most important developments the Maya made was the creation of their written language, which consisted of glyphs.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Maya glyphs were designed to fit within individual blocks and read almost like comic panels, going left, right, then down below the first left one, and so on. These glyphs were a mixture of pictographic and phonetic characters, rather like modern-day Japanese.  The Maya were avid record keepers, and their script remained in use up until the arrival of the Europeans in Mesoamerica.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>While most of their books (codices made of tree-bark) were burned during the Spanish conquest, their monuments, or “stelae,” survive. As the Maya dated their stelae with their Long Count calendar, we can use them to identify historical dates from quite far back.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>By 250 AD, the Maya began strengthening their power in major cities such as Calakmul, Palenque, Tikal, Bonampak, Kaminaljuyu, and Copán. In this era, there were over 40 Maya cities, with populations between 5,000 and 50,000 people. As these cities grew, the Maya thrived. They built ball courts for popular games, constructed massive pyramids (which grew ever more massive thanks to the Maya’s layered building methods), and educated a scholarly elite.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>Maya pyramids were created differently from Egyptian ones. Rather than using only bricks, they started with a base foundation of limestone and mortar. They then covered this with plaster, which was then painted. Any time they wanted to make improvements, they simply had to throw on some more limestone, cover it again, and paint it. There was no need for lengthy, complicated renovations, and they didn’t have to worry about structural issues. These pyramids were usually places of worship. These temples, known as “k’uh nah’, had multiple rooms, each dedicated to a deity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>Maya cities were sprawling and made up of these temples, palaces, and ball courts, all of which were set around central plazas. The cities could have multiple plazas and then the other structures grew outward from them. Art frescos and sculptures adorned the wealthier areas. Art was created for the royal court, or at least, created to be about them. Art was also used to commemorate important moments in their history. Recent advances in radar technology has revealed the extent of these cities; whereas before archaeologists assumed that the Maya were a largely dispersed people, coming together only at temple complexes, new studies have revealed strikingly large settlements, sprawled out over the jungle.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>Maya life wasn’t all monuments, math, sports, and science. Military campaigns were frequent, whether it be to establish rule, to take control over trade routes, or to send a message to an enemy city-state. Combat and the subsequent battles were important enough to be memorialized and glorified in art and hieroglyphic engravings. To be a good ruler, a Maya also had to be a good warrior. They were expected to lead battles and be good tacticians. The kings and societal elites who were defeated were captured and subsequently sacrificed. Such sacrifices were rare, though, and for the most part, the Maya focused on other kinds of sacrifices: drops of blood on paper burned as an offering, for instance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9">
			<Text>By the 900s, the Maya declined in both power and population, and some cities were entirely abandoned. But this decline turned out to be just another revolution in the cycle of rise and fall, and, by the 1100s, new cities were forming, particularly along the Caribbean and Gulf coast.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10">
			<Text>One of the most powerful of these cities, Mayapan, was, when the Spanish arrived by accident (literally – they were shipwrecked) in 1511, in yet another state of collapse. Following the first contact, the Spanish sent three more expeditions to the Yucatán and took over the Aztec capital in Tenochtitlan in 1521. From there, they turned south to modern-day Guatemala and began their conquest of Central America. By 1697, the Spanish defeated the last Maya city, Nojpeté.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_11">
			<Text>Although the Maya cities were gone and the Spanish tried to erase elements of the Maya culture, the Maya continued to persist in small villages, where they maintained their traditional life. Even after the conquest, some of these practices continued, especially food culture and crafts. Today, the Maya are still around, and the language, tzolk’in ritual calendar, and other elements of Maya society thrive.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_GRAN_COLOMBIA_LOCATION">
			<Text>South and Central America.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_GRAN_COLOMBIA_SIZE">
			<Text>973 thousand square miles (2.5 million square km).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_GRAN_COLOMBIA_POPULATION">
			<Text>2.5 million</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_GRAN_COLOMBIA_CAPITAL">
			<Text>Bogotá</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_GRAN_COLOMBIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Gran Colombia rose like a flame in southern Central America and northern South America—burning bright and fast. For twelve years, it represented a unified nation established to proclaim independence against European rule.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_GRAN_COLOMBIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Following Simón Bolívar’s triumph during the Colombian and Venezuelan wars of independence, the victors quickly worked to establish a government. But there was disagreement on multiple fronts – Bolívar’s group favored one unified Gran Colombia ruled under a central government, while others sought independence for Venezuela and Ecuador. Bolívar also favored a strong authoritarian government, with a hereditary Senate, whereas others (Bolívar’s general Santander, especially) sought the rule of law over personality instead. Gran Colombia, at least at the start, followed Bolívar’s vision, and the new country had a centralized government with distinct judicial, legislative, and executive branches.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_GRAN_COLOMBIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>On December 17, 1819, the Republic of Colombia was established (“Gran Colombia” is the name used by modern historians to avoid confusion with the present-day nation of Colombia). But Spanish troops were still present, and it took Bolívar until 1822 to finally declare an end to the war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_GRAN_COLOMBIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>But the Republic did not rest easy. In addition to the ideological differences between Bolívar and Santander – reflecting the larger tensions between rule focused on the personal charisma of the Liberator versus a rule by the Constitution, there were regional divisions. In 1826, José Antonio Páez, the famed cavalry leader, led a rebellion against Bolívar, demanding a free Venezuela. Bolívar’s attempts to mollify Páez further irritated Santander, and deepened the new country’s fault lines.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_GRAN_COLOMBIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>Further unrest led to Bolívar proposing a presidency for life in 1828, a move that led Santander to adopt a radically federalist Constitution in opposition. It was also a move that led to an assassination attempt upon Bolívar later that year.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_GRAN_COLOMBIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>Unable to hold itself together politically or regionally, Gran Colombia began to decline. By 1830, Bolívar was forced to resign due to increasing unpopularity and his worsening health, despite attempts by General Rafael Urdaneta and other pro- Bolívar elements to try and convince Bolívar to return. Gran Colombia collapsed in 1831, ultimately dissolving into independent states. Between 1830 and 1831, three separate presidents tried to save Gran Colombia from disestablishment.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_GRAN_COLOMBIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>But Spain never did come back. After Gran Colombia, the states that formed are largely those that remain today: Colombia, Venezuela, Panama, Ecuador, and Guyana.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- leaders -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_TITLE">
			<Text>Lady Six Sky</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_QUOTE">
			<Text>I am Lady Six Sky, a warrior standing above my defeated foes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Ancient chroniclers talk about a woman who ruled as a king in Dos Pilas. She claimed the titles of male rulers and proved to be a vocal and powerful leader. Even though the chroniclers of the day never said her name, the reputation of the Lady of Dos Pilas nevertheless lived on.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Lady Six Sky, also known as Wak Chan Ahau, followed in the footsteps of her father B’alaj Chan K’awiil to become ruler of Dos Pilas. After assuming the throne in the late 600s, Lady Six Sky left her home of Dos Pilas and journeyed to Wak Kab’nal. It’s never easy being king (especially as a woman), and Lady Six Sky needed to further solidify her power across the region and in Wak Kab’nal in particular. To prove her authority both as the blood ruler and through divine choice, she performed several rituals shortly after her arrival. She was, for the most part, well received by the people, and her authority was ultimately respected, although she never fully ascended as the crowned ruler of Naranjo. Nevertheless, her people erected monuments in her name to show that they respected her rule with or without a crown. She was featured wearing the garbs of the true royal she was (which may have been a bit of an unintentional slap to the face, but presumably she accepted this gift with grace).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Lady Six Sky’s son , K’ahk Tiliw Chan Chaak (or Smoking Squirrel as his friends knew him) assumed the throne at the age of five, but Lady Six Sky continued to rule in his stead (he was a little busy being a child). Like any good mother, she led several successful military campaigns during this time against nearby polities that challenged her son’s—and by extension her—rule. Her monuments shifted to depict her as a warrior standing over her enemies, poised and triumphant. By the time her son was ten years old, she’d already carried out a number of successful campaigns in his name.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>War and conquest was not the only thing that Lady Six Sky tackled during her reign as queen and regent. She also helped to perform the religious ceremonies expected of someone from her station. One, the mid-katun, she did in the same way as the previous king of Wak Kab’nal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>Lady Six Sky was determined to establish a new dynasty with her as the matriarch. This meant not only continuing to strengthen her rule through war and religious example, but also by further advancing the prosperity of her people. This was absolutely necessary if Lady Six Sky wanted to hold her power as a woman and the mother of a very young, and thus vulnerable, king. She planned to not just be there for a good time, but also for a long time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>When Lady Six Sky’s son Smoking Squirrel finally took over, he followed his mother’s legacy and continued to lead military campaigns against other, larger Maya cities, including Tikal. Lady Six Sky remained by Smoking Squirrel’s side during this time and acted as his co-ruler. The people and the nobility of Wak Kab’nal respected Lady Six Sky and Smoking Squirrel’s joint rule thanks to their consistent, unified actions and policies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>To Lady Six Sky’s and her people’s dismay, Smoking Squirrel had a short rule. He died early, leaving Lady Six Sky to lead once again until her grandson was old enough—or powerful enough—to ascend.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>Lady Six Sky lived for another twenty years before she passed in 741 AD. Her grandson was defeated by Tikal, captured, and unfortunately executed, ending the dynasty she worked so hard to build.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Lady Six Sky does not rely on the traditional sources of fresh water to establish her close knit empire, instead she capitalizes on a network of Farms and Plantations to reach for the stars.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_LADY_SIX_SKY_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>The Maya plan out their settlements differently than other civilizations. They look to get their housing from Farms rather than being near Fresh Water. Settling adjacent to luxuries provides them with additional amenities as well. Lady Six Sky wants to keep her cities close to her capital. So settle an early cluster of cities and defend them strongly with your Hulche atlatlists. With properly placed Observatory districts receiving extra science from adjacent Farms and Plantations you can start to race ahead of the other civilizations in technology, rocketing your people into space or providing a significant boost toward another victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_TITLE">
			<Text>Simón Bolívar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_QUOTE">
			<Text>Generous souls always interest themselves in the fate of a people who strive to recover the rights to which the Creator and Nature have entitled them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Simón Bolívar, who later became known as the Liberator, was born to a wealthy, upper-class Venezuelan family in 1783. Although he had more than enough money to ensure what should have been a positive, bright upbringing, Bolívar’s childhood was far from perfect. His father died when he was just three years old. Six years later, his mother passed away, leaving him in the care of his uncle. Bolívar’s uncle became the administrator of his inheritance and arranged for him to have several well-educated tutors. Many of these tutors would have a lasting impact on him and the philosophies he’d carry through his life. He was educated in classical schools of thought and began to learn about the newer and rapidly evolving ones. One of his tutors, Simón Rodriguez, opened the door to the Enlightenment movement and in particular, the philosophies of Jean-Jacques Rousseau.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Bolívar’s uncle sent him to study abroad in Spain and Europe when he was sixteen. Like with most ideal European study abroad trips, Bolívar found love in Spain. Three years after arriving, he married María Teresa del Toro y Alayza, the daughter of a Spanish noble, and returned home. However, his brief time of happiness was short lived. His wife died of yellow fever before their first anniversary. Although Bolívar was unfortunately familiar with death, the loss still hit him hard and left him changed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>He returned to Europe and watched the rise of Napoleon. For a while, Bolívar admired him. However, when Bolívar returned to Venezuela, he effectively ended his friendship with Napoleon after Napoleon made Joseph Bonaparte the King of Spain and by extension, its colonies. This included Bolívar’s home of Venezuela and prompted him to join the resistance. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>In 1810, the Caracas junta declared its independence, and Bolívar was once again shipped off to Europe, both because of his diplomatic skills and apparent ease while traveling long distances. He arrived in England and remained there for a year before once more making the long voyage back to Venezuela. His homecoming was less than welcoming, and rumors spread that he and his fellow independence leader, Francisco de Miranda, were growing apart. Miranda’s subsequent arrest and Bolívar’s quick escape to Cartagena de Indias didn’t help these allegations. Even with the rumors, Bolívar took advantage of the situation. During his time away, he wrote the Manifiesto de Cartagena. In it, Bolívar continued to push for independence from Spain. His reputation grew during this time, aided by his philosophies and Miranda’s absence.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>After a new Spanish king overthrew the new Venezuelan republic, Bolívar took charge within the military of New Granada and led an invasion into Venezuela. He earned his title, El Libertador, through numerous campaigns to liberate his home. Unfortunately, Bolívar and his forces weren’t able to hold the capital of Caracas long, and his troops were pushed out of the city. Rather than allowing himself to be defeated, Bolívar gathered his allies from across South America and even Great Britain to finally, and decisively, drive out the Spanish and Royalist forces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>Following further liberations of the region, Bolívar and his allies created the Republic of Gran Colombia. Bolívar became president with Francisco de Paula Santander, a fellow military and political leader, as his vice president. His government and time as president were far from peaceful. The region was rife with unrest from the fragile state that the extended battles had left it in. Reigning over the vast Gran Colombia wasn’t an easy task, and it became more difficult after the Peruvian Congress named Bolívar dictator of Peru. Power is fickle, difficult to hold on to, and even harder to control. Regional uprisings and dissent put Bolívar on edge. To solidify his dream of a unified Gran Colombia, Bolívar called for a constitutional convention in 1828. Unfortunately, the delegates disagreed with his proposed vision of a centralist model of government complete with a "lifetime president" who could choose his successor—within reason, of course. Although he ultimately believed in a limited government, Bolívar worried about the fragility of Gran Colombia. He felt that Gran Colombia had to grow before he could apply his true ideals to it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>To try to save face with his government and the people, Bolívar declared himself dictator—which he assured everyone was a temporary measure. This act went over spectacularly with his political opponents and lead to an assassination attempt that he narrowly escaped.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>After two more years serving as the "president," Bolívar resigned. He packed up his belongings, hoping to once again journey to Europe. However, Bolívar never boarded the boat. He contracted tuberculosis, which ultimately led to his death on December 17, 1830. Before his death, Bolívar asked his aide-de-camp, General Daniel Florencio O’Leary, to dispose of all of his writings. Like his delegates during the constitutional convention, O’Leary disagreed with this order and did not burn Bolívar’s substantial works. After more than a decade following his passing, Bolívar was buried in his hometown of Caracas. A monument was erected there to celebrate him and his accomplishments.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Simón Bolívar’s units are a nimble force to be reckoned with, whether on offense or defense. With clever use of his many Comandante Generals, his army becomes nigh unstoppable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_SIMON_BOLIVAR_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>Additional movement for military units makes long marches across the plains or hills a breeze for Gran Colombia, whether patrolling their own lands or liberating hostile lands. Field promotions do not end a unit’s turn, letting them get right back into the fray. With the addition of Comandante Generals, which join with each new era, Simón Bolívar’s army is further bolstered with additional combat strength and movement. The Llaneros are best near these Comandante Generals and other Llaneros, and serve as a powerful backbone for a mid-game military force. The Hacienda will provide sustenance and production to continue the war path. Simón Bolívar is best leading Gran Colombia towards a Domination Victory, though such might can divert resources to other paths as well.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- buildings and districts -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_DISTRICTS_PAGE_DISTRICT_OBSERVATORY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The Maya, who were both intensive agriculturalists as well as consummate mathematicians, took an intense interest in the movement of the heavens. At observatories in Mayan cities such as Palenque and Chichén Itzá, Mayan astronomers used an artificial horizon – a flat, circular platform of regular size – on which they marked carefully the points at which stars, planets, the moon and sun rose and fell each year. The Mayans used these observations to create detailed calendars. We are familiar with a solar one – our 365-day calendar is based upon the length of time that it takes for the sun to complete one cycle, but many cultures also use a lunar calendar (i.e. the length of time it takes for the moon to wax and wane 12 times). The Mayans added more and more cycles to this. For instance, the planet Venus takes 584 days to return to the same spot on the rim of one of the Mayan observatories’ artificial horizons. Noticing and recording this, the Maya also developed a Venusian calendar. Finally, to these astronomical observations, the Mayans added a 260-day calendar, one that lines up with the average time from human conception to birth.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_DISTRICTS_PAGE_DISTRICT_OBSERVATORY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The function of this astronomy was astrology, religion, agriculture, and politics combined. The stars and planets (as were, at times, Mayan rulers) were Mayan gods. As calendars interlinked, different activities – planting, warfare, festivals, the fortunes of a particular leader – would become more or less auspicious. Astronomy via the observatory was, for the Mayans, a way of tracking how the natural world, the supernatural world, and the political world were interlinked. Today, astronomical observations and calendrical cycles still influence how present-day Maya practice indigenous religion and divination.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- improvements -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_BATEY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The Mesoamerican ball game, called in Mexico “ulama,” is ancient. While it was likely invented by the Olmec several thousand years ago, it became popular in the first millennium A.D., spreading beyond its Mesoamerican origins and into North America and the Caribbean. In its Mayan versions, it involved getting a rubber ball through a stone ring (perhaps representing the sun in its journeys through the underworld) without using one’s hands. The players were often war captives, and the losers could be sacrificed to the gods. Images of such sacrifices are clearly shown on the walls of the Maya ball courts at Chichén Itzá. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_BATEY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The bateyes at Caguana in Puerto Rico are no such grand affairs. Here, they are roughly rectangular, flat pitches without the stone rings that characterize Mayan courts. The rules, then, were likely different, involving throwing the ball between teams, but the link between the court and religious life remained – Caguana’s bateyes are decorated with petroglyphs (stone carvings) and are clustered around the base of a mountain that was the center of Taíno religious life in Puerto Rico.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_BATEY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>The Taíno word “batey” has had a bad afterlife in the years since colonization. While the word originally means “ball court,” it is now widely used to refer to temporary housing for workers on sugar plantations, both enslaved peoples on historical plantations and present-day workers, many of whom are still forced into involuntary labor. It is unclear how the Taíno word for ball court has come to refer to something so different; here, “batey” refers to the original meaning of the word.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_HACIENDA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Somewhere between a farm and a factory, the hacienda in Latin America was a large estate, held by a wealthy patron, that became the dominant mode of land ownership during the 19th century. Being located more inland than a plantation, and without the ready access to the sea, haciendas had to be agriculturally self-sufficient in addition to producing crops for export. In Gran Colombia, these crops could be coffee, coca, sugar, tobacco, or others.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_HACIENDA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The hacienda system was by its very nature exploitative. While the enslavement of African-descended people was more dominant in coastal plantations, the inland haciendas relied upon the dispossession of indigenous peoples. These people often labored unpaid and, in exchange for their labor, “permitted” to remain on hacienda land – land that had been, in many cases, taken from them or from their ancestors in the first place.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_HACIENDA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>With the abolition of slavery, and with social and labor reforms in much of Latin America, the hacienda system has ended, although nostalgia-tinged farms or estates might still use the name.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- units -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MAYAN_HULCHE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The hul’che, a Mayan weapon for throwing a dart or arrow, seems at first to be quite simple. It is a long wooden shaft with a notch at the end, where an arrow sits. Used by an experienced marksman, the hul’che greatly increases the force of a throw, throwing a dart at over three hundred miles per hour (150 meters per second). Against lightly armored Mesoamerican soldiers, the hul’che would have been deadly. It was used in many ancient societies: the Aztec called it the atlatl, Australian aboriginal groups called theirs a woomera, and archaeological evidence for similar devices exists across Europe.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_MAYAN_HULCHE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Both Maya men and women were trained in the use of the hul’che. Mayan battles would begin with an exchange of hul’che darts, wounding opponents before individual melee fighters rushed in in a search for individual glory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_COLOMBIAN_LLANERO_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The Llanos grasslands extend across eastern Colombia and western Venezuela, and are the home of those countries’ brave, hardy cattlemen, the llaneros. Separated from the rich coastal Caribbean ports, the llaneros developed a strong individualistic and resourceful streak, something that won them acclaim when they served as cavalry on both sides of the wars of Latin American independence. Famously, one of their own, José Antonio Páez, formed the llaneros into an effective fighting force, especially when facing down the similarly-organized royalist llaneros of José Tomás Boves.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_COLOMBIAN_LLANERO_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The llanero culture came as Spanish settlers lived near and intermingled with indigenous groups, creating a new, distinctive society with its own music, cuisine, and, especially, its own tradition of horsemanship. Owing to their dislike for the coastal elites, llaneros initially were persuaded to fight for the Crown, but under Páez, the llaneros became a potent force for independence, leading the revolutionaries to victory in the battles of Boyacá and Carabobo. In one memorable scene, Páez led his llaneros through a burning plain, stunning the Spanish, who had been disorientated by the flames and smoke… and the thunder of thousands of horses galloping straight for them!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_LAHORE_NIHANG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The Nihang were a sect of Sikh religious warriors in the 17th - 19th century in what is now northern India, Pakistan and Afghanistan. Their name, meaning “crocodile” in Persian, referred to their ferocity in combat, but they called themselves the Akali, literally “the immortals.” Wearing an iconic outfit of electric blue and a turban a foot high, the Nihang were masters of the shastar vidya, Sikh martial arts. In addition to their military skill, they were known for their strict codes of morality and religious discipline, swearing off alcohol, tobacco, and other indulgences; a Nihang, according to a Sikh scholar of the time, is he who “guards the Sikh temples without a desire for material gain, he who is always eager to fight a just and righteous war.” And fight they did; as one official reported, the Nihang were “unaffected by pain or comfort... where there is the place of battle, having no fear of death, he never steps back.”</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_LAHORE_NIHANG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>But, formidable fighters though they were, they were not an army. Rather, they were warrior-priests who would wander the countryside helping themselves to what they needed and defending Sikh communities and temples as they saw fit. The arrival of the British mobilized them into a grassroots resistance movement, one which constantly threatened to sweep out of control. As a result, the leader of the short-lived Sikh Empire, Ranjit Singh, sought to control and co-opt their fierce fighting power when he organized several thousand Nihang into his army around the conquest of Lahore in the early 1800s.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_LAHORE_NIHANG_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>By the mid-1800s, Nihang and the Sikh Empire had gone down in defeat. However, their art is still practiced in some Sikh communities in India and the UK.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_COMANDANTE_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Gran Colombia’s history is marked by resistance, and this resistance was led by a series of brilliant military commanders. From José de St Martín to José María Córdova, Francisco de Paula Santander to José Antonio Páez, to Simón Bolívar, “El Libertador,” himself, Latin American military leaders shaped the course of South America’s history.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_COMANDANTE_GENERAL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>As an example of their daring, during the liberation of New Granada, Bolívar led his 3,000 troops through swollen rainy-season rivers and up the flanks of the icy Andes, a move that would be nearly suicidal for another general. But Bolívar came down from the heights, outflanking the Spanish and cutting off reinforcements. Bogotá – the Spanish colonial capital - fell just days later.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- resources -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_RESOURCES_PAGE_RESOURCE_MAIZE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Maize – what North Americans call “corn” – is a grain first cultivated in Mesoamerica from the grass plant teosinte. Deliberate cultivation and selective breeding in the Central American milpas (slash-and-burned maize fields) or chinampas (floating maize fields) altered the small teosinte grains into the large cobs with which we are familiar today. As a staple crop, maize allowed for the expansion and dominance of the great New World cities of the Maya and Aztec empires and remains important for Central American cuisine. Soon after European contact, maize spread to much of the Old World as well, as maize used different kinds of soil and topography from rice, wheat or barley. The grain was taken up enthusiastically in Africa, where maize was first introduced by the Portuguese, and where maize transformed agricultural practices and land use on that continent: maize cultivation, with its faster growing season and intensive processing work, opened new roles for women’s labor in many African societies, thus further altering social divisions in the societies in which it entered.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_RESOURCES_PAGE_RESOURCE_HONEY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Honey is a natural sweetener made from flower nectar by bees stored in a hive for larvae to eat – it is literally insect regurgitate. But it is also one of the oldest delicacies in human history; a rock painting in Valencia, Spain, shows a person taking honey from a wild beehive. To harvest honey, nearly every society has the same technique: beekeepers – or bee-hunters – make the insects drowsy by filling the hive with smoke, allowing for the taking of the honeycomb without suffering the bees’ painful stings. Honey has a wide variety of uses; while we most often associate honey as a sweetener, it also has powerful antimicrobial properties and has been used as a treatment for wounds and burns. Additionally, the oldest alcoholic beverage, mead, is made from honey, and this “honey-wine” is referenced in Greek, Indian, Chinese, and Norse myths.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- city states -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_SINGAPORE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Singapore is a city-state on an island at the tip of the Malay Peninsula, in Southeast Asia. Here, at the Straits of Johor, the island sits just in the middle of a vital trade route connecting South Asia and the Indian Sea with East Asia and the Pacific. Before the colonial era, the region was home to a number of indigenous empires, namely Srivijaya, in Sumatra; Majapahit, on Java, and a network of Malay sultanates. When Europeans arrived, the Spanish and Portuguese sought (unsuccessfully) to convert the local population to Catholicism, and the English and Dutch looked to capitalize on the spice trade. But before 1800, the island of Singapore remained a small fishing village under the control of the Johor Sultanate, a Malay kingdom just across the water on the Malay mainland.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_SINGAPORE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>But in 1819, the island, with its potentially profitable location, fell into the sights of the British Empire, who desired to control the Straits in order to ensure that Indian opium could reach Chinese markets on British ships. Sir Stamford Raffles, a British officer, arranged a coup in Johor, and the newly installed sultan in return granted the British the rights to the island as a reward – just what Raffles had planned. Singapore became important as the center for British colonial operations in the region: not only a trade hub, but a laboratory for new cash crops and an extension of the British presence in India eastward. The British brought a range of new migrants to the island: Hokkien, Cantonese, and Hakka migrants from southern China; Tamil workers from southern India, and new immigrants from elsewhere in Malaya. Singapore became the vital heart of the British colonies in Malaya: what was to become known as the Straits Settlements.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_SINGAPORE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>In the 1900s, Singapore was destined for another twist of fate. The Imperial Japanese army took the island in a deadly siege in World War II. While the Japanese eventually surrendered, the British failure to protect the island meant that the population of the Straits Settlements were reluctant to return to colonial rule – the era of European imperialism was over. Through mass demonstrations and agitation, they eventually won their independence, but the next question arose – what would the character of a post-British Malaya be? Majority-Muslim Malaya saw the Malays as the natural inheritors of the former colony, and the Chinese as interlopers. Bloody ethnic violence resulted, and ethnic Chinese fled in large numbers to majority-Chinese Singapore and Singapore’s leader, Lee Kuan Yew. After tense negotiations, Malaya – now Malaysia – cast Singapore out in 1965.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_SINGAPORE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>Lee was determined not to have Singapore fail, and he ruled with what at times was a heavy hand, seeking to balance ethnic and labor tensions with a commitment to economic prosperity over all. Perhaps because of Lee’s determination, or simply because of Singapore’s fortuitous position in the Straits, Singapore emerged into the 21st century as an economic powerhouse. Today, with a cosmopolitan population of about six million and a global outlook, Singapore remains a politically stable but economically dynamic force in the region. It carries with it both a colonial legacy of drawing upon laborers and riches in the surrounding region, and, under Lee’s son Lee Hsien Loong, a "soft authoritarian" political orientation, but keeps its independent outlook and, above all, pragmatic approach to politics.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_CAGUANA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>When Columbus sailed to the Caribbean, the first people that he encountered were the Taino, a group of agricultural people living on what is now Puerto Rico, Hispanola, and Cuba. The Taino were a matrilineal society – they reckoned descent from the mother’s line – and Taino women and men lived in separate communities. They lived in constant tension with the more warlike Caribs (from whom we get the word "Caribbean"), who would occasionally raid Taino settlements by canoe, but despite this, the Taino managed to build a thriving society with a distinct noble class, complex religion, and sports.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_CAGUANA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Archaeologists estimate that when Columbus landed, there were perhaps two million Taino living in the area. But this number would plummet as a mixture of disease, enslavement, and warfare devastated the Taino. The Spanish priest Bartolome de las Casas, writing just over a decade after Columbus’s arrival, estimated that three million people died in the intervening years. "Who in future generations would believe this?" he wondered.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_CAGUANA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>The site of Caguana, a significant center for the Taino people, lies in central Puerto Rico. It contains near thirty ball courts – arenas where the Mesoamerican ball game was played. In addition, carved stones covered in petroglyphs attest to the site’s significance for the Taino, who associated the nearby mountains with their gods. At its height in the 1200s, Caguana would have been a site of religious festivities, astronomical observations, and sports – activities that were likely linked for the Taino. It remains a cultural heritage site for Puerto Rico. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_LAHORE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Lahore is, today, a major world city, and a commercial and cultural center in the Punjab region, an arid stretch south of the Himalayas and split between India and Pakistan. The city played significant roles in the Mughal Empire, the short-lived Sikh Empire, British India, and is presently the second largest city in Pakistan. In addition to its importance as a crossroads of inland trade routes across Asia, Lahore remains a significant cultural capital for Pakistan and beyond.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_LAHORE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Lahore was likely first settled in the first millennium A.D., but its real height came during the Mughal Empire, that remnant of the Mongol hordes that converted to Islam, settled, became acculturated, and ruled South Asia from the 16th century to the 19th. Mughal rulers built lavishly in Lahore, including the massive gates at the roads leading out of the city and its holy sites: saints’ graves and royal mosques. By the 18th century, Lahore’s wealth became world-famous; Lahore even secures a mention in Milton’s Paradise Lost as a city of wealth and power, "the Seat of the Great Mughal," revealed to Milton’s Adam as a wonder of the earth. Other British writers were similarly enamored of the city: the colonial British author Rudyard Kipling describes Lahore as "full of beauty even when the noonday heat silences the voices of men and puts the pigeons of the mosque to sleep," and raptured at having seen Lahore’s great, Armenian-made "Zam-Zammeh" cannon as a child. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_LAHORE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>As the Mughal Empire went into decline, new powers arose in the region and fought over Punjab. First to take Lahore were the Hindu armies of the Maratha, who took the city from the Mughals in 1758. But the Maratha were not as long-lived as the Mughals, and Lahore again changed hands, falling to Sikh and Afghan forces. In 1799, the city became the seat of the Sikh Empire under Ranjit Singh. Singh, the "Lion of Punjab," sought to build a new army for a new empire, and in so doing reached out both to international and local sources of power, bringing soldiers from Napoleon’s army to train his troops and co-opting the fierce Nihang warrior-priests into his forces. But the Sikh empire could not last without Singh, and after Singh’s death the region was entirely annexed into the British empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_LAHORE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>Lahore under the British saw the development of an entirely new quarter of the city, as colonial officials abandoned the Mughal district for new construction. Punjab, for the British, presented some problems: it was close to a fractious frontier and away from the ports where the British concentrated. And, indeed, Lahore became an important center for the Indian independence movement as, in 1929, the site where Pandit Nehru declared "complete independence" from Britain and raised the Indian tricolor flag.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_LAHORE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>But after independence came the bloody affair of partition. As Pakistan, declaring itself a Muslim nation, split from India, riots erupted. Hindus and Muslims killed each other in a frenzy of mass violence. Lahore was no exception, and saw the widespread slaughter of Hindus. Indira Kumar, a Hindu resident of Lahore, wondered as she, as a child, fled into the mountains from the violence, "What price Freedom and to what end?"</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_LAHORE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>The end of partition did not mean the end of violence. Lahore was damaged during another bout of violence, as India and Pakistan fought again in 1965. Today, Lahore persists. It is the capital of Pakistani Punjab, and hosts over 10 million residents.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_VATICAN_CITY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The Vatican City, at less than 0.2 square miles and 1,000 residents, is the world’s smallest sovereign state. The Vatican’s legacy goes back nearly two thousand years as the home of the Holy See, the administrative heart of the Catholic Church and its more than a billion followers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_VATICAN_CITY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Named for the hill on which it sits, the Vatican lies across the river Tiber from the historical heart of Rome. For the Romans, the Vatican Hill was the site of tombs and shrines to pagan deities, and it was on that site that the Roman Emperor Nero built his gardens and massive entertainment complex. And it was at this complex that he, according to Catholic tradition, crucified the Apostle Peter upside-down. But, while Nero’s circus was not to survive, in the 300s the Roman Emperor Constantine built the Basilica of St. Peter on the site of the apostle’s death. Constantine also designated sites for popular pilgrimage across the Empire, and as such the Vatican became a popular site for travelers. This in turn called for new renovations – accommodations, a marketplace (the Borgo), and higher and more elaborate walls.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_VATICAN_CITY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Perhaps as an ultimate revenge over Nero and his gardens, the Vatican became a site for Renaissance arts far surpassing the mad Emperor’s, most famously being the home of the Sistine Chapel, with its 1508 ceiling by Michelangelo, commissioned by Pope Julius II. Julius also sought to reshape the now thousand-year-old St. Peter’s, commissioning a new basilica, completed over a hundred years later, in 1626.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_VATICAN_CITY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>As the heart of the Catholic Church, the Vatican was the place where many momentous decisions were made. It persisted through the fall of the Western Roman Empire, the schism with the Eastern Orthodox Church, and into the Middle Ages. In the 14th century, the popes briefly abandoned the Vatican for France, but returned a few decades later. Catholic kings turned to the Vatican seeking legitimation and support and, when this wasn’t enough, enterprising popes expanded into Italy, creating the Papal States.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_VATICAN_CITY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>But secular forces were on the rise, and, in 1870, a now-unified Italy seized papal land outside of the Vatican. The conflict remained unresolved until 1929, when Benito Mussolini compensated the Holy See for its losses and granted the See the Vatican as a sovereign state.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_VATICAN_CITY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>Today, the Pope still resides in the Vatican, and the Vatican remains a significant voice – cultural, religious, and political – in world affairs. It remains home to impressive art museums, architectural feats, and gardens.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_TARUGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Taruga is the name of an archaeological site in central Nigeria significant for its evidence of some of the earliest production of iron in West Africa. In addition, the site has yielded compelling terracotta figures with elaborate hairstyles and elongated faces, some of the first artistic and scientific advancements from that region.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_TARUGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>What the people who lived in Taruga called their city is lost to history, as is the name that they called themselves. Archaeologists have dubbed them the "Nok culture," after another iconic site. Archaeologists use the term "Nok culture," rather than "Nok people," or "Nok empire," as we do not know if they shared a political unity, nor if they were one particular people or a group sharing a common culture. They lived in a territory about the same size as present-day Portugal and comprising most of present-day Nigeria, including its capital, Abuja. The Nok culture was at its greatest extent around 500 BC, although they may have emerged nearly a thousand years prior, according to newer archaeological research. They had a system of social organization that extended beyond simple kin relations, including an elite ruling class. Nok sculptures show pumpkins, and traces of sorghum and millet grains are found in their sites. As Nok populations grew in size, the control, trade, and storage of these products became more and more important and complex, leading to large granaries and trade networks.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_TARUGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>The Nok are most significant in world history for two things: their early discovery of ironworking, and their terracotta sculptures. Nok forges produced agricultural tools as well as tools of war – while war does not figure significantly into Nok art, Nok arrows and spears tell a different tale. Nok sculptures are a blend of the everyday and the fantastic. Many are of men carrying ritualized weapons, with small square beards and moustaches grown long just at the corners of their mouths. Others are of human-animal hybrids: an elephant with human eyes, men with birds’ beaks, etc.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_TARUGA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>The Nok declined around 200 AD for unknown reasons. But they clearly had an influence on later West African civilizations and are an example of innovation and scientific production at an early date.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_HUNZA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>When the Spanish arrived in South America, they were tantalized by stories of "El Dorado," "the golden one," a city of gold. While much of their fascination came from simple greed, later writers have wondered what effects the sight of adobe-brick pueblo cities in the setting sun may have had upon explorers’ imaginations. Such fantasies would have been fueled by the sheer richness of many South American cities. Hunza, the heart of the Muisca people, was one such place brimming with gold. When the Spanish found it, it was one of the wealthiest kingdoms in South America, and, after the conquest of the Muisca, made their lands the capital region of Spanish settlements in what was to become Colombia.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_HUNZA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The Muisca, speakers of the Chibcha language, numbered about 120,000 to 160,000 at the time that the Spanish arrived. They were divided into two main polities, one ruled by kings known as zipa, and the other by kings known as zaque. These were kings of a sort of confederacy: individuals in semi-autonomous communities would be united by a captain, who in turn answered to the ruling zaque (or zipa). Muisca villages were heavily concentrated, with thatched roofs, temples to a complicated pantheon of divinities, and palaces for rulers. Religion and rulership, as in many societies, were linked, and zipa and zaque extended their legitimacy by laying claim to sources of esoteric magical knowledge.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_HUNZA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>The Muisca lands were rich, but arid. While they grew maize, they also raided their neighbors in the wetter lowlands, carrying off grain as well as slaves for field and domestic labor… and human sacrifice. Muisca warriors were terrifying; these "guecha warriors" sometimes carried mummified bodies on their backs to show their might – indeed, one translation of their name means "the man who brings death." In more peaceful times, Muisca traded elaborate textiles as well as the spoils from their rich mines with their neighbors. As they do today, the mines in this region of the Andes produce emeralds, and coal (which the Muisca used for household fires). And, of course, the Muisca worked gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_HUNZA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>The Muisca were awash in gold, sometimes literally. In their devotions to the gods at Lake Guatavita, Muisca devotees would paint themselves in gold dust and bathe in the water. Ornaments for the zipa and zaque were solid gold (gold obtained via trade, not from Muisca mines), and meeting such a figure must have started Spanish minds thinking about profits that might be made from conquest – or a fabled distant city made entirely of the metal. In 1537, a Spanish expeditionary force searching for El Dorado made it to the Bogotá savannah – the prehistoric lakebed that was the heart of Muisca territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_HUNZA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>Quemuenchatocha, the Muisca leader, recognized the threat the Spanish posed and attempted to stay hidden from them. But this could not last; when the Spanish discovered him decked out in gold and emeralds, his companions fled. The Spanish captured his valuables – and him. It is on his lands – Hunza – that the Spanish town of Tunja was built, and on the fertile Muisca lands where the capital-to-be of Bogotá was later founded.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CITYSTATES_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_HUNZA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>Today, a recent census counted just under fifteen thousand Muisca remaining in Colombia. Local groups have recently formed councils to protest environmental destruction in Colombia and to preserve their cultural heritage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- great people -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_JOSE_DE_SUCRE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Antonio José de Sucre, named the “Liberator of Ecuador and Peru,” was a chief lieutenant of Simon Bolívar during the wars of independence against Spain. He began his military career at the age of 15 and quickly became involved with the republican (as opposed to the royalist pro-Spanish) cause. His most famous victory came at the battle of Ayacucho, where royalist forces, expecting to face a disorganized and scattered republican army, foolishly spread their forces thin and charged Sucre. Sucre’s soldiers held firm, and destroyed the royalist’s flanking maneuver before it could get into position. The battle secured the independence of Peru and highland South America.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_JOSE_DE_SUCRE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Sucre then became the first elected leader of upper Peru – what is now Bolivia, and defeated several pro-Spanish attempts to retake the silver-rich region. But after victory, local generals fell to fighting amongst themselves. Sucre’s attempt to appropriate Catholic land for the new nation in particular offended conservative elements in South America. He was ambushed and assassinated in 1830, as a part of a rival’s scheme to create an independent Ecuador.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_PAULA_SANTANDER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Long the counterpart to Simon Bolívar, Francisco de Paula Santander was both an ally and an enemy to the Liberator, and remains one of the greatest Colombian heroes to this day. He served as one of the two lead commanders in the pivotal Battle of Boyaca, an assault on the heart of Spanish power in Colombia, after leading (with Bolívar) troops across a grueling hike through rain-swollen rivers and icy mountain passes in order to catch the Spanish off-guard. The battle secured Colombian victory, and its success prompted Bolívar to declare the liberation of Gran Colombia complete.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_PAULA_SANTANDER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>But their partnership was to see hard times. While Bolívar favored a lifetime rule for leaders and cultivated a cult of personality for himself, Santander, the “Man of Laws,” as he was later known, favored constitutional rule. His opposition grew even stronger when Bolívar declared himself dictator, something that Santander could not in any way support. His opposition won him the enmity of many of Bolívar’s supporters, including many of his fellow generals. But in addition to Bolívar’s supporters, Santander also faced those who wanted to see Gran Colombia divided into smaller, independent units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_PAULA_SANTANDER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Implicated in a plot against Bolívar, Santander was exiled. Bolívar relented, however, and years later, after Gran Colombia fragmented into smaller states, Santander was permitted to return. He became the president of New Granada, and remains a central figure in Colombia today, especially for those who support the rule of law and a check on military power.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_ANTONIO_PAEZ_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>José Antionio Páez, named the “Centaur of the Plains” owing to his skill on horseback, was, according to history author Mike Duncan, a “short, stocky illiterate cowboy,” born on the “llanos,” a grassy plain in the remote south of Venezuela. Before his military career, Páez was, before his military career, a ranch hand and cattleman. But as the wave of revolution swept over South America, Páez organized a band of llaneros – Venezuelan cowboys – into a stunningly efficient cavalry. In this, he operated often independently of Bolívar, refusing attempts by Santander, Bolívar’s general, to join. But when Páez and Bolívar finally met, they proved a devastating force. In one battle, Páez led 1100 men against 4000 royalists, achieving victory by repeatedly confounding the Spanish. He led his horsemen into their camp at night, kicking up dust from the dry ground, then charging through it. Then, as the Spanish regrouped in a field of dry grass, Páez had the grass set on fire, again charging his men through the flames at the Spanish. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_ANTONIO_PAEZ_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>After independence, Páez remained a staunch advocate for Venezuelan sovereignty, leading a rebellion against the authority of Gran Colombia and the administration of Santander (Páez preferred the authoritarian and charismatic Bolívar to the “Man of Laws” Santander). After Venezuela became independent, Páez was its first president. But not for long. His rivals deposed him, and the Centaur of the Plains found himself fighting for his own Venezuela… again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_URDANETA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Rafael Urdaneta was a general in Bolívar’s “Admirable Campaign” against Spanish rule in Venezuela, and became a senior statesman after independence. Fiercely loyal to Bolívar, who referred to Urdaneta as “the Brilliant,” Urdaneta sought to protect him from threats internal and external.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_URDANETA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>After independence, Urdaneta clashed with Francisco de Paula Santander, another confidante of Bolívar who advocated for constitutional rule (rather than a more authoritarian, personality-centered rule by Bolívar himself). Santander attempted to move troops loyal to Bolívar away from the capital, but in so doing provoked a fight between Santander-loyal groups and those loyal to Bolívar. With Santander gone, Urdaneta took control of Colombia and tried to persuade an old and frail Bolívar to return to power. When Bolívar refused, Urdaneta was deposed by pro-Santander forces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MARINO_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Gran Colombia had conflicts across a wide region. At times, Bolívar undertook military campaigns directly to a conflicted area, as in the “Admirable Campaign” to liberate Venezuela. But at times, republican (anti-royal) armies seemed to be operating nearly independently. Such was the case with Santiago Mariño. Originally from the island of Margarita, in present-day Venezuela, Mariño attempted to single-handedly liberate the region from the Spanish. With Bolívar invading from the west, Mariño attacked Venezuela from the east. Each claimed to be fighting for the same cause, but with neither recognizing the other as dominant. A story goes that Mariño, dressed in his full military uniform, once boasted to his attache, “Antonio, I am young, rich, handsome, General in Chief at the age of 25! What do I lack?” His assistant responded simply, “Prudence.”</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MARINO_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Mariño eventually had to back down, and Bolívar gave him command of the Venezuelan front. The two continued to fight together, and were even arrested together – by one of their own generals, José Ribas, who sought to rule the western half of Gran Colombia.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MARINO_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Despite this, Mariño always kept a dream of his own Venezuelan state in mind. After José Antonio Páez eventually declared an independent Venezuela, Mariño in turn declared an independent “State of the East”. Mariño was forced to flee as his nascent state was put down, but his conviction was not – he was to lead a coup attempt and, later, as Páez’s rivals took power and deposed the former President, it was Mariño to meet him – and defeat him – on the field.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MACGREGOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Historian Richard Slatta describes the Scottish adventurer as “indominable and perhaps not completely sane.” The label seems to fit. Gregor MacGregor was a young Scottish soldier who had fought in the wars against Napoleon, but whose real claim to fame was in adopting invented knightly and noble titles for himself and parading about Edinburgh in a luxurious coach. After hearing of Latin America’s struggles against Spanish domination, MacGregor moved to Caracas seeking to get in on the action and declared his willingness to support the revolutionary cause. The local military, overlooking or ignoring MacGregor’s quirks, saw the benefit in having a veteran soldier in their employ, and set MacGregor to training troops.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MACGREGOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>He soon found himself in military action again, and his most famous maneuver involved not a victory, but a retreat. After a loss to Spanish forces, MacGregor moved his troops across Venezuela, keeping one step ahead of pursuing royalists. Then, finding himself cut off by a new force, he lured his enemies into a swamp and pinned them down with volleys of arrows from his mostly indigenous archers. For this, Bolívar dubbed him the “Xenophon of the Americas,” naming him after the Greek commander who stunned pursuing Persian forces.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MACGREGOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Later, MacGregor began a series of odd (mis)adventures. He conceived of an invasion of Florida, thinking that the area – still Spanish at the time – would make a convenient base to launch more anti-colonial interventions in the Caribbean. The attempt, however, was stopped by the United States, which would soon purchase Florida from Spain for itself.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MACGREGOR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>Then, he returned to Europe and claimed to be the leader of a (fictitious) South American country. He collected money from wealthy English and Scottish investors and amassed a small fortune before being found out – when investors arrived in “Poyais,” they found nothing but jungle. Later in life he returned to Venezuela where he successfully convinced his former comrades to let him retire on a veteran’s pension.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_PIAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>In the chaos of the Latin American wars of independence, new visions of what the future might be took hold, were contested, and, at times, were extinguished: what new states might arise? How would they be governed? What would become of people of different ancestry in these states? Manuel Piar embodied some of this utopian hope, as well as its fragility.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_PIAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Piar was a morisco, a word that, in the Spanish colonies, meant that his mother was of mixed European-African ancestry. This in turn meant that he faced a certain degree of discrimination from his criollo (European-ancestry) comrades, something that likely influenced his motivations to fight and, ultimately, his fate.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_PIAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Piar fought against many different colonial regimes, beginning with a push to expel the British from Curaco. Then, he moved on to fight in the Haitian Revolution, one of the first true anti-slavery revolutions in the New World. After Haiti, Piar joined with Bolívar and the struggle for Latin American independence, but continued to push further – significantly joining with Santiago Mariño in an attempt to liberate (and possibly take over) Guayana.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_PIAR_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>Piar’s primary motivation, whether spurred by his own personal experience or from his time amongst the Haitian rebels, was for equal rights for the mestizo population – those Latin Americans not of pure European blood. His agitation against the post-independence Bolívarian regime saw him stripped of his title, and he fled back to Guayana. There, he teamed up with Marino, José Félix Ribas, and other generals dissatisfied with how Bolívar’s Latin America was shaping up. This rebellion was to cost him – and only him – his life. Bolívar ordered him arrested and subsequently executed. In what may be an expression of regret – or may be just a story – Bolívar is said to have announced “I have spilled my blood” upon hearing of Piar’s death.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_NARINO_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The Latin American wars of independence came on the heels of the French Revolution and were in part inspired by the ideals of that struggle. This is certainly the case for Antonio Nariño, a wealthy merchant of Bogotá.  Nariño idolized French and American Revolutionary leaders (he hung a portrait of Benjamin Franklin above the mantle in his home). Nariño translated, printed and distributed the French Declaration of the Rights of Man to nascent revolutionaries in Latin America, something which got him in trouble with the Spanish authorities. The Declaration’s calls to free political association, national sovereignty, and the idea that social distinctions should exist only for the common good ran afoul of the Spanish claim to authority that rested on the idea of monarchy. But Nariño pressed things further, writing to the viceroy of the colony that “people are everywhere discontented” with Spanish rule. For this, Nariño was called the “Precursor” of the Revolution. He was also arrested.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_NARINO_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>But he was to return. In 1811, Nariño was freed by revolutionaries from his prison cell, and went on to command the New Granadan forces, capturing Popayan (in Colombia) for the revolutionaries. For his role in the revolutions, Nariño’s name is featured in the Colombian national anthem, and is recognized as a hero of the modern-day republic.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MONTILLA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Mariano Montilla was among the first supporters of independence, being present at the proclamation of independence for the state of Venezuela, in 1810. But this revolution, and the First Republic of Venezuela, were not long for the world. After a devastating earthquake in 1812 and a series of military defeats, the Republic was gone, and Montilla fled to the United States. In so doing, he escaped the worst of the violence that followed the Republic’s collapse.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MONTILLA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>But as Montilla stayed in exile, Bolívar began his “Admirable Campaign” to liberate Venezuela from the west, just as Mariño began his campaign in the east. Montilla returned and, despite having once fought for an independent Venezuela (as opposed to a united Gran Colombia), Montilla joined with the forces of Bolívar. Montilla fought in the defense of San Mateo, Ocumare, and Carabobo. He also led the defense of the city of Cartagena, but when the city fell, Montilla was forced – again – into exile in the north.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MONTILLA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>He returned again, this time to be placed at the head of an Irish contingent on the island of Margarita. From there, he led raids into royalist-occupied territory along the Caribbean coast, eventually fighting in yet another siege of Cartagena – this time on the besieger’s side and this time victorious.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_MONTILLA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>After Independence, Montilla supported the Bolívarist wing of Gran Colombian politics. For this, he was yet again exiled and yet again returned, this time to support again and finally see the creation of an independent Venezuela. His body now sits in the highest place of honor in Caracas, in the National Pantheon of Venezuela.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_RIBAS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>José Félix Ribas was an independence leader in the Latin American wars against the Spanish crown. Born in Venezuela, Ribas had no military background, but was active in agitating against Spanish rule. He was also rich and was able to secure a military position when he financed his own battalion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_RIBAS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Ribas’s most significant military victory was the battle of La Victoria, when royalists besieged the city. Ribas, low on men, armed students from local colleges and seminaries and told them, “we cannot choose between victory or death; we must have victory!” And victory he had – the Spanish forces under Morales were defeated. Ribas gained the title “Victor over the Tyrants,” and the date of the battle is now marked as Youth Day in Venezuela, in commemoration of how Ribas armed the students.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_RIBAS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Ribas’s career was not all glorious highs, though. At one point, he even arrested Bolívar after a defeat at Aragua de Barcelona scattered the republican forces. Bolívar fled by water, carrying the city’s church silver to the island of Margarita. Seeing Bolívar flee, and seeing an opportunity to seize a claim to Gran Colombia for himself, Ribas declared Bolívar a traitor, although he later relented.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_GREATPEOPLE_PAGE_GREAT_PERSON_INDIVIDUAL_COMMANDANTE_RIBAS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>At the Battle of Urica, Ribas was to meet his end. In a tremendous conflict, Ribas’s royalist rival Boves was killed, but Boves’s forces pressed on and won the day for the Spanish. Ribas fled but was discovered by royalists and killed. Yet despite this defeat, the death of Boves meant that many Venezuelan llaneros (cowboys turned cavalry) defected away from the Spanish side towards the charismatic republican leader Páez. As a result of Urica and La Victoria, Ribas remains a hero to the cause of Latin American independence.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- features -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_BERMUDA_TRIANGLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>It started with reports about strange lights. It evolved into tales of missing and phantom-crew ships. Since the mid-19th century (and perhaps even earlier if Columbus’s journals are to be believed), ships and planes have been disappearing from the region known as the Bermuda Triangle. More than 50 ships and 20 planes allegedly have vanished within the triangle, never to be seen again. Although aliens are a popular theory for the mass disappearances of transportation and people, there are a few more mundane hypotheses to explain the triangle. Some scientists suggest that there are “air bombs” or microbursts that may have sunk the ships. Other scientists suggest giant “rogue waves” or magnetic shifts that lie about true north on compasses. In spite of the persistent legends and rumors, it is generally agreed that the frequency of disappearances and wrecks in the Bermuda Triangle aren’t any greater than any other section of well-traveled ocean.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_FOUNTAIN_OF_YOUTH_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The Fountain of Youth of legend is less of a cement or stone fountain, and more of a spring said to restore the youth of anyone who drinks or swims in it. The trusty Herodotus wrote about the fountain in the 5th century BC, and Alexander the Great allegedly found a healing river a hundred years later. Unfortunately, neither of them bottled up any of the water to help them later on in life when old age and wounds respectively took them to Hades. Over countless centuries, the myth persisted, and explorers such as Juan Ponce de Leon spent countless years searching for the mystical spring. If anyone has found it, they haven’t shared the secret with the world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_FEATURES_PAGE_FEATURE_PAITITI_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Humans, ever on the search for “lost cities,” particularly Lost Cities of Gold, tend to gravitate towards legends of great wealth and prosperity. Like most mystical cities, the prevailing thought is that Païtiti exists deep within the unknown wilds just waiting to be discovered. The Inca saw the city as the last safe haven from the Spanish Conquest. However, others (predominantly non-Incan explorers from the 1600s) perceived the city to be a treasure trove just waiting to be plundered. The legends of Païtiti’s wealth were perpetuated by the attack of Francisco Pizarro and his murder of Atahualpa, the last ruler of the Inca. He searched for the remaining gold said to exist, but Pizarro never received all of the alleged gold he tried so desperately to gain from his conquest. Despite multiple expeditions into the “unknown” jungles of the Amazon, no explorer has yet discovered the location of Païtiti.</Text>
		</Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FIRES_TITLE">
      <Text>Forest Fires</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FIRES_PARA_1">
      <Text>Any tile with Woods or Rainforest can catch ablaze.  The fire burns hot for three turns, destroying improvements on the tile, reducing the owning city's population, and damaging units.  On the second and third turns, this fire might spread to any adjacent Woods or Rainforest tiles.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_FIRES_PARA_2">
      <Text>Once the fire has burned out, the Woods or Rainforest is replaced with a Burnt variant, boosting the tile's [ICON_Food] Food yield.  Over the next 3 turns, it regrows until it returns to its normal state, at which point it also boosts the tile's [ICON_Production] Production yield.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_SHOWERS_TITLE">
      <Text>Meteor Showers</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_ENVIRONMENTAL_EFFECTS_CHAPTER_SHOWERS_PARA_1">
      <Text>Meteors may shower anywhere on land in the space between player territories, and leave behind a Meteor Site.  Any unit can collect this Meteor Site, gathering the easily-accessible advanced ores in the fallen rocks, granting them a free Heavy Cavalry unit in their nearest city.  This unit has no resource maintenance cost.</Text>
    </Row>
	<!-- promotions -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_NIHANG_SUZERAIN_COMBAT_BONUS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>One of the first pieces of equipment that a Nihang would wear is the kara, the steel bracelet. Worn on the warrior’s strongest hand, the bracelet provided both a physical defense during swordfights as well as a symbol of the vows that a Nihang had taken. Its strength was to be the strength of the warrior’s commitment to God, and the unbroken link of steel similarly symbolized God’s eternal presence and the wearer’s unbroken faith.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_NIHANG_MOVEMENT_BONUS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>A Nihang learned to fight with his sword, gun... and shoes. Jangi mojeh were bladed slippers, adding an extra deadly edge to a soldier’s kicks.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_NIHANG_FLANKED_BONUS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Tegh, simply “sword,” refers to a broad, curved blade “ten fists long,” a weapon in addition to the traditional kirpan, or dagger, that Sikhs carry. These weapons symbolize a commitment to independence, a vow to punish evil and protect the good in the world. The use of the tegh was to be a last resort, after kindness and charity (“deg,” or “the kettle”) had proved to be not enough.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_NIHANG_NO_WOUNDED_PENALTY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Chainmail – sanjo – has a long history in Punjab, dating back to its introduction by the Persians in the early first millennium, and a chain shirt was a core part of a Nihang’s equipment. In 18th-century warfare, muskets were present, and Nihang were certainly trained in their use, but muskets were slow and unreliable, and a real fight always came down to swords and armor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITPROMOTIONS_PAGE_PROMOTION_NIHANG_FAITH_FOR_VICTORIES_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>For a Nihang who had proven himself in battle, the ultimate honor was to wear the trident – the Trehsool Mukh - in his turban. This showed the warrior’s closeness with Shiva – and provided a very sharp, very close weapon of last resort.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
